<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Large cities get more for less: Water footprint efficiency across the US</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0202301</url>
<snippet>Many urban indicators and functional citywide properties have been shown to scale with population due to agglomeration effects. We hypothesize that scaling relations may also exist for water-related urban indicators such as the water footprint. The water footprint is an indicator of water use that measures humans appropriation of freshwater resources. We analyze the scaling of the water footprint for 65 mid- to large-sized US cities using both empirical estimates and a social interaction network model of city functioning. The network model is used to explain the presence of any scaling exponent in the empirical estimates of the urban water footprint by linking to previous theories of urban scaling. We find that the urban water footprint tends to approximately show sublinear scaling behavior with both population and gross domestic product. Thus, large cities tend to be more water footprint efficient and productive than mid-sized cities, where efficiency and productivity are quantified, in a broad sense, as deviations from a linear scaling exponent. We find the sublinear scaling may be linked to changes in urban economic structure with city size, which lead to large cities shifting water intensive economic activities to less populated regions. In addition, we find that green water contributes to the scaling both positively by transferring the dependence of food consumption on population into the water footprint and negatively by increasing heterogeneity. Overall, the proposed scaling relations allow for the comparison of water footprint efficiency and productivity of cities. Comparing these properties and identifying deviations from the expected behavior has implications for water resources and urban sustainability. OI Grady, Caitlin/0000-0002-9151-6664
WOS:000442202100024
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>Mass Gatherings Health 4 Crowd and environmental management during mass gatherings</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(11)70287-0</url>
<snippet>Crowds are a feature of large cities, occurring not only at mass gatherings but also at routine events such as the journey to work. To address extreme crowding, various computer models for crowd movement have been developed in the past decade, and we review these and show how they can be used to identify health and safety issues. State-of-the-art models that simulate the spread of epidemics operate on a population level, but the collection of fine-scale data might enable the development of models for epidemics that operate on a microscopic scale, similar to models for crowd movement. We provide an example of such simulations, showing how an individual-based crowd model can mirror aggregate susceptible-infected-recovered models that have been the main models for epidemics so far. RI Johansson, Anders/C-5551-2009; Batty, Michael/I-5638-2014
WOS:000299656000024
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Simple Urban Simulation Atop Complicated Models: Multi-Scale Equation-Free Computing of Sprawl Using Geographic Automata</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/e15072606</url>
<snippet>Reconciling competing desires to build urban models that can be simple and complicated is something of a grand challenge for urban simulation. It also prompts difficulties in many urban policy situations, such as urban sprawl, where simple, actionable ideas may need to be considered in the context of the messily complex and complicated urban processes and phenomena that work within cities. In this paper, we present a novel architecture for achieving both simple and complicated realizations of urban sprawl in simulation. Fine-scale simulations of sprawl geography are run using geographic automata to represent the geographical drivers of sprawl in intricate detail and over fine resolutions of space and time. We use Equation-Free computing to deploy population as a coarse observable of sprawl, which can be leveraged to run automata-based models as short-burst experiments within a meta-simulation framework. RI Ghanem, Roger/B-8570-2008 OI Ghanem, Roger/0000-0002-1890-920X
WOS:000322183300008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Strategic Islands in Economic Games: Isolating Economies From Better Outcomes</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/e16095102</url>
<snippet>Many of the issues we face as a society are made more problematic by the rapidly changing context in which important decisions are made. For example buying a petrol powered car is most advantageous when there are many petrol pumps providing cheap petrol whereas buying an electric car is most advantageous when there are many electrical recharge points or high capacity batteries available. Such collective decision-making is often studied using economic game theory where the focus is on how individuals might reach an agreement regarding the supply and demand for the different energy types. But even if the two parties find a mutually agreeable strategy, as technology and costs change over time, for example through cheaper and more efficient batteries and a more accurate pricing of the total cost of oil consumption, so too do the incentives for the choices buyers and sellers make, the result of which can be the stranding of an industry or even a whole economy on an island of inefficient outcomes. In this article we consider the issue of how changes in the underlying incentives can move us from an optimal economy to a sub-optimal economy while at the same time making it impossible to collectively navigate our way to a better strategy without forcing us to pass through a socially undesirable "tipping point". We show that different perturbations to underlying incentives results in the creation or destruction of "strategic islands" isolated by disruptive transitions between strategies. The significant result in this work is the illustration that an economy that remains strategically stationary can over time become stranded in a suboptimal outcome from which there is no easy way to put the economy on a path to better outcomes without going through an economic tipping point.
WOS:000343110100021
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>The Leaf as a Sustainable and Renewable System</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sres.2487</url>
<snippet>Leaves play a critical role in the Earths biosphere, regulating weather, renewing mineral nutrients and maintaining biotic processes to support both flora and fauna. Leaves also form an important resource for consumers. Together, plant hosts and consumers represent complex adaptive selection. We used systems dynamic and holon models to understand the ability of the leaf to meet both host plant and host consumer criteria resulting in socio-ecological system sustainability. We first identified dynamic cycles facilitated by the leaf as a component of both plant and consumer systems. Each of the variables in these loops serves a critical role in the production and function of the leaf, recycling energy and matter through plant and consumer systems. Control feedback balances the system, optimizing opposing selective forces to meet criteria for viability of host plants and usability by consumers, which return benefits through various services. We then examine the organization of the leaf host system, revealing mutually closed sub-systems corresponding to a definition of component life. We thus showthe leaf host relation to be a theoretically whole system having positive, sustainable impacts on biomass, food, energy, etc. These results may inform more general sustainability assessments by offering a mathematical definition of sustainability as emergent, cyclical organization in ecosystems. Copyright (C) 2017 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.
WOS:000413766100006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>Population predictions for the world's largest cities in the 21st century</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0956247816663557</url>
<snippet>We project populations to 2100 for the worlds larger cities. Three socioeconomic scenarios with various levels of sustainability and global cooperation are evaluated, and individual best fit projections made for each city using global urbanization forecasts. In 2010, 757 million people resided in the 101 largest cities - 11 per cent of the worlds population. By the end of the century, world population is projected to range from 6.9 billion to 13.1 billion, with 15 per cent to 23 per cent of people residing in the 101 largest cities (1.6 billion to 2.3 billion). The disparate effects of socioeconomic pathways on regional distribution of the worlds 101 largest cities in the 21st century are examined by changes in population rank for 2010, 2025, 2050, 2075 and 2100. Socioeconomic pathways are assessed based on their influence on the worlds largest cities. Two aspects of the projections raise concerns about reliability: the unlikely degree of growth of cities suggested for Africa and the growth of cities in coastal settings (and likely global immigration). Trends and the effect of sustainable development on regional distribution of large cities throughout the 21st century are discussed. OI Hoornweg, Daniel/0000-0002-2340-7204
WOS:000400086300012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>The light pollution as a surrogate for urban population of the US cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2017.11.039</url>
<snippet>We show that the definition of the city boundaries can have a dramatic influence on the scaling behavior of the night-time light (NTL) as a function of population (POP) in the US. Precisely, our results show that the arbitrary geopolitical definition based on the Metropolitan/Consolidated Metropolitan Statistical Areas (MSA/CMSA) leads to a sublinear power-law growth of NTL with POP. On the other hand, when cities are defined according to a more natural agglomeration criteria, namely, the City Clustering Algorithm (CCA), an isometric relation emerges between NTL and population. This discrepancy is compatible with results from previous works showing that the scaling behaviors of various urban indicators with population can be substantially different for distinct definitions of city boundaries. Moreover, considering the CCA definition as more adequate than the MSA/CMSA one because the former does not violate the expected extensivity between land population and area of their generated clusters, we conclude that, without loss of generality, the CCA measures of light pollution and population could be interchangeably utilized in future studies. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Andrade, Jose/C-5451-2013; Carmona, Humberto/L-4967-2016; Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/J-4630-2016 OI Andrade, Jose/0000-0002-5571-7610; Carmona, Humberto/0000-0002-7505-6717; Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/0000-0002-9247-6780
WOS:000423495100090
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Complexity, the science of cities and long-range futures</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.futures.2013.01.006</url>
<snippet>The emergence of a 'science of cities' provides the foundations for long-range futures research that may be applied to models of climate change, with a time horizon in excess of 150 years. The features of a complexity theory of cities have been developed at multiple levels with scientific analogies such as ecology, biology and physics. The following principles apply: (1) complexity science unifies a wide variety of urban phenomena including emergence, technological evolution, civil phase transitions, macrolaws, and resilience to system failures and extreme events. (2). World urbanisation raises the number of levels in the urban hierarchy, with an increasing number of megacities with over 10 m inhabitants. (3) Urban development involves the institutional coordination of technological development with engineered transformations. (4) Civil and societal transitions arise with increasing per capita investment, such that some social norms and planning standards have consistent scaling factors across a range of city sizes for countries at similar stages of development. (5) The trajectory of the urban system depends upon the allometric pattern of growth for cities, and human settlements in 2150 will occupy less than 10&#37; of the world's land area. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000317160600006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>The technosphere in Earth System analysis: A coevolutionary perspective</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/2053019616676608</url>
<snippet>Earth System analysis is the study of the joint dynamics of biogeophysical, social and technological processes on our planet. To advance our understanding of possible future development pathways and identify management options for navigating to safe operating spaces while avoiding undesirable domains, computer models of the Earth System are developed and applied. These models hardly represent dynamical properties of technological processes despite their great planetary-scale influence on the biogeophysical components of the Earth System and the associated risks for human societies posed, e.g. by climatic change or novel entities. In this contribution, we reflect on the technosphere from the perspective of Earth System analysis with a threefold focus on agency, networks and complex coevolutionary dynamics. First, we argue that Haffs conception of the technosphere takes an extreme position in implying a strongly constrained human agency in the Earth System. Assuming that the technosphere develops according to dynamics largely independently of human intentions, Haffs perspective appears incompatible with a humanistic view that underlies the sustainability discourse at large and, more specifically, current frameworks such as UN sustainable development goals and the safe and just operating space for humanity. Second, as an alternative to Haffs static three-stratum picture, we propose complex adaptive networks as a concept for describing the interplay of social agents and technospheric entities and their emergent dynamics for Earth System analysis. Third, we argue that following a coevolutionary approach in conceptualising and modelling technospheric dynamics, also including the socio-cultural and biophysical spheres of the Earth System, could resolve the apparent conflict between the discourses on sustainability and the technosphere. Hence, this coevolutionary approach may point the way forward in modelling technological influences in the Earth System and may lead to a considerably deeper understanding of pathways to sustainable development in the future. OI Donges, Jonathan/0000-0001-5233-7703
WOS:000447103500003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="10">
<title>Ecology in an anthropogenic biosphere</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1890/14-2274.1</url>
<snippet>Humans, unlike any other multicellular species in Earths history, have emerged as a global force that is transforming the ecology of an entire planet. It is no longer possible to understand, predict, or successfully manage ecological pattern, process, or change without understanding why and how humans reshape these over the long term. Here, a general causal theory is presented to explain why human societies gained the capacity to globally alter the patterns, processes, and dynamics of ecology and how these anthropogenic alterations unfold over time and space as societies themselves change over human generational time. Building on existing theories of ecosystem engineering, niche construction, inclusive inheritance, cultural evolution, ultrasociality, and social change, this theory of anthroecological change holds that sociocultural evolution of subsistence regimes based on ecosystem engineering, social specialization, and non-kin exchange, or "sociocultural niche construction," is the main cause of both the long-term upscaling of human societies and their unprecedented transformation of the biosphere. Human sociocultural niche construction can explain, where classic ecological theory cannot, the sustained transformative effects of human societies on biogeography, ecological succession, ecosystem processes, and the ecological patterns and processes of landscapes, biomes, and the biosphere. Anthroecology theory generates empirically testable hypotheses on the forms and trajectories of long-term anthropogenic ecological change that have significant theoretical and practical implications across the subdisciplines of ecology and conservation. Though still at an early stage of development, anthroecology theory aligns with and integrates established theoretical frameworks including social-ecological systems, social metabolism, countryside biogeography, novel ecosystems, and anthromes. The "fluxes of nature" are fast becoming "cultures of nature." To investigate, understand, and address the ultimate causes of anthropogenic ecological change, not just the consequences, human sociocultural processes must become as much a part of ecological theory and practice as biological and geophysical processes are now. Strategies for achieving this goal and for advancing ecological science and conservation in an increasingly anthropogenic biosphere are presented. OI Ellis, Erle/0000-0002-2006-3362
WOS:000358731100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="11">
<title>Keeping global climate change within 1.5 degrees C through net negative electric cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cosust.2018.02.009</url>
<snippet>The development of net negative electric cities encompasses the three strategies of decarbonizing power supply, energy efficiency and electrification. There is potential to pursue these combined strategies rapidly to hold climate change to within 1.5 degrees C. Recent work has identified many cities in developing countries that are ideal for electrification today based on carbon intensity and high access to electricity. Net negative electric cities could be achieved by following a comprehensive policy framework for low carbon investment.
WOS:000444521500004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="12">
<title>Explaining the prevalence, scaling and variance of urban phenomena</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41562-016-0012</url>
<snippet>The prevalence of many urban phenomena changes systematically with population size(1). We propose a theory that unifies models of economic complexity(2,3) and cultural evolution(4) to derive urban scaling. The theory accounts for the difference in scaling exponents and average prevalence across phenomena, as well as the difference in the variance within phenomena across cities of similar size. The central ideas are that a number of necessary complementary factors must be simultaneously present for a phenomenon to occur, and that the diversity of factors is logarithmically related to population size. The model reveals that phenomena that require more factors will be less prevalent, scale more superlinearly and show larger variance across cities of similar size. The theory applies to data on education, employment, innovation, disease and crime, and it entails the ability to predict the prevalence of a phenomenon across cities, given information about the prevalence in a single city. OI Gomez-Lievano, Andres/0000-0001-8320-0857
WOS:000418775900022
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="13">
<title>Professional diversity and the productivity of cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep05393</url>
<snippet>Attempts to understand the relationship between diversity, productivity and scale have remained limited due to the scheme-dependent nature of the taxonomies describing complex systems. We analyze the diversity of US metropolitan areas in terms of profession diversity and employment to show how this frequency distribution takes a universal scale-invariant form, common to all cities, in the limit of infinite resolution of occupational taxonomies. We show that this limit is obtained under general conditions that follow from the analysis of the variation of the occupational frequency across taxonomies at different resolutions in a way analogous to finite-size scaling in statistical physical systems. We propose a theoretical framework that derives the form and parameters of the limiting distribution of professions based on the appearance, in urban social networks, of new occupations as the result of specialization and coordination of labor. By deriving classification scheme-independent measures of functional diversity and modeling cities as social networks embedded in infrastructural space, these results show how standard economic arguments of division and coordination of labor can be articulated in detail in cities and provide a microscopic basis for explaining increasing returns to population scale observed at the level of entire metropolitan areas. OI Youn, Hyejin/0000-0002-6190-4412
WOS:000337888600007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="14">
<title>Synergies and trade-offs between energy-efficient urbanization and health</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/aa9281</url>
<snippet>Energy-efficient urbanization and public health pose major development challenges for India. While both issues are intensively studied, their interaction is not well understood. Here we explore the relationship between urban infrastructures, public health, and household-related emissions, identifying potential synergies and trade-offs of specific interventions by analyzing nationally representative household surveys from 2005 and 2012. Our analysis confirms previous characterizations of the environmental-health transition, but also points to an important role of energy use and urbanization as modifiers of this transition. We find that non-motorized transport may prove a sweet spot for development, as its use is associated with lower emissions and better public health in cities. Urbanization and improved access to basic services correlate with lower short-term morbidity (STM), such as fever, cough and diarrhea. Our analysis suggests that a 10&#37; increase in urbanization from current levels and concurrent improvement in access to modern cooking and clean water could lower STM for 2.4 million people. This would be associated with a modest increase in electricity related emissions of 84 ktCO(2)e annually. Promoting energy-efficient mobility systems, for instance by a 10&#37; increase in bicycling, could lower chronic conditions like diabetes and cardio-vascular diseases for 0.3 million people while also abating emissions. These findings provide empirical evidence to validate that energy-efficient and sustainable urbanization can address both public health and climate change challenges simultaneously. OI Pachauri, Shonali/0000-0001-8138-3178; Ahmad, Sohail/0000-0002-2816-8484
WOS:000414647300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="15">
<title>Innovation: an emerging focus from cells to societies</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2016.0414</url>
<snippet>Innovations are generally unexpected, often spectacular changes in phenotypes and ecological functions. The contributions to this theme issue are the latest conceptual, theoretical and experimental developments, addressing how ecology, environment, ontogeny and evolution are central to understanding the complexity of the processes underlying innovations. Here, we set the stage by introducing and defining key terms relating to innovation and discuss their relevance to biological, cultural and technological change. Discovering how the generation and transmission of novel biological information, environmental interactions and selective evolutionary processes contribute to innovation as an ecosystem will shed light on how the dominant features across life come to be, generalize to social, cultural and technological evolution, and have applications in the health sciences and sustainability. This article is part of the theme issue 'Process and pattern in innovations from cells to societies'. OI Marquet, Pablo/0000-0001-6369-9339
WOS:000413446100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="16">
<title>Scale and diversity of the physical technosphere: A geological perspective</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/2053019616677743</url>
<snippet>We assess the scale and extent of the physical technosphere, defined here as the summed material output of the contemporary human enterprise. It includes active urban, agricultural and marine components, used to sustain energy and material flow for current human life, and a growing residue layer, currently only in small part recycled back into the active component. Preliminary estimates suggest a technosphere mass of approximately 30 trillion tonnes (Tt), which helps support a human biomass that, despite recent growth, is similar to 5 orders of magnitude smaller. The physical technosphere includes a large, rapidly growing diversity of complex objects that are potential trace fossils or technofossils. If assessed on palaeontological criteria, technofossil diversity already exceeds known estimates of biological diversity as measured by richness, far exceeds recognized fossil diversity, and may exceed total biological diversity through Earths history. The rapid transformation of much of Earths surface mass into the technosphere and its myriad components underscores the novelty of the current planetary transformation. OI IVAR DO SUL, JULIANA/0000-0003-0851-3559
WOS:000447103500002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="17">
<title>The role of utilities in developing low carbon, electric megacities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.enpol.2017.02.047</url>
<snippet>Development of electric cities, with low carbon power supply, is a key strategy for reducing global CO2 emissions. We analyze the role of electric utilities as important actors to catalyze the transition to electric cites, drawing upon data for the worlds 27 megacities. Progress towards the ideal electric city is most advanced for Paris, Rio de Janeiro, Sao Paulo and Buenos Aires for low carbon electricity, while Indian megacities have relatively high use of carbon-intensive electricity as a percentage of total energy use. There is wide variety in the structure of markets for electricity provision in megacities, with a dominant, public utility being the most common model. We review literature on electricity sector business models and broadly propose future models dependent on the predominance of locally dispersed generation and the nature of the ownership of the electric grid within the city. Where a high proportion of electricity can be provided by locally distributed supply within a city, the role of utilities could predominantly become that of enabler of exchange with the grid, but new pricing structures are required. A further challenge for utilities in enabling the electric city is to provide a higher level of resilience to events that disrupt power supply.
WOS:000402343600013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="18">
<title>Cities in the age of the Anthropocene: Climate change agents and the potential for mitigation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ancene.2017.08.001</url>
<snippet>Cities are human creations where many of the emissions causing climate change originate. Every aspect of daily life in cities, which spans buildings, transit, food, energy, and water, relies on fossil fuels that materially contribute to climate change. This paper explores the need for research to better uncover the processes driving urbanization in order to develop novel ways to mitigate climate impacts on Earth. Areas of fruitful research include better quantification of teleconnections between cities and their hinterlands and coupling those to the socio-economic drivers and organization of those relationships; the financialization of much urban policy; understanding where cities fit in the global economic order and their role in generating economic growth, and the ways in which they are also seen as leaders of sustainability and climate actions, but constrained in so-doing by the nested and tiered layers of institutions they operate within. This paper concludes by outlining ways for cities to transition toward nurturing human well-being and reducing their impacts on planetary processes resulting in the proposed new Earth epoch - the Anthropocene. 
WOS:000423549300008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="19">
<title>Transdisciplinary Application of Cross-Scale Resilience</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/su6106925</url>
<snippet>The cross-scale resilience model was developed in ecology to explain the emergence of resilience from the distribution of ecological functions within and across scales, and as a tool to assess resilience. We propose that the model and the underlying discontinuity hypothesis are relevant to other complex adaptive systems, and can be used to identify and track changes in system parameters related to resilience. We explain the theory behind the cross-scale resilience model, review the cases where it has been applied to non-ecological systems, and discuss some examples of social-ecological, archaeological/anthropological, and economic systems where a cross-scale resilience analysis could add a quantitative dimension to our current understanding of system dynamics and resilience. We argue that the scaling and diversity parameters suitable for a resilience analysis of ecological systems are appropriate for a broad suite of systems where non-normative quantitative assessments of resilience are desired. Our planet is currently characterized by fast environmental and social change, and the cross-scale resilience model has the potential to quantify resilience across many types of complex adaptive systems. OI Sundstrom, Shana/0000-0003-0823-8008
WOS:000344355700023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="20">
<title>The Metabolism and Growth of Web Forums</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0102646</url>
<snippet>We view web forums as virtual living organisms feeding on users clicks and investigate how they grow at the expense of clickstreams. We find that PVt (the number of page views in a given time period) and UVt (the number of unique visitors in the time period) of the studied forums satisfy the law of the allometric growth, i.e., PVt similar to UVt theta. We construct clickstream networks and explain the observed temporal dynamics of networks by the interactions between nodes. We describe the transportation of clickstreams using the function D-i similar to T-i(gamma), in which T-i is the total amount of clickstreams passing through node i and D-i is the amount of the clickstreams dissipated from i to the environment. It turns out that gamma, an indicator for the efficiency of network dissipation, not only negatively correlates with theta, but also sets the bounds for theta. In particular, 1/gamma &gt; theta when 0 &lt; gamma &lt; 1 and 1/gamma &lt; theta when gamma &gt; 1. Our findings have practical consequences. For example, theta can be used as a measure of the "stickiness of forums, which quantifies the stable ability of forums to remain users "lock-in on the forum. Meanwhile, the correlation between gamma and theta provides a method to predict the long-term "stickiness of forums from the clickstream data in a short time period. Finally, we discuss a random walk model that replicates both of the allometric growth PVt similar to UVt theta and the dissipation function D-i similar to T-i(gamma).
WOS:000341230400007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="21">
<title>Estimating the potential for industrial waste heat reutilization in urban district energy systems: method development and implementation in two Chinese provinces</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/aa8a17</url>
<snippet>Utilizing low-grade waste heat from industries to heat and cool homes and businesses through fourth generation district energy systems (DES) is a novel strategy to reduce energy use. This paper develops a generalizable methodology to estimate the energy saving potential for heating/cooling in 20 cities in two Chinese provinces, representing cold winter and hot summer regions respectively. We also conduct a life-cycle analysis of the new infrastructure required for energy exchange in DES. Results show that heating and cooling energy use reduction from this waste heat exchange strategy varies widely based on the mix of industrial, residential and commercial activities, and climate conditions in cities. Low-grade heat is found to be the dominant component of waste heat released by industries, which can be reused for both district heating and cooling in fourth generation DES, yielding energy use reductions from 12&#37;-91&#37; (average of 58&#37;) for heating and 24&#37;-100&#37; (average of 73&#37;) for cooling energy use in the different cities based on annual exchange potential. Incorporating seasonality and multiple energy exchange pathways resulted in energy savings reductions from 0&#37;-87&#37;. The life-cycle impact of added infrastructure was small (&lt; 3&#37; for heating) and 1.9&#37; similar to 6.5&#37;(cooling) of the carbon emissions from fuel use in current heating or cooling systems, indicating net carbon savings. This generalizable approach to delineate waste heat potential can help determine suitable cities for the widespread application of industrial waste heat re-utilization. RI wang, shuxiao/H-5990-2011 OI wang, shuxiao/0000-0001-9727-1963; Li, Yang/0000-0002-9134-2051
WOS:000417925700002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="22">
<title>Socio-Economic Instability and the Scaling of Energy Use with Population Size</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0130547</url>
<snippet>The size of the human population is relevant to the development of a sustainable world, yet the forces setting growth or declines in the human population are poorly understood. Generally, population growth rates depend on whether new individuals compete for the same energy (leading to Malthusian or density-dependent growth) or help to generate new energy (leading to exponential and super-exponential growth). It has been hypothesized that exponential and super-exponential growth in humans has resulted from carrying capacity, which is in part determined by energy availability, keeping pace with or exceeding the rate of population growth. We evaluated the relationship between energy use and population size for countries with long records of both and the world as a whole to assess whether energy yields are consistent with the idea of an increasing carrying capacity. We find that on average energy use has indeed kept pace with population size over long time periods. We also show, however, that the energy-population scaling exponent plummets during, and its temporal variability increases preceding, periods of social, political, technological, and environmental change. We suggest that efforts to increase the reliability of future energy yields may be essential for stabilizing both population growth and the global socio-economic system. OI Burger, Oskar/0000-0002-7552-5851; DeLong, John/0000-0003-0558-8213
WOS:000356835000125
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="23">
<title>Rare Earths from Mines to Metals Comparing Environmental Impacts from China's Main Production Pathways</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jiec.12491</url>
<snippet>Over the past decade, China has supplied over 90&#37; of global rare earths, and in doing so bore significant environmental burdens from processing its complex ores. In this study, we used life cycle assessment to quantify environmental impacts for producing 1 kilogram (kg) of 15 rare earth elements from each major production pathway. The scope of assessment included the largest rare earth oxide (REO) production chain in Bayan Obo, as well as lesser known production chains for bastnasite in Sichuan and in-situ leaching of kaolin clays in the Seven Southern Provinces of China. This was followed by assessing impacts from the three major metal refining processes: molten salt electrolysis, calciothermic reduction, and lanthanothermic reduction. Among 11 impact categories assessed, results were highest for human toxicity that ranged between 13.1 and 50.4 kg 1,4-dichlorobenzene-eq (equivalent)/kg of rare earth metal(-1), followed by eutrophication (0.04 to 1.26 kg phosphate-eq/kg of rare earth metal(-1)), abiotic depletion potential of fossil fuels (592 to 1,857 megajoules per kg of rare earth metal(-1)), acidification (0.25 to 0.87 kg sulfur dioxide-eq/kg of rare earth metal(-1)), and global warming (39.1 to 109.6 kg carbon dioxide-eq/kg of rare earth metal(-1)) potentials. Regionally, impacts in Sichuan were lower across all key impact categories than in Bayan Obo: 32&#37; lower for human toxicity, 67&#37; lower for eutrophication, 58&#37; lower for acidification, and 45&#37; lower for global warming. A scenario analysis between the industry average and best available technologies revealed considerable potential to mitigate impacts across all production chains, particularly by improving waste treatment practices.
WOS:000413579000019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="24">
<title>Network Centrality of Metro Systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0040575</url>
<snippet>Whilst being hailed as the remedy to the worlds ills, cities will need to adapt in the 21st century. In particular, the role of public transport is likely to increase significantly, and new methods and technics to better plan transit systems are in dire need. This paper examines one fundamental aspect of transit: network centrality. By applying the notion of betweenness centrality to 28 worldwide metro systems, the main goal of this paper is to study the emergence of global trends in the evolution of centrality with network size and examine several individual systems in more detail. Betweenness was notably found to consistently become more evenly distributed with size (i.e. no "winner takes all") unlike other complex network properties. Two distinct regimes were also observed that are representative of their structure. Moreover, the share of betweenness was found to decrease in a power law with size (with exponent 1 for the average node), but the share of most central nodes decreases much slower than least central nodes (0.87 vs. 2.48). Finally the betweenness of individual stations in several systems were examined, which can be useful to locate stations where passengers can be redistributed to relieve pressure from overcrowded stations. Overall, this study offers significant insights that can help planners in their task to design the systems of tomorrow, and similar undertakings can easily be imagined to other urban infrastructure systems (e.g., electricity grid, water/wastewater system, etc.) to develop more sustainable cities.
WOS:000306461800108
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="25">
<title>Innovation and the growth of human population</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2016.0415</url>
<snippet>Biodiversity is sustained by and is essential to the services that ecosystems provide. Different species would use these services in different ways, or adaptive strategies, which are sustained in time by continuous innovations. Using this framework, we postulate a model for a biological species (Homo sapiens) in a finite world where innovations, aimed at increasing the flux of ecosystem services (a measure of habitat quality), increase with population size, and have positive effects on the generation of new innovations (positive feedback) as well as costs in terms of negatively affecting the provision of ecosystem services. We applied this model to human populations, where technological innovations are driven by cumulative cultural evolution. Our model shows that depending on the net impact of a technology on the provision of ecosystem services (theta), and the strength of technological feedback (xi), different regimes can result. Among them, the human population can fill the entire planet while maximizing their well-being, but not exhaust ecosystem services. However, this outcome requires positive or green technologies that increase the provision of ecosystem services with few negative externalities or environmental costs, and that have a strong positive feedback in generating newtechnologies of the same kind. If the feedback is small, then the technological stock can collapse together with the human population. Scenarios where technological innovations generate net negative impacts may be associated with a limited technological stock as well as a limited human population at equilibrium and the potential for collapse. The only way to fill the planet with humans under this scenario of negative technologies is by reducing the technological stock to a minimum. Otherwise, the only feasible equilibrium is associated with population collapse. Our model points out that technological innovations per se may not help humans to grow and dominate the planet. Instead, different possibilities unfold for our future depending on their impact on the environment and on further innovation. This article is part of the themed issue 'Process and pattern in innovations from cells to societies'. OI Marquet, Pablo/0000-0001-6369-9339
WOS:000413446100002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="26">
<title>Environmental and natural resource implications of sustainable urban infrastructure systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/aa98ca</url>
<snippet>As cities grow, their environmental and natural resource footprints also tend to grow to keep up with the increasing demand on essential urban services such as passenger transportation, commercial space, and thermal comfort. The urban infrastructure systems, or socio-technical systems providing these services are the major conduits through which natural resources are consumed and environmental impacts are generated. This paper aims to gauge the potential reductions in environmental and resources footprints through urban transformation, including the deployment of resource-efficient socio-technical systems and strategic densification. Using hybrid life cycle assessment approach combined with scenarios, we analyzed the greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, water use, metal consumption and land use of selected socio-technical systems in 84 cities from the present to 2050. The socio-technical systems analyzed are: (1) bus rapid transit with electric buses, (2) green commercial buildings, and (3) district energy. We developed a baseline model for each city considering gross domestic product, population density, and climate conditions. Then, we overlaid three scenarios on top of the baseline model: (1) decarbonization of electricity, (2) aggressive deployment of resource-efficient socio-technical systems, and (3) strategic urban densification scenarios to each city and quantified their potentials in reducing the environmental and resource impacts of cities by 2050. The results show that, under the baseline scenario, the environmental and natural resource footprints of all 84 cities combined would increase 58&#37;-116&#37; by 2050. The resource-efficient scenario along with strategic densification, however, has the potential to curve down GHG emissions to 17&#37; below the 2010 level in 2050. Such transformation can also limit the increase in all resource footprints to less than 23&#37; relative to 2010. This analysis suggests that resource-efficient urban infrastructure and decarbonization of electricity coupled with strategic densification have a potential to mitigate resources and environmental footprints of growing cities. RI Baynes, Timothy/D-4738-2011 OI Baynes, Timothy/0000-0001-8416-3365; Suh, Sangwon/0000-0001-8290-6276
WOS:000417925700003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="27">
<title>Mapping collective behavior in the big-data era</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X13000289</url>
<snippet>The behavioral sciences have flourished by studying how traditional and/or rational behavior has been governed throughout most of human history by relatively well-informed individual and social learning. In the online age, however, social phenomena can occur with unprecedented scale and unpredictability, and individuals have access to social connections never before possible. Similarly, behavioral scientists now have access to "big data" sets - those from Twitter and Facebook, for example - that did not exist a few years ago. Studies of human dynamics based on these data sets are novel and exciting but, if not placed in context, can foster the misconception that mass-scale online behavior is all we need to understand, for example, how humans make decisions. To overcome that misconception, we draw on the field of discrete-choice theory to create a multiscale comparative "map" that, like a principal-components representation, captures the essence of decision making along two axes: (1) an east-west dimension that represents the degree to which an agent makes a decision independently versus one that is socially influenced, and (2) a north-south dimension that represents the degree to which there is transparency in the payoffs and risks associated with the decisions agents make. We divide the map into quadrants, each of which features a signature behavioral pattern. When taken together, the map and its signatures provide an easily understood empirical framework for evaluating how modern collective behavior may be changing in the digital age, including whether behavior is becoming more individualistic, as people seek out exactly what they want, or more social, as people become more inextricably linked, even "herdlike," in their decision making. We believe the map will lead to many new testable hypotheses concerning human behavior as well as to similar applications throughout the social sciences. OI Bentley, R. Alexander/0000-0001-9086-2197
WOS:000332474000031
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="28">
<title>The scaling structure of the global road network</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.170590</url>
<snippet>Because of increasing global urbanization and its immediate consequences, including changes in patterns of food demand, circulation and land use, the next century will witness a major increase in the extent of paved roads built worldwide. To model the effects of this increase, it is crucial to understand whether possible self-organized patterns are inherent in the global road network structure. Here, we use the largest updated database comprising all major roads on the Earth, together with global urban and cropland inventories, to suggest that road length distributions within croplands are indistinguishable from urban ones, once rescaled to account for the difference in mean road length. Such similarity extends to road length distributions within urban or agricultural domains of a given area. We find two distinct regimes for the scaling of the mean road length with the associated area, holding in general at small and at large values of the latter. In suitably large urban and cropland domains, we find that mean and total road lengths increase linearly with their domain area, differently from earlier suggestions. Scaling regimes suggest that simple and universal mechanisms regulate urban and cropland road expansion at the global scale. As such, our findings bear implications for global road infrastructure growth based on land-use change and for planning policies sustaining urban expansions. OI Giometto, Andrea/0000-0002-0544-6023
WOS:000413965600016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="29">
<title>A Dynamic Network Measure of Technological Change</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2015.2366</url>
<snippet>This article outlines a network approach to the study of technological change. We propose that new inventions reshape networks of interlinked technologies by shifting inventors attention to or away from the knowledge on which those inventions build. Using this approach, we develop novel indexes of the extent to which a new invention consolidates or destabilizes existing technology streams. We apply these indexes in analyses of university research commercialization and find that, although federal research funding pushes campuses to create inventions that are more destabilizing, deeper commercial ties lead them to produce technologies that consolidate the status quo. By quantifying the effects that new technologies have on their predecessors, the indexes we propose allow patent-based studies of innovation to capture conceptually important phenomena that are not detectable with established measures. The measurement approach presented here offers empirical insights that support theoretical development in studies of innovation, entrepreneurship, technology strategy, science policy, and social network theory. OI Owen-Smith, Jason/0000-0001-8007-1121
WOS:000395813600011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="30">
<title>CO2 emissions in relation to street-network configuration and city size</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.trd.2014.11.025</url>
<snippet>The street-network efficiency of tens of British cities in relation to transport fuel consumption and CO2 emissions are analyzed. The results show a strong linear positive correlation between length entropy and average street length, and a negative correlation between entropy and street density. Also, the results suggest that in a large city the street network is used more efficiently than in a small city, as indicated by the sublinear relations between city size (population) and the number of streets, total length of streets, and the area covered by the street network. The sublinear relation means that these parameters grow more slowly than the city size. By contrast, because a larger fraction of the street network is used at close to full capacity during considerable part of the time in a large city than a small one, the fuel consumption and the CO2 emissions show a linear relation with city size and superlinear relation with total street length. The superlinear relation means that the CO2 emissions increase faster than the total street length, a measure of the network size. Thus, large cities may be less energy efficient and environmentally friendly than small cities. In every city the street network needs to interconnect all the buildings, which requires a certain minimum size. In a small city, however, the network is used to a low capacity most of the time so that its relations to fuel consumption and the CO2 emissions are more favorable than those in a large city. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000350525300009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="31">
<title>Zipf's law, 1/f noise, and fractal hierarchy</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.chaos.2011.10.001</url>
<snippet>Fractals, 1/f noise, and Zipfs laws are frequently observed within the natural living world as well as in social institutions, representing three signatures of complex systems. All these observations are associated with scaling laws and therefore have created much research interest in many diverse scientific circles. However, the inherent relationships between these scaling phenomena are not yet clear. In this paper, theoretical demonstration and mathematical experiments based on urban studies are employed to reveal the analogy between fractal patterns, 1/f spectra, and the Zipf distribution. First, the multifractal process empirically suggests the Zipf distribution. Second, a 1/f spectrum is mathematically identical to Zipfs law. Third, both spectra and Zipfs law can be converted into a self-similar hierarchy. Fourth, fractals, 1/f spectra, Zipfs law can be rescaled with similar exponential laws and power laws. The self-similar hierarchy is a more general scaling method which can be used to unify different scaling phenomena and rules in both physical and social systems such as cities, rivers, earthquakes, fractals, 1/f noise, and rank-size distributions. The mathematical laws of this hierarchical structure can provide us with a holistic perspective of looking at complexity and complex systems. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000300595500007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="32">
<title>Impact of Changing Technology on the Evolution of Complex Informational Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JPROC.2014.2367132</url>
<snippet>We live in an era of increasing connectivity in human societies and in technology. These structural changes in the ways we interact with each other and with increasingly ubiquitous computational and communication devices have been formalized in research across several disciplines through the dynamics of complex informational networks. Complex networks are (mathematical) graphs, connecting nodes (people, computers) via edges (relationships, wires). While much progress in methods for network analysis has been achieved, the fundamental principles that drive network growth in human societies and in worldwide computer networks remain rather obscure. Mechanistic models for the origin of certain structural graph elements have now become common, but the formal connection between large empirical studies of network evolution and fundamental concepts of information, learning, and social theory remains only latent. To address these issues, I argue here that the most interesting aspect of the dynamics of informational networks in complex systems is that they are the physical manifestations of processes of evolution, inference, and learning, from natural ecosystems, to cities and to online environments. I formalize the general problem of learning and computation in network environments in terms of average structural network changes and propose a conceptual framework to explain the transition from initially static, undifferentiated, and information-poor environments to dynamical, richly diverse, and interconnected systems. I illustrate these ideas empirically by providing examples from cities, and from global computer networks and webs of documents. I finish with an overview of expected changes to urban form and function and to computational hardware under likely technological scenarios.
WOS:000345524100003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="33">
<title>The size of cities: A synthesis of multi-disciplinary perspectives on the global' megalopolis</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.progress.2016.03.001</url>
<snippet>This interdisciplinary treatise integrates notions from the biological, geographical, sociological, politico administrative, economic, psychological, futurist, and other scientific literature about the expansion of urban areas by taking the reader through a series of conjectures about the practical upper limits of the size of cities, and centering the discussion around the possibilities for a world-spanning megalopolis or city-planet. It specifically frames urban growth against a survey of known conceptual and logical limits established by previous research in the natural and social sciences, and demonstrates that while there are absolute and practical constraints to the establishment of what the author calls a Pangaean City, they might be overcome"by new technologies, innovations in governance, and behavioral adjustments. The author also shows that there are prior, overlapping, or parallel sociopolitical and cultural constraints that govern city size,,and that while these are not immutable, they represent sets of actual influences on development of the magnified urban form itself, including its reach beyond physical presence. Finally, while it is shown that a thorough-going planetary urbanization may be physically impossible, the research concludes by suggesting what planners can or should do about such a phenomenon. It further relates the discussion to the rich body of utopian planning literature, where the aspiration for an all embracing urbanity remains to mirror the panoramic analyses of this paper. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000411551500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="34">
<title>Identifying Concavity Laws of Attractiveness Character for Composite Regions Application through Geo-tagged Media Check-ins</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>In this era of social networking sites, peoples behavior online could help us have an idea about their offline lives as well. Social check-ins, which store geo-tagged information about users, can be utilized by researchers to investigate the tastes and preferences of individuals for the places they live in or travel to. In this paper, I introduce one possible research direction that can be taken using Yahoo Flickr Creative Commons 100M dataset of publically available geo-tagged media objects. I intended to focus this study on investigating the attractiveness character of most checked-in countries and large-scale composite regions, like the states of US, for foreign tourists. The attractiveness character is specified as the total amount of media check-ins done by the visitors compared to the population size of the country or state. In addition to this, I utilize International migrations dataset, made available publically by UN, to analyze the attractiveness potential of destination countries/states from a long-term perspective too. As most studies show that the attractiveness of cities follows a super-linear trend, my study is about identifying if the same trend is applicable to the attractiveness of large-scale composite regions too. In the end, the explanation of the results is discussed.
WOS:000427628300184
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="35">
<title>The niche construction of cultural complexity: interactions between innovations, population size and the environment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2016.0428</url>
<snippet>Niche construction is a process through which organisms alter their environments and, in doing so, influence or change the selective pressures to which they are subject. Cultural niche construction refers specifically to the effect of cultural traits on the selective environments of other biological or cultural traits and may be especially important in human evolution. In addition, the relationship between population size and cultural accumulation has been the subject of extensive debate, in part because anthropological studies have demonstrated a significant association between population size and toolkit complexity in only a subset of studied cultures. Here, we review the role of cultural innovation in constructing human evolutionary niches and introduce a new model to describe the accumulation of human cultural traits that incorporates the effects of cultural niche construction. We consider the results of this model in light of available data on human toolkit sizes across populations to help elucidate the important differences between food-gathering societies and food-producing societies, in which niche construction may be a more potent force. These results support the idea that a populations relationship with its environment, represented here by cultural niche construction, should be considered alongside population size in studies of cultural complexity. This article is part of the themed issue 'Process and pattern in innovations from cells to societies'. OI Creanza, Nicole/0000-0001-8821-7383
WOS:000413446100014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="36">
<title>Political economies and environmental futures for the sharing economy</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsta.2016.0367</url>
<snippet>The sudden rise of the sharing economy has sparked an intense public debate about its definition, its effects and its future regulation. Here, I attempt to provide analytical guidance by defining the sharing economy as the practice that consumers grant each other temporary access to their under-utilized physical assets. Using this definition, the rise of the sharing economy can be understood as occurring at the intersection of three salient economic trends: peer-topeer exchange, access over ownership and circular business models. I shortly discuss some of the environmental impacts of online sharing platforms and then articulate three possible futures of the sharing economy: a capitalist future cumulating in monopolistic super-platforms allowing for seamless services, a state-led future that shifts taxation from labour to capital and redistributes the gains of sharing from winners to losers, and a citizen-led future based on cooperatively owned platforms under democratic control. The nature and size of the social and environmental impacts are expected to differ greatly in each of the three scenarios.
WOS:000400238600006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="37">
<title>Extra-metabolic energy use and the rise in human hyper-density</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep43869</url>
<snippet>Humans, like all organisms, are subject to fundamental biophysical laws. Van Valen predicted that, because of zero-sum dynamics, all populations of all species in a given environment flux the same amount of energy on average. Damuths energetic equivalence rulesupported Van Valen s conjecture by showing a tradeoff between few big animals per area with high individual metabolic rates compared to abundant small species with low energy requirements. We use metabolic scaling theory to compare variation in densities and individual energy use in human societies to other land mammals. We show that hunter-gatherers occurred at densities lower than the average for a mammal of our size. Most modern humans, in contrast, concentrate in large cities at densities up to four orders of magnitude greater than hunter-gatherers, yet consume up to two orders of magnitude more energy per capita. Today, cities across the globe flux greater energy than net primary productivity on a per area basis. This is possible by importing enormous amounts of energy and materials required to sustain hyper-dense, modern humans. The metabolic rift with nature created by modern cities fueled largely by fossil energy poses formidable challenges for establishing a sustainable relationship on a rapidly urbanizing, yet finite planet.
WOS:000395581200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="38">
<title>Urbanization and the carbon cycle: Contributions from social science</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/2014EF000257</url>
<snippet>This paper outlines the contributions of social science to the study of interactions between urbanization patterns and processes and the carbon cycle, and identifies gaps in knowledge and priority areas for future social scientific research contributions. While previously studied as a unidimensional process, we conceptualize urbanization as a multidimensional, social and biophysical process driven by continuous changes across space and time in various subsystems including biophysical, built environment, and socio-institutional (e.g., economic, political, demographic, behavioral, and sociological). We review research trends and findings focused on the socio-institutional subsystem of the urbanization process, and particularly the dynamics, relationships, and predictions relevant to energy use and greenhouse gas emissions. Our findings suggest that a multidimensional perspective of urbanization facilitates a wider spectrum of research relevant to carbon cycle dynamics, even within the socio-institutional subsystem. However, there is little consensus around the details and mechanisms underlying the relationship between urban socio-institutional subsystems and the carbon cycle. We argue that progress in understanding the relationship between urbanization and the carbon cycle may be achieved if social scientists work collaboratively with each other as well as with scientists from other disciplines. From this review, we identify research priorities where collaborative social scientific efforts are necessary in conjunction with other disciplinary approaches to generate a more complete understanding of urbanization as a process and its relationship to the carbon cycle. RI Seto, Karen/C-2722-2008 OI Sarzynski, Andrea/0000-0001-9941-5764; Marcotullio, Peter/0000-0001-8133-1204
WOS:000358136100003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="39">
<title>Building a science of cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cities.2011.11.008</url>
<snippet>Our understanding of cities is being transformed by new approaches from the complexity sciences (Batty, 2005). Here we review progress, sketching the background beginning with the systems approach which treated systems as being organised from the top down to that which now dominates where systems are treated as evolving from the bottom up. The switch in thinking we describe is best pictured in the transition from thinking of cities as machines to cities as organisms. We first review developments in the dynamics of cities where the notion of equilibrium has been replaced by a veritable potpourri of different types such as chaos, catastrophes, and bifurcations. We then look at patterns and processes that give rise to morphologies that illustrate fractal patterns and self-similarity. We follow this with ideas about networks and interactions that sustain cities through their transport and then we show how such processes of movement and mobility can give rise to the diffusion and segregation of different spatial activities. In all these developments, ideas about scaling that relate size, shape and scale in space and time are evident and we thus sketch three scaling laws based on rank-size, allometry and gravitation that are central to our synthesis of how spatial processes give rise to physical morphologies. We conclude with notions about how these ideas are being embedded into models that have potential applications to inform policy. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. RI Batty, Michael/I-5638-2014
WOS:000300813400003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="40">
<title>Organization and scaling in water supply networksnn</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.96.062317</url>
<snippet>Public water supply is one of the societys most vital resources and most costly infrastructures. Traditional concepts of these networks capture their engineering identity as isolated, deterministic hydraulic units, but overlook their physics identity as related entities in a probabilistic, geographic ensemble, characterized by size organization and property scaling. Although discoveries of allometric scaling in natural supply networks (organisms and rivers) raised the prospect for similar findings in anthropogenic supplies, so far such a finding has not been reported in public water or related civic resource supplies. Examining an empirical ensemble of large number and wide size range, we show that water supply networks possess self-organized size abundance and theory-explained allometric scaling in spatial, infrastructural, and resource-and emission-flow properties. These discoveries establish scaling physics for water supply networks and may lead to novel applications in resource and jurisdiction-scale water governance.
WOS:000419014700004
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
