<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Information dynamics shape the sexual networks of Internet-mediated prostitution</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0914080107</url>
<snippet>Like many other social phenomena, prostitution is increasingly coordinated over the Internet. The online behavior affects the offline activity; the reverse is also true. We investigated the reported sexual contacts between 6,624 anonymous escorts and 10,106 sex buyers extracted from an online community from its beginning and six years on. These sexual encounters were also graded and categorized (in terms of the type of sexual activities performed) by the buyers. From the temporal, bipartite network of posts, we found a full feedback loop in which high grades on previous posts affect the future commercial success of the sex worker, and vice versa. We also found a peculiar growth pattern in which the turnover of community members and sex workers causes a sublinear preferential attachment. There is, moreover, a strong geographic influence on network structure-the network is geographically clustered but still close to connected, the contacts consistent with the inverse-square law observed in trading patterns. We also found that the number of sellers scales sublinearly with city size, so this type of prostitution does not, comparatively speaking, benefit much from an increasing concentration of people. RI Holme, Petter/A-7646-2008; Rocha, Luis/D-5333-2011; Liljeros, Fredrik/I-2667-2018 OI Holme, Petter/0000-0003-2156-1096; Liljeros, Fredrik/0000-0001-8642-6624; Correa Rocha, Luis Enrique/0000-0001-9046-8739
WOS:000276159500005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>Measuring social dynamics in a massive multiplayer online game</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2010.06.001</url>
<snippet>Quantification of human group-behavior has so far defied an empirical, falsifiable approach. This is due to tremendous difficulties in data acquisition of social systems. Massive multiplayer online games (MMOG) provide a fascinating new way of observing hundreds of thousands of simultaneously socially interacting individuals engaged in virtual economic activities. We have compiled a data set consisting of practically all actions of all players over a period of 3 years from a MMOG played by 300,000 people. This large-scale data set of a socio-economic unit contains all social and economic data from a single and coherent source. Players have to generate a virtual income through economic activities to survive and are typically engaged in a multitude of social activities offered within the game. Our analysis of high-frequency log files focuses on three types of social networks, and tests a series of social-dynamics hypotheses. In particular we study the structure and dynamics of friend-, enemy- and communication networks. We find striking differences in topological structure between positive (friend) and negative (enemy) tie networks. All networks confirm the recently observed phenomenon of network densification. We propose two approximate social laws in communication networks, the first expressing betweenness centrality as the inverse square of the overlap, the second relating communication strength to the cube of the overlap. These empirical laws provide strong quantitative evidence for the Weak ties hypothesis of Granovetter. Further, the analysis of triad significance profiles validates well-established assertions from social balance theory. We find overrepresentation (underrepresentation) of complete (incomplete) triads in networks of positive ties, and vice versa for networks of negative ties. Empirical transition probabilities between triad classes provide evidence for triadic closure with extraordinarily high precision. For the first time we provide empirical results for large-scale networks of negative social ties. Whenever possible we compare our findings with data from non-virtual human groups and provide further evidence that online game communities serve as a valid model for a wide class of human societies. With this setup we demonstrate the feasibility for establishing a socio-economic laboratory which allows to operate at levels of precision approaching those of the natural sciences. All data used in this study is fully anonymized: the authors have the written consent to publish from the legal department of the Medical University of Vienna. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Szell, Michael/H-5269-2011 OI Szell, Michael/0000-0003-3022-2483
WOS:000283402000006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Understanding, managing, and minimizing urban impacts on surface water nitrogen loading</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1196/annals.1439.014</url>
<snippet>The concentration of materials and energy within cities is an inevitable consequence of dense populations and their per capita requirements for food, fiber, and fuel. As the world population becomes increasingly urban over the coming decades, urban areas will dramatically affect the distribution of nutrients across the face of the planet. In many cities, technological developments and urban planning have been effective at reducing the amount of waste nitrogen that is ultimately exported to downstream surface waters, largely through investments in sanitary sewer infrastructure and wastewater treatment. There are, however, still large cities throughout the developed world that have failed to take advantage of these obvious innovations to reduce their impact on downstream ecosystems. In addition, very few cities have adequately addressed the problems of diffuse nitrogen pollution, instead city infrastructure is often designed to route this N directly into downstream ecosystems. In the developing world, many of these problems are more acute, as rapidly growing urban populations exceed the capacity of limited municipal infrastructure. Reducing urban N pollution of groundwaters and surface waters both locally and globally can only be achieved through cultural and political adaptation in addition to technological innovations. In this review, we will focus on the implications of an increasingly urban world population on local, regional, and global nitrogen cycles and propose a variety of approaches for minimizing and mitigating the impacts of urban N concentration. RI Walsh, Christopher/B-2552-2009; Bernhardt, Emily/D-9940-2011; Bernhardt, Emily/B-4541-2010 OI Walsh, Christopher/0000-0002-4181-6722; Bernhardt, Emily/0000-0003-3031-621X;
WOS:000257506400003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>The evolution of prompt reaction to adverse ties</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/1471-2148-8-287</url>
<snippet>Background: In recent years it has been found that the combination of evolutionary game theory with population structures modelled in terms of dynamical graphs, in which individuals are allowed to sever unwanted social ties while keeping the good ones, provides a viable solution to the conundrum of cooperation. It is well known that in reality individuals respond differently to disadvantageous interactions. Yet, the evolutionary mechanism determining the individuals willingness to sever unfavourable ties remains unclear. Results: We introduce a novel way of thinking about the joint evolution of cooperation and social contacts. The struggle for survival between cooperators and defectors leads to an arms race for swiftness in adjusting social ties, based purely on a self-regarding, individual judgement. Since defectors are never able to establish social ties under mutual agreement, they break adverse ties more rapidly than cooperators, who tend to evolve stable and long-term relations. Ironically, defectors' constant search for partners to exploit leads to heterogeneous networks that improve the survivability of cooperators, compared to the traditional homogenous population assumption. Conclusion: When communities face the prisoner's dilemma, swift reaction to adverse ties evolves when competition is fierce between cooperators and defectors, providing an evolutionary basis for the necessity of individuals to adjust their social ties. Our results show how our innate resilience to change relates to mutual agreement between cooperators and how "loyalty" or persistent social ties bring along an evolutionary disadvantage, both from an individual and group perspective. RI Pacheco, Jorge/B-6116-2008; Santos, Francisco/D-2394-2010 OI Pacheco, Jorge/0000-0002-2579-8499; Santos, Francisco/0000-0002-9103-2862; Lenaerts, Tom/0000-0003-3645-1455
WOS:000260656400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>Dynamic peer-to-peer competition</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2010.02.032</url>
<snippet>The dynamic behavior of a multiagent system in which the agent size si is variable it is studied along a Lotka-Volterra approach. The agent size has hereby the meaning of the fraction of a given market that an agent is able to capture (market share). A Lotka-Volterra system of equations for prey-predator problems is considered, the competition factor being related to the difference in size between the agents in a one-on-one competition. This mechanism introduces a natural self-organized dynamic competition among agents. In the competition factor, a parameter sigma is introduced for scaling the intensity of agent size similarity, which varies in each iteration cycle. The fixed points of this system are analytically found and their stability analyzed for small systems (with n = 5 agents). We have found that different scenarios are possible, from chaotic to non-chaotic motion with cluster formation as function of the a parameter and depending on the initial conditions imposed to the system. The present contribution aim is to show how a realistic though minimalist nonlinear dynamics model can be used to describe the market competition (companies, brokers, decision makers) among other opinion maker communities. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Caiafa, Cesar/A-6045-2010 OI Caiafa, Cesar/0000-0001-5437-6095
WOS:000277824800016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>Mother-child emotional availability in ecological perspective: Three countries, two regions, two genders</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0012-1649.44.3.666</url>
<snippet>This study used a cross-national framework to examine country, region, and gender differences in emotional availability (EA), a prominent index of mutual socioemotional adaptation in the parent-child dyad. Altogether 220 Argentine, Italian, and U.S. mothers and their daughters and sons from both rural and metropolitan areas took part in home observations when the children were 20 months old. In terms of country, Italian mothers were more sensitive and optimally structuring, and Italian children were more responsive and involving, than Argentine and U.S. dyads. In terms of region, rural mothers were more intrusive than metropolitan mothers, and boys from metropolitan areas were more responsive than boys from rural areas. In terms of gender, mothers of girls were more sensitive and optimally structuring than mothers of boys, and daughters were more responsive and involving than sons. Understanding how country, region, and gender influence EA exposes forces that shape child development, parent-infant interaction, and family systems. RI Putnick, Diane/B-1707-2009 OI De Falco, Simona/0000-0001-9137-2958; Putnick, Diane/0000-0002-6323-749X
WOS:000255842800004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>Research core and framework of sustainability science</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11625-008-0053-1</url>
<snippet>This paper reviews recent achievements in sustainability science and discusses the research core and framework of sustainability science. We analyze and organize papers published in three selected core journals of sustainability science: Sustainability Science, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, and Sustainability: Science, Practice, &amp; Policy. Papers are organized into three categories: sustainability and its definition, domain-oriented research, and a research framework for sustainability science. First, we provide a short history and define the basic characteristics of sustainability; then we review current efforts in the following research domains: climate, biodiversity, agriculture, fishery, forestry, energy and resources, water, economic development, health, and lifestyle. Finally, we propose a research framework for sustainability science that includes the following components: goal setting, indicator setting, indicator measurement, causal chain analysis, forecasting, backcasting, and problem-solution chain analysis. We emphasize the importance of this last component for improving situations and attaining goals. RI Kajikawa, Yuya/C-1996-2015 OI Kajikawa, Yuya/0000-0003-3577-5167
WOS:000264104100006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Negative density-area relationships: the importance of the zeros</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1466-8238.2007.00354.x</url>
<snippet>Aim Estimates of abundances and densities of birds and mammals have often been shown to be scale dependent, in that population sizes over large areas are overestimated if extrapolated from surveys of small plots. Previous tests of the mechanisms suggested to cause this decelerating scaling pattern found evidence of a biased choice of small plots in patches of homogeneous habitat. Here we show that negative density-area relationships can also arise as result of not considering plots where individuals of the species or assemblage of interest are absent in surveys of differing spatial resolution. Location We took a complete census of violets (Viola spp.) in 800 m(2) of chalk grassland in Wye, Kent, UK, and used human population censuses for Finnish, Swiss and Italian municipalities, English districts, states of the USA and European countries. Methods We used mixed models of logarithmically transformed number of individuals or densities as a function of area. Results The census of violets shows that by increasing the survey resolution and by not considering plots without individuals, the effectively occupied area diminishes and a negative density-area relationship arises. The finding that negative density-area relationships are also common for people is evidence that the non-random choice of plots in population surveys of varying areas can be responsible for many observed negative density-area relationships. The shallower slope of the people-administrative area relationship for Switzerland and Finland compared with Italy, as well as for England and the USA compared with Europe, confirms that less than proportionate individuals-area relationships can be the consequence of larger plot areas containing a higher proportion of areas without individuals. Main conclusions Densities should be reported together with the effective areas for which they were estimated. It should be clearly conveyed whether or not plots where the surveyed species was absent were included in the density estimation. OI Pautasso, Marco/0000-0003-1850-6416
WOS:000252966000006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>Global change and the ecology of cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.1150195</url>
<snippet>Urban areas are hot spots that drive environmental change at multiple scales. Material demands of production and human consumption alter land use and cover, biodiversity, and hydrosystems locally to regionally, and urban waste discharge affects local to global biogeochemical cycles and climate. For urbanites, however, global environmental changes are swamped by dramatic changes in the local environment. Urban ecology integrates natural and social sciences to study these radically altered local environments and their regional and global effects. Cities themselves present both the problems and solutions to sustainability challenges of an increasingly urbanized world. RI Grimm, Nancy/D-2840-2009; Wu, Jianguo/G-6267-2010; Bai, Xuemei/H-7072-2012; Bai, Xuemei/A-5443-2012; WU, Jingle/A-4055-2009 OI Grimm, Nancy/0000-0001-9374-660X; Bai, Xuemei/0000-0001-6556-8041;
WOS:000252963000045
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
