<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Allometric scaling of foraging rate with trail dimensions in leaf-cutting ants</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2011.2583</url>
<snippet>Leaf-cutting ants (Atta spp.) create physical pathways to support the transport of resources on which colony growth and reproduction depend. We determined the scaling relationship between the rate of resource acquisition and the size of the trail system and foraging workforce for 18 colonies of Atta colombica and Atta cephalotes. We examined conventional power-law scaling patterns, but did so in a multivariate analysis that reveals the simultaneous effects of forager number, trail length and trail width. Foraging rate (number of resource-laden ants returning to the nest per unit time) scaled at the 0.93 power of worker numbers, the -1.02 power of total trail length and the 0.65 power of trail width. These scaling exponents indicate that individual performance declines only slightly as more foragers are recruited to the workforce, but that trail length imposes a severe penalty on the foraging rate. A model of mass traffic flow predicts the allometric patterns for workforce and trail length, although the effect of trail width is unexpected and points to the importance of the little-known mechanisms that regulate a colonys investment in trail clearance. These results provide a point of comparison for the role that resource flows may play in allometric scaling patterns in other transport-dependent entities, such as human cities. OI Burd, Martin/0000-0002-1175-2596
WOS:000303888500021
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>Human macroecology: linking pattern and process in big-picture human ecology</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-185X.2011.00192.x</url>
<snippet>Humans have a dual nature. We are subject to the same natural laws and forces as other species yet dominate global ecology and exhibit enormous variation in energy use, cultural diversity, and apparent social organization. We suggest scientists tackle these challenges with a macroecological approachusing comparative statistical techniques to identify deep patterns of variation in large datasets and to test for causal mechanisms. We show the power of a metabolic perspective for interpreting these patterns and suggesting possible underlying mechanisms, one that focuses on the exchange of energy and materials within and among human societies and with the biophysical environment. Examples on human foraging ecology, life history, space use, population structure, disease ecology, cultural and linguistic diversity patterns, and industrial and urban systems showcase the power and promise of this approach. OI Burger, Oskar/0000-0002-7552-5851
WOS:000298732300010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Models and tests of optimal density and maximal yield for crop plants</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1210955109</url>
<snippet>We introduce a theoretical framework that predicts the optimum planting density and maximal yield for an annual crop plant. Two critical parameters determine the trajectory of plant growth and the optimal density, N-opt, where canopies of growing plants just come into contact, and competition: (i) maximal size at maturity, M-max, which differs among varieties due to artificial selection for different usable products; and (ii) intrinsic growth rate, g, which may vary with variety and environmental conditions. The model predicts (i) when planting density is less than N-opt, all plants of a cropmature at the same maximal size, M-max, and biomass yield per area increases linearly with density; and (ii) when planting density is greater than N-opt, size at maturity and yield decrease with -4/3 and -1/3 powers of density, respectively. Field data from China show that most annual crops, regardless of variety and life form, exhibit similar scaling relations, with maximal size at maturity, M-max, accounting for most of the variation in optimal density, maximal yield, and energy use per area. Crops provide elegantly simple empirical model systems to study basic processes that determine the performance of plants in agricultural and less managed ecosystems.
WOS:000309604500062
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Growth, metabolic partitioning, and the size of microorganisms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1115585109</url>
<snippet>Population growth rate is a fundamental ecological and evolutionary characteristic of living organisms, but individuals must balance the metabolism devoted to biosynthesis and reproduction against the maintenance of existing structure and other functionality. Here we present a mathematical model that relates metabolic partitioning to the form of growth. The model captures the observed growth trajectory of single cells and individuals for a variety of species and taxa spanning prokaryotes, unicellular eukaryotes, and small multicellular eukaryotes. Our analysis suggests that the per-unit costs of biosynthesis and maintenance are conserved across prokaryotes and eukaryotes. However, the relative metabolic expenditure on growth and maintenance of whole organisms clearly differentiates taxa: prokaryotes spend an increasing fraction of their entire metabolism on growth with increasing cell size, whereas eukaryotes devote a diminishing fraction. These differences allow us to predict the minimum and maximum size for each taxonomic group, anticipating observed evolutionary life-history transitions. The framework provides energetic insights into taxonomic tradeoffs related to growth and metabolism and constrains traits that are important for size-structured modeling of microbial communities and their ecological and biogeochemical effects.
WOS:000298950200035
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
