<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Scaling laws in the dynamics of crime growth rate</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2013.02.002</url>
<snippet>The increasing number of crimes in areas with large concentrations of people have made cities one of the main sources of violence. Understanding characteristics of how crime rate expands and its relations with the cities size goes beyond an academic question, being a central issue for contemporary society. Here, we characterize and analyze quantitative aspects of murders in the period from 1980 to 2009 in Brazilian cities. We find that the distribution of the annual, biannual and triannual logarithmic homicide growth rates exhibit the same functional form for distinct scales, that is, a scale invariant behavior. We also identify asymptotic power-law decay relations between the standard deviations of these three growth rates and the initial size. Further, we discuss similarities with complex organizations. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Ribeiro, Haroldo/C-8614-2012; Alves, Luiz/H-3389-2013; Mendes, Renio/F-9261-2017 OI Ribeiro, Haroldo/0000-0002-9532-5195; Alves, Luiz/0000-0001-6204-5552;
WOS:000317699400006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>The Area and Population of Cities: New Insights from a Different Perspective on Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1257/aer.101.5.2205</url>
<snippet>
WOS:000293892300019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Toward a synthetic economic systems modeling tool for sustainable exploitation of ecosystems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.2010.05901.x</url>
<snippet>Environmental resources that underpin the basic human needs of water, energy, and food are predicted to become in such short supply by 2050 that global security and the well-being of millions will be under threat. These natural commodities have been allowed to reach crisis levels of supply because of a failure of economic systems to sustain them. This is largely because there have been no means of integrating their exploitation into any economic model that effectively addresses ecological systemic failures in a way that provides an integrated ecological-economic tool that can monitor and evaluate market and policy targets. We review the reasons for this and recent attempts to address the problem while identifying outstanding issues. The key elements of a policy-oriented economic model that integrates ecosystem processes are described and form the basis of a proposed new synthesis approach. The approach is illustrated by an indicative case study that develops a simple model for rainfed and irrigated food production in the Murray-Darling basin of southeastern Australia.
WOS:000288933600009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Distance to the Scaling Law: A Useful Approach for Unveiling Relationships between Crime and Urban Metrics</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0069580</url>
<snippet>We report on a quantitative analysis of relationships between the number of homicides, population size and ten other urban metrics. By using data from Brazilian cities, we show that well-defined average scaling laws with the population size emerge when investigating the relations between population and number of homicides as well as population and urban metrics. We also show that the fluctuations around the scaling laws are log-normally distributed, which enabled us to model these scaling laws by a stochastic-like equation driven by a multiplicative and log-normally distributed noise. Because of the scaling laws, we argue that it is better to employ logarithms in order to describe the number of homicides in function of the urban metrics via regression analysis. In addition to the regression analysis, we propose an approach to correlate crime and urban metrics via the evaluation of the distance between the actual value of the number of homicides ( as well as the value of the urban metrics) and the value that is expected by the scaling law with the population size. This approach has proved to be robust and useful for unveiling relationships/behaviors that were not properly carried out by the regression analysis, such as i) the non-explanatory potential of the elderly population when the number of homicides is much above or much below the scaling law, ii) the fact that unemployment has explanatory potential only when the number of homicides is considerably larger than the expected by the power law, and iii) a gender difference in number of homicides, where cities with female population below the scaling law are characterized by a number of homicides above the power law. RI Mendes, Renio/F-9261-2017; Ribeiro, Haroldo/C-8614-2012; Alves, Luiz/H-3389-2013 OI Ribeiro, Haroldo/0000-0002-9532-5195; Alves, Luiz/0000-0001-6204-5552; Lenzi, Ervin/0000-0003-3853-1790
WOS:000324465000019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>Dependence of the Firearm-Related Homicide Rate on Gun Availability: A Mathematical Analysis</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0071606</url>
<snippet>In the USA, the relationship between the legal availability of guns and the firearm-related homicide rate has been debated. It has been argued that unrestricted gun availability promotes the occurrence of firearm-induced homicides. It has also been pointed out that gun possession can protect potential victims when attacked. This paper provides a first mathematical analysis of this tradeoff, with the goal to steer the debate towards arguing about assumptions, statistics, and scientific methods. The model is based on a set of clearly defined assumptions, which are supported by available statistical data, and is formulated axiomatically such that results do not depend on arbitrary mathematical expressions. According to this framework, two alternative scenarios can minimize the gun-related homicide rate: a ban of private firearms possession, or a policy allowing the general population to carry guns. Importantly, the model identifies the crucial parameters that determine which policy minimizes the death rate, and thus serves as a guide for the design of future epidemiological studies. The parameters that need to be measured include the fraction of offenders that illegally possess a gun, the degree of protection provided by gun ownership, and the fraction of the population who take up their right to own a gun and carry it when attacked. Limited data available in the literature were used to demonstrate how the model can be parameterized, and this preliminary analysis suggests that a ban of private firearm possession, or possibly a partial reduction in gun availability, might lower the rate of firearm-induced homicides. This, however, should not be seen as a policy recommendation, due to the limited data available to inform and parameterize the model. However, the model clearly defines what needs to be measured, and provides a basis for a scientific discussion about assumptions and data. OI Abbott, Derek/0000-0002-0945-2674
WOS:000322838900191
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>The Collaborative Image of The City: Mapping the Inequality of Urban Perception</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0068400</url>
<snippet>A traveler visiting Rio, Manila or Caracas does not need a report to learn that these cities are unequal; she can see it directly from the taxicab window. This is because in most cities inequality is conspicuous, but also, because cities express different forms of inequality that are evident to casual observers. Cities are highly heterogeneous and often unequal with respect to the income of their residents, but also with respect to the cleanliness of their neighborhoods, the beauty of their architecture, and the liveliness of their streets, among many other evaluative dimensions. Until now, however, our ability to understand the effect of a citys built environment on social and economic outcomes has been limited by the lack of quantitative data on urban perception. Here, we build on the intuition that inequality is partly conspicuous to create quantitative measure of a citys contrasts. Using thousands of geo-tagged images, we measure the perception of safety, class and uniqueness; in the cities of Boston and New York in the United States, and Linz and Salzburg in Austria, finding that the range of perceptions elicited by the images of New York and Boston is larger than the range of perceptions elicited by images from Linz and Salzburg. We interpret this as evidence that the cityscapes of Boston and New York are more contrasting, or unequal, than those of Linz and Salzburg. Finally, we validate our measures by exploring the connection between them and homicides, finding a significant correlation between the perceptions of safety and class and the number of homicides in a NYC zip code, after controlling for the effects of income, population, area and age. Our results show that online images can be used to create reproducible quantitative measures of urban perception and characterize the inequality of different cities. OI /0000-0002-6031-5982
WOS:000322167900010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>Relations between allometric scalings and fluctuations in complex systems: The case of Japanese firms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2012.10.020</url>
<snippet>To elucidate allometric scaling in complex systems, we investigated the underlying scaling relationships between typical three-scale indicators for approximately 500,000 Japanese firms; namely, annual sales, number of employees, and number of business partners. First, new scaling relations including the distributions of fluctuations were discovered by systematically analyzing conditional statistics. Second, we introduced simple probabilistic models that reproduce all these scaling relations, and we derived relations between scaling exponents and the magnitude of fluctuations. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Takayasu, Misako/H-9890-2014; Takayasu, Hideki/B-9899-2015 OI Takayasu, Misako/0000-0002-2467-614X; Takayasu, Hideki/0000-0002-4452-5517
WOS:000314738700020
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Urban characteristics attributable to density-driven tie formation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/ncomms2961</url>
<snippet>Motivated by empirical evidence on the interplay between geography, population density and societal interaction, we propose a generative process for the evolution of social structure in cities. Our analytical and simulation results predict both super-linear scaling of social-tie density and information contagion as a function of the population. Here we demonstrate that our model provides a robust and accurate fit for the dependency of city characteristics with city-size, ranging from individual-level dyadic interactions (number of acquaintances, volume of communication) to population level variables (contagious disease rates, patenting activity, economic productivity and crime) without the need to appeal to heterogeneity, modularity, specialization or hierarchy. OI Ghoshal, Gourab/0000-0001-7593-5626
WOS:000323624100029
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
