<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Network Structure and City Size</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0029721</url>
<snippet>Network structure varies across cities. This variation may yield important knowledge about how the internal structure of the city affects its performance. This paper systematically compares a set of surface transportation network structure variables (connectivity, hierarchy, circuity, treeness, entropy, accessibility) across the 50 largest metropolitan areas in the United States. A set of scaling parameters are discovered to show how network size and structure vary with city size. These results suggest that larger cities are physically more inter-connected. Hypotheses are presented as to why this might obtain. This paper then consistently measures and ranks access to jobs across 50 US metropolitan areas. It uses that accessibility measure, along with network structure variables and city size to help explain journey-to-work time and auto mode share in those cities. A 1 percent increase in accessibility reduces average metropolitan commute times by about 90 seconds each way. A 1 percent increase in network connectivity reduces commute time by 0.1 percent. A 1 percent increase in accessibility results in a 0.0575 percent drop in auto mode share, while a 1 percent increase in treeness reduces auto mode share by 0.061 percent. Use of accessibility and network structure measures is important for planning and evaluating the performance of network investments and land use changes. RI Levinson, David/A-8554-2012 OI Levinson, David/0000-0002-4563-2963
WOS:000301357100019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>Entangled communities and spatial synchronization lead to criticality in urban traffic</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep01798</url>
<snippet>Understanding the relation between patterns of human mobility and the scaling of dynamical features of urban environments is a great importance for todays society. Although recent advancements have shed light on the characteristics of individual mobility, the role and importance of emerging human collective phenomena across time and space are still unclear. In this Article, we show by using two independent data-analysis techniques that the traffic in London is a combination of intertwined clusters, spanning the whole city and effectively behaving as a single correlated unit. This is due to algebraically decaying spatio-temporal correlations, that are akin to those shown by systems near a critical point. We describe these correlations in terms of Taylors law for fluctuations and interpret them as the emerging result of an underlying spatial synchronisation. Finally, our results provide the first evidence for a large-scale spatial human system reaching a self-organized critical state. RI Expert, Paul/E-7697-2012; Polak, John/L-1481-2017 OI Polak, John/0000-0002-3222-483X
WOS:000318651200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Solar potential scaling and the urban road network topology</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.95.012323</url>
<snippet>We explore the scaling of cities solar potentials with their number of buildings and reveal a latent dependence between the solar potential and the length of the corresponding citys road network. This scaling is shown to be valid at the grid and block levels and is attributed to a common street length distribution. Additionally, we compute the buildings solar potential correlation function and length in order to determine the set of critical exponents typifying the urban solar potential universality class. OI Najem, Sara/0000-0002-1171-870X
WOS:000402243300006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Limited Urban Growth: London's Street Network Dynamics since the 18th Century</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0069469</url>
<snippet>We investigate the growth dynamics of Greater London defined by the administrative boundary of the Greater London Authority, based on the evolution of its street network during the last two centuries. This is done by employing a unique dataset, consisting of the planar graph representation of nine time slices of Greater Londons road network spanning 224 years, from 1786 to 2010. Within this time-frame, we address the concept of the metropolitan area or city in physical terms, in that urban evolution reveals observable transitions in the distribution of relevant geometrical properties. Given that London has a hard boundary enforced by its long standing green belt, we show that its street network dynamics can be described as a fractal space-filling phenomena up to a capacitated limit, whence its growth can be predicted with a striking level of accuracy. This observation is confirmed by the analytical calculation of key topological properties of the planar graph, such as the topological growth of the network and its average connectivity. This study thus represents an example of a strong violation of Gibrats law. In particular, we are able to show analytically how London evolves from a more loop-like structure, typical of planned cities, toward a more tree-like structure, typical of self-organized cities. These observations are relevant to the discourse on sustainable urban planning with respect to the control of urban sprawl in many large cities which have developed under the conditions of spatial constraints imposed by green belts and hard urban boundaries. RI Batty, Michael/I-5638-2014 OI MASUCCI, ARMANDO/0000-0001-6633-4239
WOS:000323097300009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>Entropy and order in urban street networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep03324</url>
<snippet>Many complex networks erase parts of their geometry as they develop, so that their evolution is difficult to quantify and trace. Here we introduce entropy measures for quantifying the complexity of street orientations and length variations within planar networks and apply them to the street networks of 41 British cities, whose geometric evolution over centuries can be explored. The results show that the street networks of the old central parts of the cities have lower orientation/length entropies - the streets are more tightly ordered and form denser networks - than the outer and more recent parts. Entropy and street length increase, because of spreading, with distance from the network centre. Tracing the 400-year evolution of one network indicates growth through densification (streets are added within the existing network) and expansion (streets are added at the margin of the network) and a gradual increase in entropy over time.
WOS:000327528400007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>Living in Living Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1162/ARTL_a_00112</url>
<snippet>This article presents an overview of current and potential applications of living technology to some urban problems. Living technology can be described as technology that exhibits the core features of living systems. These features can be useful to solve dynamic problems. In particular, urban problems concerning mobility, logistics, telecommunications, governance, safety, sustainability, and society and culture are presented, and solutions involving living technology are reviewed. A methodology for developing living technology is mentioned, and supraoptimal public transportation systems are used as a case study to illustrate the benefits of urban living technology. Finally, the usefulness of describing cities as living systems is discussed. OI Gershenson, Carlos/0000-0003-0193-3067
WOS:000324116700008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>Allometric scaling of foraging rate with trail dimensions in leaf-cutting ants</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2011.2583</url>
<snippet>Leaf-cutting ants (Atta spp.) create physical pathways to support the transport of resources on which colony growth and reproduction depend. We determined the scaling relationship between the rate of resource acquisition and the size of the trail system and foraging workforce for 18 colonies of Atta colombica and Atta cephalotes. We examined conventional power-law scaling patterns, but did so in a multivariate analysis that reveals the simultaneous effects of forager number, trail length and trail width. Foraging rate (number of resource-laden ants returning to the nest per unit time) scaled at the 0.93 power of worker numbers, the -1.02 power of total trail length and the 0.65 power of trail width. These scaling exponents indicate that individual performance declines only slightly as more foragers are recruited to the workforce, but that trail length imposes a severe penalty on the foraging rate. A model of mass traffic flow predicts the allometric patterns for workforce and trail length, although the effect of trail width is unexpected and points to the importance of the little-known mechanisms that regulate a colonys investment in trail clearance. These results provide a point of comparison for the role that resource flows may play in allometric scaling patterns in other transport-dependent entities, such as human cities. OI Burd, Martin/0000-0002-1175-2596
WOS:000303888500021
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Used planet: A global history</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1217241110</url>
<snippet>Human use of land has transformed ecosystem pattern and process across most of the terrestrial biosphere, a global change often described as historically recent and potentially catastrophic for both humanity and the biosphere. Interdisciplinary paleoecological, archaeological, and historical studies challenge this view, indicating that land use has been extensive and sustained for millennia in some regions and that recent trends may represent as much a recovery as an acceleration. Here we synthesize recent scientific evidence and theory on the emergence, history, and future of land use as a process transforming the Earth System and use this to explain why relatively small human populations likely caused widespread and profound ecological changes more than 3,000 y ago, whereas the largest and wealthiest human populations in history are using less arable land per person every decade. Contrasting two spatially explicit global reconstructions of land-use history shows that reconstructions incorporating adaptive changes in land-use systems over time, including land-use intensification, offer a more spatially detailed and plausible assessment of our planets history, with a biosphere and perhaps even climate long ago affected by humans. Although land-use processes are now shifting rapidly from historical patterns in both type and scale, integrative global land-use models that incorporate dynamic adaptations in human-environment relationships help to advance our understanding of both past and future land-use changes, including their sustainability and potential global effects. RI Klein Goldewijk, Kees/L-5567-2013; Kaplan, Jed/P-1796-2015; Verburg, Peter/A-8469-2010 OI Klein Goldewijk, Kees/0000-0003-2714-7507; Kaplan, Jed/0000-0001-9919-7613; Verburg, Peter/0000-0002-6977-7104; Ellis, Erle/0000-0002-2006-3362
WOS:000319803500013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>Fractal cartography of urban areas</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep00527</url>
<snippet>In a world in which the pace of cities is increasing, prompt access to relevant information is crucial to the understanding and regulation of land use and its evolution in time. In spite of this, characterization and regulation of urban areas remains a complex process, requiring expert human intervention, analysis and judgment. Here we carry out a spatio-temporal fractal analysis of a metropolitan area, based on which we develop a model which generates a cartographic representation and classification of built-up areas, identifying (and even predicting) those areas requiring the most proximate planning and regulation. Furthermore, we show how different types of urban areas identified by the model co-evolve with the city, requiring policy regulation to be flexible and adaptive, acting just in time. The algorithmic implementation of the model is applicable to any built-up area and simple enough to pave the way for the automatic classification of urban areas worldwide. RI Santos, Francisco/D-2394-2010; Pacheco, Jorge/B-6116-2008 OI Santos, Francisco/0000-0002-9103-2862; Pacheco, Jorge/0000-0002-2579-8499; Encarnacao, Sara/0000-0001-8262-2927; Tenedorio, Jose Antonio/0000-0003-3047-0807
WOS:000306710300002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="10">
<title>Form and urban change - An urban morphometric study of five gentrified neighbourhoods in London</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0265813516658031</url>
<snippet>Research in Urban Morphology has long been exploring the form of cities and their changes over time, especially by establishing links with the parallel dynamics of these cities social, economic and political environments. The capacity of an adaptable and resilient urban form to provide a fertile environment for economic prosperity and social cohesion is at the forefront of discussion. Gentrification has emerged in the past few decades as an important topic of research in urban sociology, geography and economy, addressing the social impact of some forms of urban evolution. To some extent, these studies emphasize the form of the environment in which gentrification takes place. However, a systematic and quantitative method for a detailed characterization of this type of urban form is still far from being achieved. With this article, we make a first step towards the establishment of an approach based on urban morphometrics. To this end, we measure and compare key morphological features of five London neighbourhoods that have undergone a process of piecemeal gentrification. Findings suggest that these five case studies display similar and recognizable morphological patterns in terms of their built form, geographical location of main and local roads and physical relationships between street fronts and street types. These initial results, while not implying any causal or universal relationship between morphological and social dynamics, nevertheless contribute to (a) highlight the benefits of a rigorous quantitative approach towards interpreting urban form beyond the disciplinary boundaries of Urban Morphology and (b) define the statistical recurrence of a few, specific morphological features amongst the five cases of gentrified areas in London. RI Zanella, Mattia/U-7517-2017 OI Zanella, Mattia/0000-0001-8456-5866; Porta, Sergio/0000-0003-1458-9517
WOS:000414907900004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="11">
<title>Time Evolution of Road Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-10629-8_38</url>
<snippet>Urbanization is a fundamental phenomenon which however still remains poorly quantitatively characterized. An important facet of this phenomenon is the road network which co-evolves with other urban structures and we review here the most recent results about the structure and the evolution of these important infrastructures. These studies suggest that the natural evolution of a road network is governed by two elementary processes: (i) densification, which corresponds to an increase in the local density of roads around existing central points and (ii) exploration which consists in new roads triggering the spatial evolution of the urbanization front. However, interventions of central, top-down planning could modify this simple picture of a natural evolution and we will present the example of the street network of Paris (France), which during the nineteenth century experienced large modifications supervised by a central authority, the Haussmann period. In this case, the usual network measures display a smooth behavior and the most important quantitative signatures of central planning are the spatial reorganization of centrality and the modification of the block shape distribution. Such effects can only be obtained by structural modifications at a large-scale level, with the creation of new roads not constrained by the existing geometry. These different results suggest that the evolution of a road network results from the superimposition of continuous, local growth processes and punctual changes operating at large spatial scales, opening new directions for the modelling of these systems.
WOS:000380446300038
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="12">
<title>World citation and collaboration networks: uncovering the role of geography in science</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep00902</url>
<snippet>Modern information and communication technologies, especially the Internet, have diminished the role of spatial distances and territorial boundaries on the access and transmissibility of information. This has enabled scientists for closer collaboration and internationalization. Nevertheless, geography remains an important factor affecting the dynamics of science. Here we present a systematic analysis of citation and collaboration networks between cities and countries, by assigning papers to the geographic locations of their authors affiliations. The citation flows as well as the collaboration strengths between cities decrease with the distance between them and follow gravity laws. In addition, the total research impact of a country grows linearly with the amount of national funding for research &amp; development. However, the average impact reveals a peculiar threshold effect: the scientific output of a country may reach an impact larger than the world average only if the country invests more than about 100,000 USD per researcher annually. RI Fortunato, Santo/C-3586-2009; Kaski, Kimmo/G-8067-2012; Saramaki, Jari/E-5226-2011; Pan, Raj Kumar/B-4352-2010 OI Fortunato, Santo/0000-0002-9039-4730; Pan, Raj Kumar/0000-0001-9803-6332
WOS:000311898400004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="13">
<title>Self-organization versus top-down planning in the evolution of a city</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep02153</url>
<snippet>Interventions of central, top-down planning are serious limitations to the possibility of modelling the dynamics of cities. An example is the city of Paris (France), which during the 19th century experienced large modifications supervised by a central authority, the Haussmann period. In this article, we report an empirical analysis of more than 200 years (1789-2010) of the evolution of the street network of Paris. We show that the usual network measures display a smooth behavior and that the most important quantitative signatures of central planning is the spatial reorganization of centrality and the modification of the block shape distribution. Such effects can only be obtained by structural modifications at a large-scale level, with the creation of new roads not constrained by the existing geometry. The evolution of a city thus seems to result from the superimposition of continuous, local growth processes and punctual changes operating at large spatial scales.
WOS:000321425700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="14">
<title>A model of urban scaling laws based on distance-dependent interactions</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.160926</url>
<snippet>Socio-economic related properties of a city grow faster than a linear relationship with the population, in a log-log plot, the so-called superlinear scaling. Conversely, the larger a city, the more efficient it is in the use of its infrastructure, leading to a sublinear scaling on these variables. In this work, we addressed a simple explanation for those scaling laws in cities based on the interaction range between the citizens and on the fractal properties of the cities. To this purpose, we introduced a measure of social potential which captured the influence of social interaction on the economic performance and the benefits of amenities in the case of infrastructure offered by the city. We assumed that the population density depends on the fractal dimension and on the distance-dependent interactions between individuals. The model suggests that when the city interacts as a whole, and not just as a set of isolated parts, there is improvement of the socio-economic indicators. Moreover, the bigger the interaction range between citizens and amenities, the bigger the improvement of the socio-economic indicators and the lower the infrastructure costs of the city. We addressed how public policies could take advantage of these properties to improve cities development, minimizing negative effects. Furthermore, the model predicts that the sum of the scaling exponents of social-economic and infrastructure variables are 2, as observed in the literature. Simulations with an agent-based model are confronted with the theoretical approach and they are compatible with the empirical evidences. RI Ribeiro, Fabiano/G-9519-2014; Rodrigues Neto, Camilo/C-9126-2011 OI Rodrigues Neto, Camilo/0000-0001-6783-6695; Meirelles de Miranda, Joao Vitor/0000-0001-5951-1284
WOS:000398107700032
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="15">
<title>The angular nature of road networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-017-04477-z</url>
<snippet>Road networks are characterised by several structural and geometrical properties. The topological structure determines partially the hierarchical arrangement of roads, but since these are networks that are spatially constrained, geometrical properties play a fundamental role in determining the networks behaviour, characterising the influence of each of the street segments on the system. In this work, we apply percolation theory to the UKs road network using the relative angle between street segments as the occupation probability. The appearance of the spanning cluster is marked by a phase transition, indicating that the system behaves in a critical way. Computing Shannons entropy of the cluster sizes, different stages of the percolation process can be discerned, and these indicate that roads integrate to the giant cluster in a hierarchical manner. This is used to construct a hierarchical index that serves to classify roads in terms of their importance. The obtained classification is in very good correspondence with the official designations of roads. This methodology hence provides a framework to consistently extract the main skeleton of an urban system and to further classify each road in terms of its hierarchical importance within the system.
WOS:000404126500052
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="16">
<title>Sustainable Development under Population Pressure: Lessons from Developed Land Consumption in the Conterminous US</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0119675</url>
<snippet>Population growth will result in a significant anthropogenic environmental change worldwide through increases in developed land (DL) consumption. DL consumption is an important environmental and socioeconomic process affecting humans and ecosystems. Attention has been given to DL modeling inside highly populated cities. However, modeling DL consumption should expand to non-metropolitan areas where arguably the environmental consequences are more significant. Here, we study all counties within the conterminous U.S. and based on satellite-derived product (National Land Cover Dataset 2001) we calculate the associated DL for each county. By using county population data from the 2000 census we present a comparative study on DL consumption and we propose a model linking population with expected DL consumption. Results indicate distinct geographic patterns of comparatively low and high consuming counties moving from east to west. We also demonstrate that the relationship of DL consumption with population is mostly linear, altering the notion that expected population growth will have lower DL consumption if added in counties with larger population. Added DL consumption is independent of a countys starting population and only dependent on whether the county belongs to a Metropolitan Statistical Area (MSA). In the overlapping MSA and non-MSA population range there is also a constant DL efficiency gain of approximately 20km(2) for a given population for MSA counties which suggests that transitioning from rural to urban counties has significantly higher benefits in lower populations. In addition, we analyze the socioeconomic composition of counties with extremely high or low DL consumption. High DL consumption counties have statistically lower Black/African American population, higher poverty rate and lower income per capita than average in both NMSA and MSA counties. Our analysis offers a baseline to investigate further land consumption strategies in anticipation of growing population pressures. OI Grekousis, George/0000-0003-2837-2335
WOS:000351880000035
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="17">
<title>Network Centrality of Metro Systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0040575</url>
<snippet>Whilst being hailed as the remedy to the worlds ills, cities will need to adapt in the 21st century. In particular, the role of public transport is likely to increase significantly, and new methods and technics to better plan transit systems are in dire need. This paper examines one fundamental aspect of transit: network centrality. By applying the notion of betweenness centrality to 28 worldwide metro systems, the main goal of this paper is to study the emergence of global trends in the evolution of centrality with network size and examine several individual systems in more detail. Betweenness was notably found to consistently become more evenly distributed with size (i.e. no "winner takes all") unlike other complex network properties. Two distinct regimes were also observed that are representative of their structure. Moreover, the share of betweenness was found to decrease in a power law with size (with exponent 1 for the average node), but the share of most central nodes decreases much slower than least central nodes (0.87 vs. 2.48). Finally the betweenness of individual stations in several systems were examined, which can be useful to locate stations where passengers can be redistributed to relieve pressure from overcrowded stations. Overall, this study offers significant insights that can help planners in their task to design the systems of tomorrow, and similar undertakings can easily be imagined to other urban infrastructure systems (e.g., electricity grid, water/wastewater system, etc.) to develop more sustainable cities.
WOS:000306461800108
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="18">
<title>From paths to blocks: New measures for street patterns</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0265813515599982</url>
<snippet>The street network is an important aspect of cities and contains crucial information about their organization and evolution. Characterizing and comparing various street networks could then be helpful for a better understanding of the mechanisms governing the formation and evolution of these systems. Their characterization is however not easy: there are no simple tools to classify planar networks and most of the measures developed for complex networks are not useful when space is relevant. Here, we describe recent efforts in this direction and new methods adapted to spatial networks. We will first discuss measures based on the structure of shortest paths, among which the betweenness centrality. In particular for time-evolving road networks, we will show that the spatial distribution of the betweenness centrality is able to reveal the impact of important structural transformations. Shortest paths are however not the only relevant ones. In particular, they can be very different from those with the smallest number of turns-the simplest paths. The statistical comparison of the lengths of the shortest and simplest paths provides a nontrivial and nonlocal information about the spatial organization of planar graphs. We define the simplicity index as the average ratio of these lengths and the simplicity profile characterizes the simplicity at different scales. Measuring these quantities on artificial (roads, highways, railways) and natural networks (leaves, insect wings) show that there are fundamental differences-probably related to their different function-in the organization of urban and biological systems: there is a clear hierarchy of the lengths of straight lines in biological cases, but they are randomly distributed in urban systems. The paths are however not enough to fully characterize the spatial pattern of planar networks such as streets and roads. Another promising direction is to analyze the statistics of blocks of the planar network. More precisely, we can use the conditional probability distribution of the shape factor of blocks with a given area, and define what could constitute the fingerprint of a city. These fingerprints can then serve as a basis for a classification of cities based on their street patterns. This method applied on more than 130 cities in the world leads to four broad families of cities characterized by different abundances of blocks of a certain area and shape. This classification will be helpful for identifying dominant mechanisms governing the formation and evolution of street patterns.
WOS:000397517300004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="19">
<title>The scaling structure of the global road network</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.170590</url>
<snippet>Because of increasing global urbanization and its immediate consequences, including changes in patterns of food demand, circulation and land use, the next century will witness a major increase in the extent of paved roads built worldwide. To model the effects of this increase, it is crucial to understand whether possible self-organized patterns are inherent in the global road network structure. Here, we use the largest updated database comprising all major roads on the Earth, together with global urban and cropland inventories, to suggest that road length distributions within croplands are indistinguishable from urban ones, once rescaled to account for the difference in mean road length. Such similarity extends to road length distributions within urban or agricultural domains of a given area. We find two distinct regimes for the scaling of the mean road length with the associated area, holding in general at small and at large values of the latter. In suitably large urban and cropland domains, we find that mean and total road lengths increase linearly with their domain area, differently from earlier suggestions. Scaling regimes suggest that simple and universal mechanisms regulate urban and cropland road expansion at the global scale. As such, our findings bear implications for global road infrastructure growth based on land-use change and for planning policies sustaining urban expansions. OI Giometto, Andrea/0000-0002-0544-6023
WOS:000413965600016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="20">
<title>Spatial effects in real networks: Measures, null models, and applications</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.86.066110</url>
<snippet>Spatially embedded networks are shaped by a combination of purely topological (space-independent) and space-dependent formation rules. While it is quite easy to artificially generate networks where the relative importance of these two factors can be varied arbitrarily, it is much more difficult to disentangle these two architectural effects in real networks. Here we propose a solution to this problem, by introducing global and local measures of spatial effects that, through a comparison with adequate null models, effectively filter out the spurious contribution of nonspatial constraints. Our filtering allows us to consistently compare different embedded networks or different historical snapshots of the same network. As a challenging application we analyze the World Trade Web, whose topology is known to depend on geographic distances but is also strongly determined by nonspatial constraints (degree sequence or gross domestic product). Remarkably, we are able to detect weak but significant spatial effects both locally and globally in the network, showing that our method succeeds in retrieving spatial information even when nonspatial factors dominate. We finally relate our results to the economic literature on gravity models and trade globalization. DOI: 10.1103/PhysRevE.86.066110 RI Garlaschelli, Diego/O-4862-2014; Basosi, Riccardo/E-7497-2011 OI Garlaschelli, Diego/0000-0001-6035-1783; Basosi, Riccardo/0000-0003-1026-7668; Picciolo, Francesco/0000-0002-5595-1140
WOS:000312296300002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="21">
<title>Do Physicists Have Geography Envy? And What Can Geographers Learn from It?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00045608.2015.1039105</url>
<snippet>Recent years have seen an increasing amount of work by physicists on topics outside their traditional research domain, including geography. We explore the scope of this development, place it in a historical context dating back at least to statistical physics in the nineteenth century and trace the origins of more recent developments to the roots of computational science after World War II. Our primary purpose is not historical, however. Instead, we are concerned with understanding what geographers can learn from the many recent contributions by physicists to understanding spatiotemporal systems. Drawing on examples of work in this tradition by physicists, we argue that two apparently different modes of investigation are common: model-driven and data-driven approaches. The former is associated with complexity science, whereas the latter is more commonly associated with the fourth paradigm, more recently known as "big data." Both modes share technical strengths and, more important, a capacity for generalization, which is absent from much work in geography. We argue that although some of this research lacks an appreciation of previous geographical contributions, when assessed critically, it nevertheless brings useful new perspectives, new methods, and new ideas to bear on topics central to geography, yet neglected in the discipline. We conclude with some suggestions for how geographers can build on these new approaches, both inside and outside the discipline. OI Manson, Steven/0000-0001-7697-5339
WOS:000359478600005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="22">
<title>Elementary processes governing the evolution of road networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep00296</url>
<snippet>Urbanisation is a fundamental phenomenon whose quantitative characterisation is still inadequate. We report here the empirical analysis of a unique data set regarding almost 200 years of evolution of the road network in a large area located north of Milan (Italy). We find that urbanisation is characterised by the homogenisation of cell shapes, and by the stability throughout time of high-centrality roads which constitute the backbone of the urban structure, confirming the importance of historical paths. We show quantitatively that the growth of the network is governed by two elementary processes: (i) densification, corresponding to an increase in the local density of roads around existing urban centres and (ii) exploration, whereby new roads trigger the spatial evolution of the urbanisation front. The empirical identification of such simple elementary mechanisms suggests the existence of general, simple properties of urbanisation and opens new directions for its modelling and quantitative description. RI Nicosia, Vincenzo/C-7890-2013; strano, emanuele/J-3002-2015 OI Nicosia, Vincenzo/0000-0003-0636-3278; Latora, Vito/0000-0002-0984-8038; Porta, Sergio/0000-0003-1458-9517
WOS:000300954300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="23">
<title>A universal model for mobility and migration patterns</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature10856</url>
<snippet>Introduced in its contemporary form in 1946 (ref. 1), but with roots that go back to the eighteenth century(2), the gravity law(1,3,4) is the prevailing framework with which to predict population movement(3,5,6), cargo shipping volume(7) and inter-city phone calls(8,9), as well as bilateral trade flows between nations(10). Despite its widespread use, it relies on adjustable parameters that vary from region to region and suffers from known analytic inconsistencies. Here we introduce a stochastic process capturing local mobility decisions that helps us analytically derive commuting and mobility fluxes that require as input only information on the population distribution. The resulting radiation model predicts mobility patterns in good agreement with mobility and transport patterns observed in a wide range of phenomena, from long-term migration patterns to communication volume between different regions. Given its parameter-free nature, the model can be applied in areas where we lack previous mobility measurements, significantly improving the predictive accuracy of most of the phenomena affected by mobility and transport processes(11-23). RI Gonzalez, Marta/E-9456-2011 OI Gonzalez, Marta/0000-0002-8482-0318
WOS:000302343400041
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="24">
<title>A long-time limit for world subway networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2012.0259</url>
<snippet>We study the temporal evolution of the structure of the worlds largest subway networks in an exploratory manner. We show that, remarkably, all these networks converge to a shape that shares similar generic features despite their geographical and economic differences. This limiting shape is made of a core with branches radiating from it. For most of these networks, the average degree of a node (station) within the core has a value of order 2.5 and the proportion of k = 2 nodes in the core is larger than 60 per cent. The number of branches scales roughly as the square root of the number of stations, the current proportion of branches represents about half of the total number of stations, and the average diameter of branches is about twice the average radial extension of the core. Spatial measures such as the number of stations at a given distance to the barycentre display a first regime which grows as r(2) followed by another regime with different exponents, and eventually saturates. These results-difficult to interpret in the framework of fractal geometry-confirm and yield a natural explanation in the geometric picture of this core and their branches: the first regime corresponds to a uniform core, while the second regime is controlled by the interstation spacing on branches. The apparent convergence towards a unique network shape in the temporal limit suggests the existence of dominant, universal mechanisms governing the evolution of these structures. RI Batty, Michael/I-5638-2014
WOS:000308240400015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="25">
<title>Universal scaling of the distribution of land in urban areas</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.96.032302</url>
<snippet>In this work, we explore the spatial structure of built zones and green areas in diverse western cities by analyzing the probability distribution of areas and a coefficient that characterize their respective shapes. From the analysis of diverse datasets describing land lots in urban areas, we found that the distribution of built-up areas and natural zones in cities obey inverse power laws with a similar scaling for the cities explored. On the other hand, by studying the distribution of shapes of lots in urban regions, we are able to detect global differences in the spatial structure of the distribution of land. Our findings introduce information about spatial patterns that emerge in the structure of urban settlements; this knowledge is useful for the understanding of urban growth, to improve existing models of cities, in the context of sustainability, in studies about human mobility in urban areas, among other applications. OI Perez Riascos, Alejandro/0000-0002-9243-3246
WOS:000408829500004
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
