<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Large cities get more for less: Water footprint efficiency across the US</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0202301</url>
<snippet>Many urban indicators and functional citywide properties have been shown to scale with population due to agglomeration effects. We hypothesize that scaling relations may also exist for water-related urban indicators such as the water footprint. The water footprint is an indicator of water use that measures humans appropriation of freshwater resources. We analyze the scaling of the water footprint for 65 mid- to large-sized US cities using both empirical estimates and a social interaction network model of city functioning. The network model is used to explain the presence of any scaling exponent in the empirical estimates of the urban water footprint by linking to previous theories of urban scaling. We find that the urban water footprint tends to approximately show sublinear scaling behavior with both population and gross domestic product. Thus, large cities tend to be more water footprint efficient and productive than mid-sized cities, where efficiency and productivity are quantified, in a broad sense, as deviations from a linear scaling exponent. We find the sublinear scaling may be linked to changes in urban economic structure with city size, which lead to large cities shifting water intensive economic activities to less populated regions. In addition, we find that green water contributes to the scaling both positively by transferring the dependence of food consumption on population into the water footprint and negatively by increasing heterogeneity. Overall, the proposed scaling relations allow for the comparison of water footprint efficiency and productivity of cities. Comparing these properties and identifying deviations from the expected behavior has implications for water resources and urban sustainability. OI Grady, Caitlin/0000-0002-9151-6664
WOS:000442202100024
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>Impact of the Economic Structure of Cities on Urban Scaling Factors Implications for Urban Material and Energy Flows in China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jiec.12563</url>
<snippet>We explore the population-scaling and gross domestic product (GDP)-scaling relationships of material and energy flow (MEF) parameters in different city types based on economic structure. Using migration-corrected population data, we classify 233 Chinese city propers (Shiqu) as highly industrial (share of secondary GDP exceeds 63.9&#37;), highly commercial (share of tertiary GDP exceeds 52.6&#37;), and mixed-economy (the remaining cities). We find that, first, the GDP population-scaling factors differ in the different city types. Highly commercial and mixed-economy cities exhibit superlinear GDP population-scaling factors greater than 1, whereas highly industrial cities are sublinear. Second, GDP scaling better correlates with city-wide MEF parameters in Chinese cities; these scaling relationships also show differences by city typology. Third, highly commercial cities are significantly different from others in demonstrating greater average per capita household income creation relative to per capita GDP. Further, highly industrial cities show an apparent cap in population. This also translates to lower densities in highly industrial cities compared to other types, showing a size effect on urban population density. Finally, a multiple variable regression of total household electricity showed significant and positive correlation with population, income effect, and urban form effect. With such multivariate modeling, the apparent superlinearity of household electricity use with respect to population is no longer observed. Our study enhances understanding of MEFs associated with Chinese cities and provides new insights into the patterns of scaling observed in different city types by economic structure. Results recommend dual scaling by GDP and by population for MEF parameters and suggest caution in applying universal scaling factors to all cities in a country.
WOS:000429716700012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>A review of urban ecosystem services: six key challenges for future research</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoser.2015.05.001</url>
<snippet>Global urbanization creates opportunities and challenges for human well-being and transition towards sustainability. Urban areas are human-environment systems that depend fundamentally on ecosystems, and thus require an understanding of the management of urban ecosystem services to ensure sustainable urban planning. The purpose of this study is to provide a systematic review of urban ecosystems services research, which addresses the combined domain of ecosystem services and urban development. We examined emerging trends and gaps in how urban ecosystem services are conceptualized in peer-reviewed case study literature, including the geographical distribution of research, the development and use of the urban ecosystem services concept, and the involvement of stakeholders. We highlight six challenges aimed at strengthening the concepts potential to facilitate meaningful inter- and transdisciplinary work for ecosystem services research and planning. Achieving a cohesive conceptual approach in the research field will address (i) the need for more extensive spatial and contextual coverage, (ii) continual clarification of definitions, (iii) recognition of limited data transferability, (iv) more comprehensive stakeholder involvement, (v) more integrated research efforts, and (vi) translation of scientific findings into actionable knowledge, feeding information back into planning and management. We conclude with recommendations for conducting further research while incorporating these challenges. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. OI Abson, David/0000-0003-3755-785X; Brink, Ebba/0000-0001-5865-2536; Rau, Anna-Lena/0000-0002-1068-9273; Luederitz, Christopher/0000-0002-7873-4229
WOS:000363666900011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Transition towards sustainable cities: opportunities, constraints, and strategies in planning. A neighbourhood ecodesign case study in Barcelona</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1068/a43551</url>
<snippet>Despite covering only 2.7&#37; of the worlds total surface area, the worlds cities are responsible for 75&#37; of the worlds energy consumption and 80&#37; of greenhouse-gas emissions. For this reason, the redesign of cities is essential in the transition towards sustainability. However, planning and designing sustainable neighbourhoods is not a simple task, given that there is no agreement on what the sustainable settlement should be, nor on how this should be achieved. Furthermore, planners have to strive to achieve a balance between financial, environmental, and social goals, and must deal with multiple actors and stakeholders and with site-specific characteristics. The aim of this work is to describe the key determining factors-both opportunities and constraints-found in the process of designing and planning a neighbourhood, based on a case study in the city of Barcelona. In this practical experiment, led by the authors, the ecodesign methodology was applied on an urban scale in the neighbourhood of Vallbona, Barcelona, which occupies an area of 32.6 ha and will host 2120 dwellings. From this neighbourhood ecodesign exercise, it was found that territorial (urban form, urban fabrics, and density; availability of local resources), financial, legal, and political (local governments wishes and leadership) determinants are the most important. It is concluded that there is no single path to achieve urban sustainability, since the design of neighbourhoods in different locations will lead to different results. RI Gabarrell Durany, Xavier/F-5575-2011; Rossing-Enger, Lasse/B-4674-2012 OI Gabarrell Durany, Xavier/0000-0003-1730-4337;
WOS:000292993500009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>A brief history and the possible future of urban energy systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.enpol.2012.03.072</url>
<snippet>Modern cities depend on energy systems to deliver a range of services such as heating, cooling, lighting, mobility, communications, and so on. This article examines how these urban energy systems came to be, tracing the major transitions from the earliest settlements through to todays fossil-fuelled cities. The underlying theme is "increasing efficiency under constraints" with each transition marked by increasing energy efficiency in service provision, increasing per capita energy use, increasing complexity in the energy systems structure, with innovations driven by a strategic view of the overall system, and accompanied by wider changes in technology and society. In developed countries, the future of urban energy systems is likely to continue many of these trends, with increased efficiency being driven by the constraints of climate change and rising fuel prices. Both supply and demand side technologies are discussed as potential solutions to these issues, with different impacts on the urban environment and its citizens. However in developing countries, rising urban populations and access to basic energy services will drive the next transition. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000310405800008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>Relative size measures of urban form based on allometric subtraction</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0265813515611420</url>
<snippet>One of the most common relativization techniques in life sciences quantifies body condition based on residuals from the linear regression in the log-log plot of body mass against a linear measure of size. Given the network-based analogy between organisms and cities, the method is applied to comparative urban studies to formulate relativized allometric measures based on the allometry to size of metric and topological measures of street networks. The analysis of a sample of 70 cities from a confined region considered in three historical stages demonstrates that the more allometric scaling of a measure to size diverges from the linear, the more allometric measures show discrepancy to the existing relativization methods that are based on mean measures and ratios between measures. Allometric measures reflect the dynamics of specific regional samples of cities and therefore also differ from relativization methods that relate measures that grow exponentially with size against static theoretical yardsticks. The comparison involving two additional samples of cities from other regions suggests that the proposed allometric measures can be used to approximate size-invariant measures for cities with unknown allometry more reliably than existing relativization measures. The method can be applied to formulate relativized indices for any measure that displays allometry to size in various scales of the built environment.
WOS:000397516900008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>Water on an urban planet: Urbanization and the reach of urban water infrastructure</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.gloenvcha.2014.04.022</url>
<snippet>Urban growth is increasing the demand for freshwater resources, yet surprisingly the water sources of the worlds large cities have never been globally assessed, hampering efforts to assess the distribution and causes of urban water stress. We conducted the first global survey of the large cities water sources, and show that previous global hydrologic models that ignored urban water infrastructure significantly overestimated urban water stress. Large cities obtain 78 +/- 3&#37; of their water from surface sources, some of which are far away: cumulatively, large cities moved 504 billion liters a day (184 km(3) yr(-1)) a distance of 27,000 +/- 3800 km, and the upstream contributing area of urban water sources is 41&#37; of the global land surface. Despite this infrastructure, one in four cities, containing $4.8 +/- 0.7 trillion in economic activity, remain water stressed due to geographical and financial limitations. The strategic management of these cities water sources is therefore important for the future of the global economy. (C) 2014 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd. RI Gleeson, Tom/F-2552-2011 OI Gleeson, Tom/0000-0001-9493-7707; Eckman, Stephanie/0000-0002-8577-4085; Grill, Gunther/0000-0003-4860-3575
WOS:000340990400010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>GHG Emissions and the Rural-Urban Divide. A Carbon Footprint Analysis Based on the German Official Income and Expenditure Survey</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolecon.2017.09.004</url>
<snippet>Will climate change be mitigated automatically by ongoing processes of urbanization as proposed by the "dense cities" hypothesis? Our answer is based on the German official income and expenditure survey (EVS) of 2013, which allow us to disaggregate total household expenditures into 44 consumer good categories (COICOP) and their respective GHG intensities. Results show that the density effect of cities saves some greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions in Germany, but singularisation of households, higher Incomes and greater consumption opportunities in cities work in the opposite direction. Thus, smaller and larger municipalities are more or less on par with each other in terms of per capita emissions. Rural households are found to be more affected by environmental taxes which are imposed on direct rather than on indirect energy use in the course of German "Energiewende" policy reform. This is discussed in the article as a rural-urban social equity problem. OI Gill, Bernhard/0000-0001-8640-8557
WOS:000424316700015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>Resilience of and through urban ecosystem services</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoser.2014.07.012</url>
<snippet>Cities and urban areas are critical components of global sustainability as loci of sustainability progress and drivers of global transformation, especially in terms of energy efficiency, climate change adaptation, and social innovation. However, urban ecosystems have not been incorporated adequately into urban governance and planning for resilience despite mounting evidence that urban resident health and wellbeing is closely tied to the quality, quantity, and diversity of urban ecosystem services. We suggest that urban ecosystem services provide key links for bridging planning, management and governance practices seeking transitions to more sustainable cities, and serve an important role in building resilience in urban systems. Emerging city goals for resilience should explicitly incorporate the value of urban ES in city planning and governance. We argue that cities need to prioritize safeguarding of a resilient supply of ecosystem services to ensure livable, sustainable cities, especially given the dynamic nature of urban systems continually responding to global environmental change. Building urban resilience of and through ecosystem services, both in research and in practice, will require dealing with the dynamic nature of urban social-ecological systems and incorporating multiple ways of knowing into governance approaches to resilience including from scientists, practitioners, designers and planners. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. OI McPhearson, Timon/0000-0002-9499-0791; Elmqvist, Thomas/0000-0002-4617-6197; Frantzeskaki, Niki/0000-0002-6983-448X; Andersson, Erik/0000-0003-2716-5502
WOS:000363665300016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="10">
<title>Superlinear and sublinear urban scaling in geographical networks modeling cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.90.022803</url>
<snippet>Using a geographical scale-free network to describe relations between people in a city, we explain both superlinear and sublinear allometric scaling of urban indicators that quantify activities or performances of the city. The urban indicator Y(N) of a city with the population size N is analytically calculated by summing up all individual activities produced by person-to-person relationships. Our results show that the urban indicator scales superlinearly with the population, namely, Y(N) alpha N-beta with beta &gt; 1, if Y(N) represents a creative productivity and the indicator scales sublinearly (beta &lt; 1) if Y(N) is related to the degree of infrastructure development. These results coincide with allometric scaling observed in real-world urban indicators. We also show how the scaling exponent beta depends on the strength of the geographical constraint in the network formation.
WOS:000340003700009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="11">
<title>The urban south and the predicament of global sustainability</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41893-018-0101-5</url>
<snippet>Urbanization is a global phenomenon with strong sustainability implications across multiple scales. We argue that much of the associated challenges, and opportunities, are found in the global south. We show that urban issues in the global south are distinctly and statistically different from those in the global north, but our current urban knowledge is predominantly shaped by research on and from the global north. Cities in the global south have strong imperatives, and unique but often overlooked capacity, to innovate and experiment for sustainability. We call for a renewed research focus on urbanization in the south, and suggest targeted efforts to correct structural biases in the knowledge production system. RI Bai, Xuemei/A-5443-2012 OI Bai, Xuemei/0000-0001-6556-8041; Brondizio, Eduardo/0000-0001-9376-8366; Lwasa, Shuaib/0000-0003-4312-2836
WOS:000439238500011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="12">
<title>Synergies and trade-offs between energy-efficient urbanization and health</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/aa9281</url>
<snippet>Energy-efficient urbanization and public health pose major development challenges for India. While both issues are intensively studied, their interaction is not well understood. Here we explore the relationship between urban infrastructures, public health, and household-related emissions, identifying potential synergies and trade-offs of specific interventions by analyzing nationally representative household surveys from 2005 and 2012. Our analysis confirms previous characterizations of the environmental-health transition, but also points to an important role of energy use and urbanization as modifiers of this transition. We find that non-motorized transport may prove a sweet spot for development, as its use is associated with lower emissions and better public health in cities. Urbanization and improved access to basic services correlate with lower short-term morbidity (STM), such as fever, cough and diarrhea. Our analysis suggests that a 10&#37; increase in urbanization from current levels and concurrent improvement in access to modern cooking and clean water could lower STM for 2.4 million people. This would be associated with a modest increase in electricity related emissions of 84 ktCO(2)e annually. Promoting energy-efficient mobility systems, for instance by a 10&#37; increase in bicycling, could lower chronic conditions like diabetes and cardio-vascular diseases for 0.3 million people while also abating emissions. These findings provide empirical evidence to validate that energy-efficient and sustainable urbanization can address both public health and climate change challenges simultaneously. OI Pachauri, Shonali/0000-0001-8138-3178; Ahmad, Sohail/0000-0002-2816-8484
WOS:000414647300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="13">
<title>Cities in the age of the Anthropocene: Climate change agents and the potential for mitigation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ancene.2017.08.001</url>
<snippet>Cities are human creations where many of the emissions causing climate change originate. Every aspect of daily life in cities, which spans buildings, transit, food, energy, and water, relies on fossil fuels that materially contribute to climate change. This paper explores the need for research to better uncover the processes driving urbanization in order to develop novel ways to mitigate climate impacts on Earth. Areas of fruitful research include better quantification of teleconnections between cities and their hinterlands and coupling those to the socio-economic drivers and organization of those relationships; the financialization of much urban policy; understanding where cities fit in the global economic order and their role in generating economic growth, and the ways in which they are also seen as leaders of sustainability and climate actions, but constrained in so-doing by the nested and tiered layers of institutions they operate within. This paper concludes by outlining ways for cities to transition toward nurturing human well-being and reducing their impacts on planetary processes resulting in the proposed new Earth epoch - the Anthropocene. 
WOS:000423549300008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="14">
<title>Urban ecology and sustainability: The state-of-the-science and future directions</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.landurbplan.2014.01.018</url>
<snippet>Ecosystems and landscapes around the world have become increasingly domesticated through urbanization. Cities have been the engines of socioeconomic development but also the centers of major environmental problems since the industrial revolution. Numerous studies have shown that our urban ecosystems and landscapes are on an unsustainable trajectory. Global sustainability depends critically on cities, and urban ecology can and needs to play a key role in the transition toward sustainability. In this paper, I review different definitions and perspectives of urban ecology, discuss major advances and key issues, and propose a framework to help move the field forward. After almost 90 years of development, urban ecology has evolved into a truly transdisciplinary enterprise that integrates ecological, geographical, planning, and social sciences. The most salient thrust of current research activities in the field is the emerging urban sustainability paradigm which focuses on urban ecosystem services and their relations to human well-being. While urbanization is complex in many ways, we do know a lot about its patterns, processes, and effects. More specifically, we know a great deal about urban growth patterns in space and time, the underlying drivers and mechanisms, and myriad effects of urbanization on biodiversity, ecological processes, and ecosystem services. Compared to their ancient counterparts, contemporary cities tend to be bigger in physical size and ecological footprint, faster in growth rate in terms of both population and urbanized land, and more irregular in landscape composition and configuration. As coevolving human-environment systems, cities are spatially heterogeneous, complex adaptive systems. As such, the dynamic trajectory of cities can never be fully predicted or controlled, but can and should be influenced or guided in more desirable directions through planning and design activities that are based on urban ecological knowledge and sustainability principles. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000336465700021
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="15">
<title>General approaches for assessing urban environmental sustainability</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cosust.2012.09.003</url>
<snippet>Urban environmental sustainability assessment is increasingly a part of urban planning, from the perspective of mitigating local and global impacts and for adapting to regional and global resource constraints and anticipated climate events. We examine general techniques under three categories: consumption-based, metabolism-based and complex systems approaches. We sample recent and salient applications at spatial scales ranging from neighbourhoods to metropolitan regions. The scope and strengths of applications in these categories are complementary especially with regards to the attribution of impact. The first approach assesses environmental sustainability as a function of urban consumption, the second uses a more limited concept of consumption but better represents local and trans-boundary production activity and the third attributes cause and effect through quantifying relationships and feedbacks throughout the urban system. RI Baynes, Timothy/D-4738-2011; Wiedmann, Thomas/C-9158-2011 OI Baynes, Timothy/0000-0001-8416-3365; Wiedmann, Thomas/0000-0002-6395-8887
WOS:000310766600014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="16">
<title>Household time use, carbon footprints, and urban form: a review of the potential contributions of everyday living to the 1.5 degrees C climate target</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cosust.2018.02.007</url>
<snippet>The 1.5 degrees C mitigation challenge for urban areas goes far beyond decarbonizing the cities energy supply and needs to enable and incentivize carbon-free everyday living. Reviewing recent literature, we find that dense and mixed urban form enables lower direct emissions from mobility and housing, while income is the major driver of total household carbon footprints; importantly, these effects are not linear. The available urban infrastructure, services and societal arrangements, for example on work, all influence how households use their time, which goods and services they consume in everyday life and their subsequent carbon footprints and potential rebound effects. We conclude that changes in household consumption, time use and urban form are crucial for a 1.5 degrees C future. We further identify a range of issues for which a time use perspective could open up new avenues for research and policy. OI Smetschka, Barbara/0000-0002-7609-984X; Akenji, Lewis/0000-0003-4422-8819; Wiedenhofer, Dominik/0000-0001-7418-3477
WOS:000444521500003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="17">
<title>Convergent Surface Water Distributions in US Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10021-014-9751-y</url>
<snippet>Earths surface is rapidly urbanizing, resulting in dramatic changes in the abundance, distribution and character of surface water features in urban landscapes. However, the scope and consequences of surface water redistribution at broad spatial scales are not well understood. We hypothesized that urbanization would lead to convergent surface water abundance and distribution: in other words, cities will gain or lose water such that they become more similar to each other than are their surrounding natural landscapes. Using a database of more than 1 million water bodies and 1 million km of streams, we compared the surface water of 100 US cities with their surrounding undeveloped land. We evaluated differences in areal (A (WB)) and numeric densities (N (WB)) of water bodies (lakes, wetlands, and so on), the morphological characteristics of water bodies (size), and the density (D (C)) of surface flow channels (that is, streams and rivers). The variance of urban A (WB), N (WB), and D (C) across the 100 MSAs decreased, by 89, 25, and 71&#37;, respectively, compared to undeveloped land. These data show that many cities are surface water poor relative to undeveloped land; however, in drier landscapes urbanization increases the occurrence of surface water. This convergence pattern strengthened with development intensity, such that high intensity urban development had an areal water body density 98&#37; less than undeveloped lands. Urbanization appears to drive the convergence of hydrological features across the US, such that surface water distributions of cities are more similar to each other than to their surrounding landscapes. RI Hall, Sharon/K-7893-2012; Heffernan, James/D-1261-2010 OI Heffernan, James/0000-0001-7641-9949; Groffman, Peter/0000-0001-8371-6255; Morse, Jennifer/0000-0001-8872-4940; Cavender-Bares, Jeannine/0000-0003-3375-9630; Hobbie, Sarah/0000-0001-5159-031X
WOS:000336397600010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="18">
<title>Obsolescence in Urban Energy Infrastructures: The Influence of Scaling Laws on Consumption Forecasting</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10630732.2014.955340</url>
<snippet>Cities can be considered complex systems, constantly changing and adapting to new economic, social, and cultural dynamics. They exist in many forms and over a wide range of sizes. In spite of this, researchers have discovered regularities in the form of simple scaling laws that emerge when urban outputs of many types, such as income, patents, or energy consumption, are correlated with population size. This article briefly presents some facts and figures on scaling correlations in urban contexts and how this evidence can determine and influence the obsolescence of energy infrastructures. It finally suggests several strategies which could be used to ameliorate the impacts of this on the assessment of urban consumption forecasting.
WOS:000359698200002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="19">
<title>Cities as nuclei of sustainability?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0265813516638340</url>
<snippet>We have assembled CO2 emission figures from collections of urban GHG emission estimates published in peer-reviewed journals or reports from research institutes and non-governmental organizations. Analyzing the scaling with population size, we find that the exponent is development dependent with a transition from super- to sub-linear scaling. From the climate change mitigation point of view, the results suggest that urbanization is desirable in developed countries. Further, we compare this analysis with a second scaling relation, namely the fundamental allometry between city population and area, and propose that density might be a decisive quantity too. Last, we derive the theoretical country-wide urban emissions by integration and obtain a dependence on the size of the largest city. OI Rybski, Diego/0000-0001-6125-7705; Kropp, Juergen/0000-0001-7791-3420
WOS:000400907700003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="20">
<title>Energy and material flows of megacities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1504315112</url>
<snippet>Understanding the drivers of energy and material flows of cities is important for addressing global environmental challenges. Accessing, sharing, and managing energy and material resources is particularly critical for megacities, which face enormous social stresses because of their sheer size and complexity. Here we quantify the energy and material flows through the worlds 27 megacities with populations greater than 10 million people as of 2010. Collectively the resource flows through megacities are largely consistent with scaling laws established in the emerging science of cities. Correlations are established for electricity consumption, heating and industrial fuel use, ground transportation energy use, water consumption, waste generation, and steel production in terms of heating-degree-days, urban form, economic activity, and population growth. The results help identify megacities exhibiting high and low levels of consumption and those making efficient use of resources. The correlation between per capita electricity use and urbanized area per capita is shown to be a consequence of gross building floor area per capita, which is found to increase for lower-density cities. Many of the megacities are growing rapidly in population but are growing even faster in terms of gross domestic product (GDP) and energy use. In the decade from 2001-2011, electricity use and ground transportation fuel use in megacities grew at approximately half the rate of GDP growth. RI Cersosimo, Igor/J-6951-2014; Chen, Bin/A-6951-2012 OI Chen, Bin/0000-0002-5488-6850; Chiu, Anthony Shun Fung/0000-0003-2411-7302; Ibrahim, Nadine/0000-0003-1241-5935
WOS:000354390600050
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="21">
<title>On Scaling of Scientific Knowledge Production in US Metropolitan Areas</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0110805</url>
<snippet>Using data on all scientific publications from the Scopus database, we find a superlinear scaling effect for U. S. metropolitan areas as indicated by the increase of per capita publication output with city size. We also find that the variance of residuals is much higher for mid-sized cities (100,000 to 500,000 inhabitants) compared to larger cities. The latter result is indicative of the critical mass required to establish a scientific center in a particular discipline. Finally, we observe that the largest cities publish much less than the scaling law would predict, indicating that the largest cities are relatively unattractive locations for scientific research. RI Heimeriks, Gaston/G-1057-2012; Frenken, Koen/C-4486-2017 OI Heimeriks, Gaston/0000-0002-0577-6938; Frenken, Koen/0000-0003-4731-0201
WOS:000345204200037
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="22">
<title>Exploring the Relationship between Urban Forms and CO2 Emissions in 104 Chinese Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)UP.1943-5444.0000400</url>
<snippet>This study explores the empirical relationship between city-level urban forms and CO2 emissions in 104 Chinese prefectural-level cities. Although the analytical focus is on polycentric urban forms, the analysis has also accounted for population size and land use compactness. CO2 emissions data are aggregated from the Fossil Fuel Data Assimilation System (FFDASv2) data portal. The analysis identifies substantial economies of scale in CO2 with respect to total population. Further, despite a substantial wealth effect on CO2 emissions, cities with more centralized and compact urban forms are associated with lesser emissions, ceteris paribus. Whereas existing analyses of CO2 emissions in Chinese cities have often been limited to a handful of provincial capitals, the analysis covers a larger sample of cities. The paper concludes with spatial planning policy implications. (C) 2017 American Society of Civil Engineers. RI Wang, Mingshu/I-1533-2014 OI Wang, Mingshu/0000-0001-5260-3143; Liu, Xingjian/0000-0003-4158-3655
WOS:000415351000002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="23">
<title>Benchmarking urban energy efficiency in the UK</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.enpol.2013.08.063</url>
<snippet>This study asks what is the best way to measure urban energy efficiency. There has been recent interest in identifying efficient cities so that best practices can be shared, a process known as benchmarking. Previous studies have used relatively simple metrics that provide limited insight on the complexity of urban energy efficiency and arguably fail to provide a fair measure of urban performance. Using a data set of 198 urban UK local administrative units, three methods are compared: ratio measures, regression residuals, and data envelopment analysis. The results show that each method has its own strengths and weaknesses regarding the ease of interpretation, ability to identify outliers and provide consistent rankings. Efficient areas are diverse but are notably found in low income areas of large conurbations such as London, whereas industrial areas are consistently ranked as inefficient. The results highlight the shortcomings of the underlying production-based energy accounts. Ideally urban energy efficiency benchmarks would be built on consumption-based accounts, but interim recommendations are made regarding the use of efficiency measures that improve upon current practice and facilitate wider conversations about what it means for a specific city to be energy-efficient within an interconnected economy. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000330085400059
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="24">
<title>The geography of urban greenhouse gas emissions in Asia: A regional analysis</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.gloenvcha.2012.07.002</url>
<snippet>This paper aims to advance two objectives: (1) identify and explore greenhouse gas emissions from urban areas in Asia at the regional level; and (2) explore covariates of urban greenhouse gas emissions. We use the Emissions Database for Global Atmospheric Research estimates for carbon dioxide, methane, nitrous oxide, and sulfur hexafluoride from 14 source activities for the year 2000, which are allocated on a 1/10 degrees global grid. We extract emissions for 3535 urban extents all with populations over 50,000, accounting for approximately 91&#37; of the regions urban population. We use regression analysis to associate emissions with urban area and growth, economic, and biophysical characteristics. Our findings suggest that urban areas account for between 30 and 38&#37; of total anthropogenic greenhouse gas emissions for the region and that emission per capita averages from urban areas are lower than those at the national level. Important covariates for total urban greenhouse gas emissions include population size, density and growth rate, income per capita, development status and elevation. This is a first and preliminary assessment of regional baseline trends using these data and this top-down analysis. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. OI Marcotullio, Peter/0000-0001-8133-1204; Sarzynski, Andrea/0000-0001-9941-5764
WOS:000309788000013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="25">
<title>Features, trajectories and driving forces for energy-related GHG emissions from Chinese mega cites: The case of Beijing, Tianjin, Shanghai and Chongqing</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2011.11.040</url>
<snippet>With Chinas rapid economic development and urbanization process, cities are facing great challenges for tackling anthropogenic climate change. In this paper we present features, trajectories and driving forces for energy-related greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from four Chinese mega-cities (Beijing, Tianjin, Shanghai and Chongqing) during 1995-2009. First, top-down GHG inventories of these four cities, including direct emissions (scope 1) and emissions from imported electricity (scope 2) are presented. Then, the driving forces for the GHG emission changes are uncovered by adopting a time serial LMDI decomposition analysis. Results indicate that annual GHG emission in these four cities exceeds more than 500 million tons and such an amount is still rapidly growing. GHG emissions are mainly generated from energy use in industrial sector and coal-burning thermal power plants. The growth of GHG emissions in four mega-cities during 1995-2009 is mainly due to economic activity effect, partially offset by improvements in carbon intensity. Besides, the proportion of indirect GHG emission from imported energy use (scope 2) keeps growing, implying that big cities are further dependent on energy/material supplies from neighboring regions. Therefore, a comprehensive consideration on various perspectives is needed so that different stakeholders can better understand their responsibilities on reducing total GHG emissions. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. RI Liu, Zhu/A-4634-2013; Xue, Bing/D-1830-2009; Geng, Yong/B-6310-2018 OI Liu, Zhu/0000-0002-8968-7050; Xue, Bing/0000-0002-7790-1216; Geng, Yong/0000-0002-2284-1375; Liang, Sai/0000-0002-6306-5800
WOS:000300465800028
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="26">
<title>Does Size Matter? Scaling of CO2 Emissions and US Urban Areas</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0064727</url>
<snippet>Urban areas consume more than 66&#37; of the worlds energy and generate more than 70&#37; of global greenhouse gas emissions. With the worlds population expected to reach 10 billion by 2100, nearly 90&#37; of whom will live in urban areas, a critical question for planetary sustainability is how the size of cities affects energy use and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions. Are larger cities more energy and emissions efficient than smaller ones? Do larger cities exhibit gains from economies of scale with regard to emissions? Here we examine the relationship between city size and CO2 emissions for U.S. metropolitan areas using a production accounting allocation of emissions. We find that for the time period of 1999-2008, CO2 emissions scale proportionally with urban population size. Contrary to theoretical expectations, larger cities are not more emissions efficient than smaller ones. RI Seto, Karen/C-2722-2008
WOS:000319961900015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="27">
<title>Urbanization and the carbon cycle: Current capabilities and research outlook from the natural sciences perspective</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/2014EF000255</url>
<snippet>This paper explores the urban carbon cycle from the natural sciences perspective, identifying key knowledge gaps and priority areas for future research. The combination of large, concentrated carbon fluxes and rapid change makes cities key elements of the carbon cycle and offers the potential for them to serve as "first responders" for climate action. Estimates of urban-scale carbon fluxes are significantly more uncertain than at larger spatial scales, in part because past studies have mostly avoided local/urban scales where the mix of anthropogenic and natural fluxes is complex and difficult to observationally isolate. To develop effective emission reduction policies, we need to understand emission sources and how they may be changing. Such improved quantification and understanding of underlying processes at the urban scale will not only provide policy-relevant information and improve the understanding of urban dynamics and future scenarios, but will also translate into better global-scale anthropogenic flux estimates, and advance our understanding of carbon cycle and climate feedbacks across multiple scales. Understanding the relationship between urbanization and urban carbon flows requires intellectual integration with research communities beyond the natural sciences. Cities can serve as interdisciplinary process laboratories that are sufficiently constrained in both spatial and governance scale to support truly integrated research by the natural sciences, social sciences, and engineering. A thoughtfully crafted science research agenda that is grounded in sustained, dense observations relevant to estimating urban carbon fluxes and their controlling processes and is focused on a statistically significant sample of cities will advance our understanding of the carbon cycle. RI Kort, Eric/F-9942-2012; Grimm, Nancy/D-2840-2009 OI Kort, Eric/0000-0003-4940-7541; Grimm, Nancy/0000-0001-9374-660X; Larson, Elisabeth/0000-0001-6588-1038; Shrestha, Gyami/0000-0001-7150-8731
WOS:000358136100002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="28">
<title>Settlement Structures and Carbon Emissions in Germany: The Effects of Social and Physical Concentration on Carbon Emissions in Rural and Urban Residential Areas</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/eet.1600</url>
<snippet>Using data from the German Socio-Economic Panel (GSOEP), we show that nearly 50&#37; of all carbon emissions caused by private transportation and building operations in Germany can be explained by structural determinants that go hand in hand with infrastructural peculiarities in rural and urban residential areas. Taking the theoretical background of building physics, allometry and increasing returns to scale as a vantage point, this paper analyses the effects of physical concentration e.g. apartment buildings versus bungalows and social compactness e.g. multigenerational versus single households. In contrast to related studies, this perspective reveals that social and physical concentration tend to counteract each other and thus clarifies the intricate interactions between household structure, different infrastructural environments and carbon emissions. A supplementary finding is that the spatial distribution of fuel types plays a large role in explaining lower carbon emissions in urban settlements. This leads us to the conclusion that environmental policy should foster physical concentration in rural and social concentration in urban infrastructural environments. Copyright 
WOS:000315025900002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="29">
<title>Scaling down the "Netherlands Fallacy": a local-level quantitative study of the effect of affluence on the carbon footprint across the United States</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.envsci.2017.09.001</url>
<snippet>Much quantitative research examining the determinants of the ecological footprint has been conducted cross nationally, where data on cross-boundary flows have been readily available. While local-level studies of the footprint do exist for specific localities, most quantitative research at this scale has examined direct environmental impacts attributed to the internal activities of the locality, for instance, carbon emissions. Our analysis builds on this previous work by exploiting a local-level carbon footprint dataset with coverage for 28,321 zip codes across the United States. Following prior research, we focus on the effect of local affluence, measured in terms of median household income. In spatial regression models, we regress the per capita carbon footprint on local affluence, controlling for a variety of other factors. Consistent with previous work, we find that affluence is positively correlated the carbon footprint and there is no evidence of an environmental Kuznets curve. In the conclusion, we review the results of the study and discuss their implications for policy, specifically in terms of cross-boundary environmental problems. OI Habans, Robert/0000-0001-6693-9182
WOS:000415909600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="30">
<title>The socio-economic drivers of material stock accumulation in Japan's prefectures</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolecon.2015.03.001</url>
<snippet>Physical economy research has, thus far, focused on the throughput of materials that underpin economic development. The role of stocks of buildings and infrastructure has remained underexplored, yet it is the physical stock that provides service to society. To fill this gap, this research investigates stock dynamics in Japan in relation to population and economic drivers using panel regression and IPAT analyses for the past five decades. We recognize characteristic changes in the strength and relative influence of the drivers throughout time, in different subnational regions, and on the dynamics of buildings compared to transportation infrastructure. We find that material stock accumulation mainly occurred due to growth in economic activity, specifically by tertiary sector demand. Apart from a period of government-driven stock accumulation in the 1990s to stimulate economic growth, as economic and population growth slowed stock accumulation dynamics also changed signaling a new stock saturation trend. Migration from rural to urban areas has recently become an influential driver, leaving behind underused buildings and roads. This analysis provides a case study on how socio-economic drivers and stock accumulation interacted and changed while the country matured, which may have implications for understanding stock dynamics in rapidly industrializing economies. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Schandl, Heinz/C-5055-2008; Tanikawa, Hiroki/G-8033-2012 OI Schandl, Heinz/0000-0001-6399-4231; Tanikawa, Hiroki/0000-0002-5896-9629; Fishman, Tomer/0000-0003-4405-2382
WOS:000353096900007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="31">
<title>Network Centrality of Metro Systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0040575</url>
<snippet>Whilst being hailed as the remedy to the worlds ills, cities will need to adapt in the 21st century. In particular, the role of public transport is likely to increase significantly, and new methods and technics to better plan transit systems are in dire need. This paper examines one fundamental aspect of transit: network centrality. By applying the notion of betweenness centrality to 28 worldwide metro systems, the main goal of this paper is to study the emergence of global trends in the evolution of centrality with network size and examine several individual systems in more detail. Betweenness was notably found to consistently become more evenly distributed with size (i.e. no "winner takes all") unlike other complex network properties. Two distinct regimes were also observed that are representative of their structure. Moreover, the share of betweenness was found to decrease in a power law with size (with exponent 1 for the average node), but the share of most central nodes decreases much slower than least central nodes (0.87 vs. 2.48). Finally the betweenness of individual stations in several systems were examined, which can be useful to locate stations where passengers can be redistributed to relieve pressure from overcrowded stations. Overall, this study offers significant insights that can help planners in their task to design the systems of tomorrow, and similar undertakings can easily be imagined to other urban infrastructure systems (e.g., electricity grid, water/wastewater system, etc.) to develop more sustainable cities.
WOS:000306461800108
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="32">
<title>10 Years Later: Revisiting Priorities for Science and Society a Decade After the Millennium Ecosystem Assessment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/bs.aecr.2015.10.005</url>
<snippet>The study of ecological services (ESs) is fast becoming a cornerstone of mainstream ecology, largely because they provide a useful means of linking functioning to societal benefits in complex systems by connecting different organizational levels. In order to identify the main challenges facing current and future ES research, we analyzed the effects of the publication of the Millennium Ecosystem Assessment (MEA, 2005) on different disciplines. Within a set of topics framed around concepts embedded within the MEA, each co-author identified five key research challenges and, where feasible, suggested possible solutions. Concepts included those related to specific service types (i.e. provisioning, supporting, regulating, cultural, aesthetic services) as well as more synthetic issues spanning the natural and social sciences, which often linked a wide range of disciplines, as was the case for the application of network theory. By merging similar responses, and removing some of the narrower suggestions from our sample pool, we distilled the key challenges into a smaller subset. We review some of the historical context to the MEA and identify some of the broader scientific and philosophical issues that still permeate discourse in this field. Finally, we consider where the greatest advances are most likely to be made in the next decade and beyond. RI Mulder, Christian/N-4726-2015; Scherber, Christoph/B-6611-2009; Hines, Jes/L-7668-2016; Vonk, Jan Arie/B-1105-2009; Haughton, Alison/A-7769-2013; PASCUAL, UNAI/B-4766-2012; Cramer, Wolfgang/B-8221-2008; Wood, Stephen/A-1928-2017; Massol, Francois/D-9872-2013; Mancinelli, Giorgio/A-7679-2013 OI Mulder, Christian/0000-0001-5735-6989; Scherber, Christoph/0000-0001-7924-8911; Hines, Jes/0000-0002-9129-5179; Vonk, Jan Arie/0000-0002-8803-1148; Haughton, Alison/0000-0002-2852-5736; PASCUAL, UNAI/0000-0002-5696-236X; Cramer, Wolfgang/0000-0002-9205-5812; Wood, Stephen/0000-0002-9551-8165; Massol, Francois/0000-0002-4098-955X; Mancinelli, Giorgio/0000-0002-5833-7322; Bonkowski, Michael/0000-0003-2656-1183; Penuelas, Josep/0000-0002-7215-0150; Bohan, David/0000-0001-5656-775X; Sutherland, William/0000-0002-6498-0437; Vacher, Corinne/0000-0003-3023-6113; Setala, Heikki Martti/0000-0002-5230-4001; Eisenhauer, Nico/0000-0002-0371-6720
WOS:000376149300002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="33">
<title>Environmental and natural resource implications of sustainable urban infrastructure systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/aa98ca</url>
<snippet>As cities grow, their environmental and natural resource footprints also tend to grow to keep up with the increasing demand on essential urban services such as passenger transportation, commercial space, and thermal comfort. The urban infrastructure systems, or socio-technical systems providing these services are the major conduits through which natural resources are consumed and environmental impacts are generated. This paper aims to gauge the potential reductions in environmental and resources footprints through urban transformation, including the deployment of resource-efficient socio-technical systems and strategic densification. Using hybrid life cycle assessment approach combined with scenarios, we analyzed the greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, water use, metal consumption and land use of selected socio-technical systems in 84 cities from the present to 2050. The socio-technical systems analyzed are: (1) bus rapid transit with electric buses, (2) green commercial buildings, and (3) district energy. We developed a baseline model for each city considering gross domestic product, population density, and climate conditions. Then, we overlaid three scenarios on top of the baseline model: (1) decarbonization of electricity, (2) aggressive deployment of resource-efficient socio-technical systems, and (3) strategic urban densification scenarios to each city and quantified their potentials in reducing the environmental and resource impacts of cities by 2050. The results show that, under the baseline scenario, the environmental and natural resource footprints of all 84 cities combined would increase 58&#37;-116&#37; by 2050. The resource-efficient scenario along with strategic densification, however, has the potential to curve down GHG emissions to 17&#37; below the 2010 level in 2050. Such transformation can also limit the increase in all resource footprints to less than 23&#37; relative to 2010. This analysis suggests that resource-efficient urban infrastructure and decarbonization of electricity coupled with strategic densification have a potential to mitigate resources and environmental footprints of growing cities. RI Baynes, Timothy/D-4738-2011 OI Baynes, Timothy/0000-0001-8416-3365; Suh, Sangwon/0000-0001-8290-6276
WOS:000417925700003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="34">
<title>Effects of city size on the large-scale decentralised solar energy potential</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.egypro.2017.07.372</url>
<snippet>To assess the PV-potential on rooftops for decentralized electricity supply in Switzerland, the potential is compared with the following urban-size parameters: (a) urban population, (b) number of buildings, 
WOS:000411783600117
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="35">
<title>CO2 emissions in relation to street-network configuration and city size</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.trd.2014.11.025</url>
<snippet>The street-network efficiency of tens of British cities in relation to transport fuel consumption and CO2 emissions are analyzed. The results show a strong linear positive correlation between length entropy and average street length, and a negative correlation between entropy and street density. Also, the results suggest that in a large city the street network is used more efficiently than in a small city, as indicated by the sublinear relations between city size (population) and the number of streets, total length of streets, and the area covered by the street network. The sublinear relation means that these parameters grow more slowly than the city size. By contrast, because a larger fraction of the street network is used at close to full capacity during considerable part of the time in a large city than a small one, the fuel consumption and the CO2 emissions show a linear relation with city size and superlinear relation with total street length. The superlinear relation means that the CO2 emissions increase faster than the total street length, a measure of the network size. Thus, large cities may be less energy efficient and environmentally friendly than small cities. In every city the street network needs to interconnect all the buildings, which requires a certain minimum size. In a small city, however, the network is used to a low capacity most of the time so that its relations to fuel consumption and the CO2 emissions are more favorable than those in a large city. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000350525300009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="36">
<title>Urbanization bubble: Four quadrants measurement model</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cities.2015.04.007</url>
<snippet>The proper understanding of the urbanization bubble is very important to assist local governments in adopting strategies to mitigate the effects of the bubble and guide urbanization toward sustainable development. This paper presents a method of measuring the urbanization bubble with particular reference to China. In referring to the definition of an economic bubble, this study defines the urbanization bubble as a dynamic process in which urbanization rate (U-R) deviates from four urbanization performance variables comprising the proportion of urban population with registration (T-RP), urban construction land area (T-BA), level of industrial development (L-ID) and level of public facilities (L-PF). Four coordinates are formed between the rate of urbanization and the four performance variables to examine the practice of urbanization in terms of four quadrants. The ratios between changes in urbanization rate and the changes of the four urbanization performance variables are introduced to measure the urbanization bubble. The method is tested through a case study to show that the coordinate method has the potential to help policy makers detect any bubble in the process of urbanization. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. OI Shen, Liyin/0000-0002-0163-4377; Zhang, Xiaoling/0000-0002-6369-9424
WOS:000356734200002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="37">
<title>The GWP-Chart: An environmental tool for guiding urban planning processes. Application to concrete sidewalks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cities.2011.01.003</url>
<snippet>The systematized study of urban morphology has led to the development of integrated tools based on the knowledge of the relation between physical density and urban form. These tools do help planners and decision makers; however, environmental data is rarely included in them. This paper presents the GWP-Chart, a method that combines urban planning tools with environmental data, obtained through the use of the life cycle assessment (LCA) results. In order to explain its use, three urban fabrics have been selected. According to their morphology and their ground space index (GSI) and public space ratio (PSR) values, the contribution of the sidewalk subsystem to the global impact per square meter of urban development can be quantified and communicated. The GWP-Chart is applicable to all types of urban fabrics and scales (street or square, island, fabric or district), as well as adaptable to any urban infrastructure or subsystem and can be extended to other environmental impacts. Its advantages lie in its accurateness, adaptability and ease of interpretation. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. RI Gabarrell Durany, Xavier/F-5575-2011; Josa, Alejandro/E-7417-2016 OI Gabarrell Durany, Xavier/0000-0003-1730-4337; Josa, Alejandro/0000-0003-1180-7910; Oliver-Sola, Jordi/0000-0001-8034-8610
WOS:000290002200004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="38">
<title>Large cities are less green</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep04235</url>
<snippet>We study how urban quality evolves as a result of carbon dioxide emissions as urban agglomerations grow. We employ a bottom-up approach combining two unprecedented microscopic data on population and carbon dioxide emissions in the continental US. We first aggregate settlements that are close to each other into cities using the City Clustering Algorithm (CCA) defining cities beyond the administrative boundaries. Then, we use data on CO2 emissions at a fine geographic scale to determine the total emissions of each city. We find a superlinear scaling behavior, expressed by a power-law, between CO2 emissions and city population with average allometric exponent beta = 1.46 across all cities in the US. This result suggests that the high productivity of large cities is done at the expense of a proportionally larger amount of emissions compared to small cities. Furthermore, our results are substantially different from those obtained by the standard administrative definition of cities, i.e. Metropolitan Statistical Area (MSA). Specifically, MSAs display isometric scaling emissions and we argue that this discrepancy is due to the overestimation of MSA areas. The results suggest that allometric studies based on administrative boundaries to define cities may suffer from endogeneity bias. RI Andrade, Jose/C-5451-2013; UFC, DF/E-1564-2017; Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/J-4630-2016 OI Andrade, Jose/0000-0002-5571-7610; Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/0000-0002-9247-6780
WOS:000332016000002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="39">
<title>Ways Forward to Explore Sustainable Land Use in an Urbanizing World</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>
WOS:000348849200017
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="40">
<title>Scaling: lost in the smog Commentary</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1068/b4105c</url>
<snippet>
WOS:000344091800002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="41">
<title>A multi-level framework for metabolism in urban energy systems from an ecological perspective</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.resconrec.2017.05.005</url>
<snippet>Cities have become the main centres of consumption and transformation of resources. As cities are still growing in terms of physical size, number of inhabitants and total energy consumption, unique challenges present themselves in order to safeguard a healthy urban living environment, while preventing resource shortages and pollution. The concept of urban metabolism may contribute to sustainable growth of cities as it can be used to understand emergent patterns in flows of energy and materials in the urban environment. The concept of urban metabolism draws upon an analogy with the biological meaning of metabolism, as it occurs in organisms and ecosystems. Here we present a review of the interpretation of urban metabolism in the context of urban energy dynamics and assess the validity of the proposed analogy with biology. Based on this analogy, we propose a conceptual framework for the role of urban metabolism in urban energy systems. Our review highlights that urban energy systems show a hierarchical organization comparable to ecological systems. However, the emergent patterns that result from the dynamics within urban systems differ from those occurring within ecological systems. We suggest that, in contrast to biological systems, urban energy systems lack energetic constraints at the lowest level of organisation that could enable the resource-efficient regulation of energy requirements at larger scales. The proposed framework highlights that low-level resource supply regulations may contribute to introduce scale-dependent relationships that increase energy use efficiency as cities grow.
WOS:000428828300023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="42">
<title>Why Do Cities Grow? Insights from Nonequilibrium Thermodynamics at the Urban and Global Scales</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jiec.12239</url>
<snippet>This forum article explores thermodynamic understanding of the growth of cities, including theoretical foundations, observations, and analysis. The general theory of nonequilibrium thermodynamics is reviewed, recognizing differences in interpretation between Prigogine and Schneider and Kay as well as discussing the hypothesis of maximum entropy production. Calculations of exergy gradients in a few cities and settlements, along with measures of anthropogenic heat loss in further cities, support the notion that cities are dissipative structures. The observation that primary energy use per capita increases in Singapore and Hong Kong as they grow is further evidence to support the thermodynamic understanding of the growth of cities, indicative of an increasing rate of entropy production. At the global scale, the strong linear relationship between global urban population and total global energy use, and the distribution of city sizes according to Zipfs law, can be understood as emergent results based on thermodynamics. Parallel results might be derived from models that represent underlying microscale processes, several of which are reviewed. Issues for future research include: development of nonequilibrium thermodynamic models specific to city growth; further study of exergy flows of cities with consistent methodology, including attention to solar energy exchanges in cities; and further exploration of links between thermodynamic and economic models of urban growth.
WOS:000353243300007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="43">
<title>The study of urban metabolism and its applications to urban planning and design</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2010.10.022</url>
<snippet>Following formative work in the 1970s. disappearance in the 1980s, and reemergence in the 1990s, a chronological review shows that the past decade has witnessed increasing interest in the study of urban metabolism. The review finds that there are two related, non-conflicting, schools of urban metabolism: one following Odum describes metabolism in terms of energy equivalents: while the second more broadly expresses a citys flows of water, materials and nutrients in terms of mass fluxes. Four example applications of urban metabolism studies are discussed: urban sustainability indicators; inputs to urban greenhouse gas emissions calculation; mathematical models of urban metabolism for policy analysis; and as a basis for sustainable urban design. Future directions include fuller integration of social, health and economic indicators into the urban metabolism framework, while tackling the great sustainability challenge of reconstructing cities. (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000292670800002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="44">
<title>Bigger Is Not Always Better: A Comparative Analysis of Cities and their Air Pollution Impact</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0042098011432557</url>
<snippet>This paper investigates the pressure placed by cities on their environment with respect to urban air pollution. The analysis employs a spatially explicit global dataset of emissions to estimate urban emissions of four pollutants from a sample of 8038 cities world-wide in 2005. A cross-sectional regression analysis is then conducted to examine the association of urban air pollution with socioeconomic and geographical factors. The results confirm that urban pollution is associated primarily, but not exclusively, with demographics. The results suggest that urban pollution is likely to increase with population growth and that economic modernisation is unlikely to provide much relief from the pressures placed by coming population growth. The findings suggest that policy-makers must focus on reducing the emissions intensity of production activities within cities, especially from the energy sector, if they are to avoid rapid growth in urban air pollution in coming decades. OI Sarzynski, Andrea/0000-0001-9941-5764
WOS:000309578200009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="45">
<title>How congestion shapes cities: from mobility patterns to scaling</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep05561</url>
<snippet>The recent availability of data for cities has allowed scientists to exhibit scalings which present themselves in the form of a power-law dependence on population of various socio-economical and structural indicators. We propose here a stochastic theory of urban growth which accounts for some of the observed scalings and we confirm these predictions on US and OECD empirical data. In particular, we show that the dependence on population size of the total number of miles driven daily, the total length of the road network, the total traffic delay, the total consumption of gasoline, the quantity of CO2 emitted and the relation between area and population of cities, are all governed by a single parameter which characterizes the sensitivity to congestion. Our results suggest that diseconomies associated with congestion scale superlinearly with population size, implying that -despite polycentrism- cities whose transportation infrastructure rely heavily on traffic sensitive modes are unsustainable. OI Louf, Remi/0000-0001-7929-5507
WOS:000338422600002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="46">
<title>A Top-Down Regional Assessment of Urban Greenhouse Gas Emissions in Europe</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s13280-013-0467-6</url>
<snippet>This paper provides an account of urban greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from 40 countries in Europe and examines covariates of emissions levels. We use a "top-down" analysis of emissions as spatially reported in the Emission Dataset for Global Atmospheric Research supplemented by Carbon Monitoring for Action from 1153 European cities larger than 50 000 population in 2000 (comprising &gt; 81 &#37; of the total European urban population). Urban areas are defined spatially and demographically by the Global Rural Urban Mapping Project. We compare these results with "bottom-up" carbon accounting method results for cities in the region. Our results suggest that direct (Scopes 1 and 2) GHG emissions from urban areas range between 44 and 54 &#37; of total anthropogenic emissions for the region. While individual urban GHG footprints vary from bottom-up studies, both the mean differences and the regional energy-related GHG emission share support previous findings. Correlation analysis indicates that the urban GHG emissions in Europe are mainly influenced by population size, density, and income and not by biophysical conditions. We argue that these data and methods of analysis are best used at the regional or higher scales. OI Marcotullio, Peter/0000-0001-8133-1204; Sarzynski, Andrea/0000-0001-9941-5764
WOS:000343659300013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="47">
<title>Urbanization and the carbon cycle: Contributions from social science</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/2014EF000257</url>
<snippet>This paper outlines the contributions of social science to the study of interactions between urbanization patterns and processes and the carbon cycle, and identifies gaps in knowledge and priority areas for future social scientific research contributions. While previously studied as a unidimensional process, we conceptualize urbanization as a multidimensional, social and biophysical process driven by continuous changes across space and time in various subsystems including biophysical, built environment, and socio-institutional (e.g., economic, political, demographic, behavioral, and sociological). We review research trends and findings focused on the socio-institutional subsystem of the urbanization process, and particularly the dynamics, relationships, and predictions relevant to energy use and greenhouse gas emissions. Our findings suggest that a multidimensional perspective of urbanization facilitates a wider spectrum of research relevant to carbon cycle dynamics, even within the socio-institutional subsystem. However, there is little consensus around the details and mechanisms underlying the relationship between urban socio-institutional subsystems and the carbon cycle. We argue that progress in understanding the relationship between urbanization and the carbon cycle may be achieved if social scientists work collaboratively with each other as well as with scientists from other disciplines. From this review, we identify research priorities where collaborative social scientific efforts are necessary in conjunction with other disciplinary approaches to generate a more complete understanding of urbanization as a process and its relationship to the carbon cycle. RI Seto, Karen/C-2722-2008 OI Sarzynski, Andrea/0000-0001-9941-5764; Marcotullio, Peter/0000-0001-8133-1204
WOS:000358136100003
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
