<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Population stability, cooperation, and the invasibility of the human species</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0905708106</url>
<snippet>The biogeographic expansion of modern humans out of Africa began approximate to 50,000 years ago. This expansion resulted in the colonization of most of the land area and habitats throughout the globe and in the replacement of preexisting hominid species. However, such rapid population growth and geographic spread is somewhat unexpected for a large primate with a slow, density-dependent life history. Here, we suggest a mechanism for these outcomes by modifying a simple density-dependent population model to allow varying levels of intraspecific competition for finite resources. Reducing intraspecific competition increases carrying capacities, growth rates, and stability, including persistence times and speed of recovery from perturbations. Our model suggests that the energetic benefits of cooperation in modern humans may have outweighed the slow rate of human population growth, effectively ensuring that once modern humans colonized a region long-term population persistence was near inevitable. Our model also provides insight into the interplay of structural complexity and stability in social species. OI DeLong, John/0000-0003-0558-8213; Burger, Oskar/0000-0002-7552-5851
WOS:000268440200012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>City density and CO2 efficiency</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.enpol.2016.01.015</url>
<snippet>Cities play a vital role in the global climate change mitigation agenda. City population density is one of the key factors that influence urban energy consumption and the subsequent GHG emissions. However, previous research on the relationship between population density and GHG emissions led to contradictory results due to urban/rural definition conundrum and the varying methodologies for estimating GHG emissions. This work addresses these ambiguities by employing the City Clustering Algorithm (CCA) and utilizing the gridded CO2 emissions data. Our results, derived from the analysis of all inhabited areas in the US, show a sub-linear relationship between population density and the total emissions (i.e. the sum of on-road and building emissions) on a per capita basis. Accordingly, we find that doubling the population density would entail a reduction in the total CO2 emissions in buildings and on-road sectors typically by at least 42&#37;. Moreover, we find that population density exerts a higher influence on on-road emissions than buildings emissions. From an energy consumption point of view, our results suggest that on-going urban sprawl will lead to an increase in on-road energy consumption in cities and therefore stresses the importance of developing adequate local policy measures to limit urban sprawl. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. OI Kropp, Juergen/0000-0001-7791-3420; Gudipudi, Venkata Ramana/0000-0002-8758-9369
WOS:000371550300032
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>A unified theory of urban living</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/467912a</url>
<snippet>
WOS:000283254700015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>A review of urban ecosystem services: six key challenges for future research</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoser.2015.05.001</url>
<snippet>Global urbanization creates opportunities and challenges for human well-being and transition towards sustainability. Urban areas are human-environment systems that depend fundamentally on ecosystems, and thus require an understanding of the management of urban ecosystem services to ensure sustainable urban planning. The purpose of this study is to provide a systematic review of urban ecosystems services research, which addresses the combined domain of ecosystem services and urban development. We examined emerging trends and gaps in how urban ecosystem services are conceptualized in peer-reviewed case study literature, including the geographical distribution of research, the development and use of the urban ecosystem services concept, and the involvement of stakeholders. We highlight six challenges aimed at strengthening the concepts potential to facilitate meaningful inter- and transdisciplinary work for ecosystem services research and planning. Achieving a cohesive conceptual approach in the research field will address (i) the need for more extensive spatial and contextual coverage, (ii) continual clarification of definitions, (iii) recognition of limited data transferability, (iv) more comprehensive stakeholder involvement, (v) more integrated research efforts, and (vi) translation of scientific findings into actionable knowledge, feeding information back into planning and management. We conclude with recommendations for conducting further research while incorporating these challenges. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. OI Abson, David/0000-0003-3755-785X; Brink, Ebba/0000-0001-5865-2536; Rau, Anna-Lena/0000-0002-1068-9273; Luederitz, Christopher/0000-0002-7873-4229
WOS:000363666900011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>A global fingerprint of macro-scale changes in urban structure from 1999 to 2009</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/8/2/024004</url>
<snippet>Urban population now exceeds rural population globally, and 60-80&#37; of global energy consumption by households, businesses, transportation, and industry occurs in urban areas. There is growing evidence that built-up infrastructure contributes to carbon emissions inertia, and that investments in infrastructure today have delayed climate cost in the future. Although the United Nations statistics include data on urban population by country and select urban agglomerations, there are no empirical data on built-up infrastructure for a large sample of cities. Here we present the first study to examine changes in the structure of the worlds largest cities from 1999 to 2009. Combining data from two space-borne sensors-backscatter power (PR) from NASAs SeaWinds microwave scatterometer, and nighttime lights (NL) from NOAAs defense meteorological satellite program/operational linescan system (DMSP/OLS)-we report large increases in built-up infrastructure stock worldwide and show that cities are expanding both outward and upward. Our results reveal previously undocumented recent and rapid changes in urban areas worldwide that reflect pronounced shifts in the form and structure of cities. Increases in built-up infrastructure are highest in East Asian cities, with Chinese cities rapidly expanding their material infrastructure stock in both height and extent. In contrast, Indian cities are primarily building out and not increasing in verticality. This new dataset will help characterize the structure and form of cities, and ultimately improve our understanding of how cities affect regional-to-global energy use and greenhouse gas emissions. RI Seto, Karen/C-2722-2008 OI Milliman, Thomas/0000-0001-6234-8967
WOS:000321425100008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>Are there higher pedestrian fatalities in larger cities?: A scaling analysis of 115 to 161 largest cities in the United States</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15389588.2016.1162904</url>
<snippet>Objective: In 2012, 4,743 pedestrians were killed in the United States, representing 14&#37; of total traffic fatalities. The number of pedestrians injured was higher at 76,000. Therefore, 36 out of 52 of the largest cities in the United States have adopted a citywide target of reducing pedestrian fatalities. The number of cities adopting the reduction goal during 2011 and 2012 increased rapidly with 8 more cities. We examined the scaling relationship of pedestrian fatality counts as a function of the population size of 115 to 161 large U.S. cities during the period of 1994 to 2011. We also examined the scaling relationship of nonpedestrian and total traffic fatality counts as a function of the population size.Methods: For the data source of fatality measures we used Traffic Safety Facts Fatality Analysis Reporting System/General Estimates System annual reports published each year from 1994 to 2011 by the NHTSA. Using the data source we conducted both annual cross-sectional and panel data bivariate and multivariate regression models. In the construction of the estimated functional relationship between traffic fatality measures and various factors, we used the simple power function for urban scaling used by Bettencourt etal. (2007, 2010) and the refined STIRPAT (stochastic impacts by regression on population, affluence, and technology) model used in Dietz and Rosa (1994, 1997) and York etal. (2003).Results: We found that the scaling relationship display diseconomies of scale or sublinear for pedestrian fatalities. However, the relationship displays a superlinear relationship in case of nonpedestrian fatalities. The scaling relationship for total traffic fatality counts display a nearly linear pattern. When the relationship was examined by the 4 subgroups of cities with different population sizes, the most pronounced sublinear scaling relationships for all 3 types of fatality counts was discovered for the subgroup of megacities with a population of more than 1 million.Conclusions: The scaling patterns of traffic fatalities of subgroups of cities depend on population sizes of the cities in subgroups. In particular, 9 megacities with populations of more than 1 million are significantly different from the remaining cities and should be viewed as a totally separate group. Thus, analysis of the patterns of traffic fatalities needs to be conducted within the group of megacities separately from the other cities with smaller population sizes for devising prevention policies to reduce traffic fatalities in both megacities and smaller cities.
WOS:000384322100010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>The Metabolism of the City: The Mathematics of Networks and Urban Surfaces</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/ad.1275</url>
<snippet>
WOS:000294183200019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Sharing or sparing? How should we grow the world's cities?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/1365-2664.12118</url>
<snippet>1. There has long been a debate amongst conservation biologists about how agricultural land use should be distributed spatially. Advocates of land sparing argue that high-intensity food production on small units of land will conserve more natural habitat than low-intensity farming spread across larger areas. Others argue that less intensive production over a greater area of land will reduce the overall load of human stressors upon ecosystems. 2. Although agricultural and urban systems have traditionally been considered as different fields of research, there are strong parallels between the two landscapes in the patterns of their spatial configuration and the trade-offs associated with their development. Continued and rapid urbanization, with associated losses in vegetation, highlights the need for a uniting spatial framework to assess the ecological impacts of urbanization. Here, we apply some of the thinking emerging from the agricultural land-sparing debate to urbanization, review the similarities and differences between the two systems and set out a research agenda. 3. Intensification of urban systems to increase housing density leads to buildings being interspersed with small tracts of natural or semi-natural habitat patches (e.g. forest patches, parks). Urban extensification, on the other hand, is characterized by sprawling suburbanization with less concentrated, more distributed green space, often predominantly in the form of backyard or streetscape vegetation. We argue that regional scale analyses are urgently needed to determine which of these patterns of urban growth has a lower overall impact on biodiversity and to explore the geographical and taxonomic variation in the most ecologically appropriate city layout. 4. Synthesis and applications. The spatial pattern of urban development will affect biodiversity conservation within and beyond a city's borders. We chart the early progress of empirical work on the land-sparing debate in an urban context and suggest that to yield development patterns that minimize overall ecological impact, urban planners must work at the scale of at least the entire city rather than on a case-by-case basis. RI Fuller, Richard/B-7971-2008; Lin, Brenda/A-8834-2011 OI Fuller, Richard/0000-0001-9468-9678; Lin, Brenda/0000-0002-6011-9172
WOS:000325079800009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>Mapping transition potential with stakeholder- and policy-driven scenarios in Rotterdam City</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolind.2016.02.028</url>
<snippet>This paper introduces a mapping approach to identify hot- and hard-spots for sustainability transition in cities by analyzing different stakeholder- and policy-driven land-use scenarios in Rotterdam City, the Netherlands. Rotterdams sustainability office initiated a knowledge co-production process in which visions and transition pathways for the sustainable and resilient future of Rotterdam, considering existing challenges and opportunities, were co-created. These scenarios were analyzed using a straightforward scenario approach to spatially identify, map and analyze change. By mapping change, trade-offs and synergies between different land-use options among the scenarios, this study disentangles the complexity of a stakeholder co-production process and is able to discover crucial transition areas. Furthermore, multiple urban ecosystem services were valued for each scenario, and environmental impacts could be detected for all of the different visions. The mapping approach applied is a good method to communicate the consequences of induced land-use change back to stakeholders and decision-makers and thus contributes to the visual loop of real co-design. Identifying the hot-spots of change enables attention to be drawn to the most rewarding areas for transition, and moreover, it shows areas in which different visions are not conflicting but rather cross-benefiting each other. Additionally, hard-spots or areas in which existing visions contradict each other show that careful mediation and the revision of change options might be the way to go. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. OI Larondelle, Neele/0000-0003-2064-1713; Frantzeskaki, Niki/0000-0002-6983-448X
WOS:000388785200057
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="10">
<title>An expanded urban metabolism method: Toward a systems approach for assessing urban energy processes and causes</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.landurbplan.2012.06.006</url>
<snippet>The integrated study of energy and urban systems has recently become a critical component of sustainability research and policy. Increasing urbanization of human societies combined with intense energy demands of modern economies have driven a recognition that sustainable practices require a systems approach to both the study and application of sustainability principles. Urban metabolism has emerged as a leading methodology for quantifying energy consumption and use patterns in urban environments. Though typically applied as a method of accounting for total energy and materials inputs and outputs into cities, its interdisciplinary history and methods allow urban metabolism to be expanded in ways that will allow more comprehensive and integrated assessment of the patterns and processes of urban energy systems. In this article, we review the concept of urban metabolism-including its two typical approaches: mass balance and "emergy" methods-and offer a means to expand urban metabolism into a platform that incorporates socioeconomic analysis, policy analysis, and additional quantitative methodologies (such as life cycle assessment). This expanded urban metabolism framework is more comprehensive analytically and builds upon the documented capacity of traditional urban metabolism to account for total energy and materials flows of cities to provide an integrated platform for analysis of both energy patterns and the causal processes that govern energy in contemporary cities. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000307801400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="11">
<title>Scaling laws of strategic behavior and size heterogeneity in agent dynamics</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.77.036110</url>
<snippet>We consider the financial market as a model system and study empirically how agents strategically adjust the properties of large orders in order to meet their preference and minimize their impact. We quantify this strategic behavior by detecting scaling relations between the variables characterizing the trading activity of different institutions. We also observe power-law distributions in the investment time horizon, in the number of transactions needed to execute a large order, and in the traded value exchanged by large institutions, and we show that heterogeneity of agents is a key ingredient for the emergence of some aggregate properties characterizing this complex system. RI Mantegna, Rosario/H-3652-2014; Lillo, Fabrizio/E-6793-2014 OI Mantegna, Rosario/0000-0003-4177-171X; MORO, ESTEBAN/0000-0003-2894-1024
WOS:000254539900018
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="12">
<title>Allometric scaling, size distribution and pattern formation of natural cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1057/palcomms.2015.17</url>
<snippet>There has been a strong interest in more cogent definitions on economies of scale to reveal general urban growth laws and to develop urban performance metrics. Unstructured data, including satellite images, will provide us with new sources to do so by defining cities as aggregates of human activities. Such a uniform definition on the basis of nighttime light clusters is more consistent and economically meaningful than administrative or official boundaries. In comparison with patterns of city systems found in traditional census data, we examined the allometric scaling, size distribution and fractal geometry of natural cities. It can be concluded from our empirical analysis on regional, country and continental scales that a super-linear scaling between lightness and area with a stable exponent across different low light threshold levels generally holds for natural cities. But Zipf's Law does not always apply over the whole range of lightness thresholds. Furthermore, we build a model based on the simple geometric matching mechanism to reproduce the self-organized formation process of nighttime light patterns. The statistical properties including allometries, size distributions and fractal geometries generated by our model are in good agreement with empirical evidence. These findings have profound implications for understanding the effects of simple aggregation behaviour in primitive stages of city formation and the urbanization process.
WOS:000453320600021
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="13">
<title>Socio-Economic Instability and the Scaling of Energy Use with Population Size</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0130547</url>
<snippet>The size of the human population is relevant to the development of a sustainable world, yet the forces setting growth or declines in the human population are poorly understood. Generally, population growth rates depend on whether new individuals compete for the same energy (leading to Malthusian or density-dependent growth) or help to generate new energy (leading to exponential and super-exponential growth). It has been hypothesized that exponential and super-exponential growth in humans has resulted from carrying capacity, which is in part determined by energy availability, keeping pace with or exceeding the rate of population growth. We evaluated the relationship between energy use and population size for countries with long records of both and the world as a whole to assess whether energy yields are consistent with the idea of an increasing carrying capacity. We find that on average energy use has indeed kept pace with population size over long time periods. We also show, however, that the energy-population scaling exponent plummets during, and its temporal variability increases preceding, periods of social, political, technological, and environmental change. We suggest that efforts to increase the reliability of future energy yields may be essential for stabilizing both population growth and the global socio-economic system. OI Burger, Oskar/0000-0002-7552-5851; DeLong, John/0000-0003-0558-8213
WOS:000356835000125
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="14">
<title>General approaches for assessing urban environmental sustainability</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cosust.2012.09.003</url>
<snippet>Urban environmental sustainability assessment is increasingly a part of urban planning, from the perspective of mitigating local and global impacts and for adapting to regional and global resource constraints and anticipated climate events. We examine general techniques under three categories: consumption-based, metabolism-based and complex systems approaches. We sample recent and salient applications at spatial scales ranging from neighbourhoods to metropolitan regions. The scope and strengths of applications in these categories are complementary especially with regards to the attribution of impact. The first approach assesses environmental sustainability as a function of urban consumption, the second uses a more limited concept of consumption but better represents local and trans-boundary production activity and the third attributes cause and effect through quantifying relationships and feedbacks throughout the urban system. RI Baynes, Timothy/D-4738-2011; Wiedmann, Thomas/C-9158-2011 OI Baynes, Timothy/0000-0001-8416-3365; Wiedmann, Thomas/0000-0002-6395-8887
WOS:000310766600014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="15">
<title>Stocking Up: The Role of Temporal and Spatial R&amp;D Stocks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09654313.2012.745266</url>
<snippet>Endogenous growth models are built around the concept of a knowledge stock. This knowledge stock can also be interpreted as a localized stock that operates at the regional level, as is common in the regional innovation systems literature. We use data from the second, third and fourth Community Innovation Surveys (covering 1994-1996, 1998-2000 and 2002-2004) to measure the build-up of knowledge at a very low regional aggregation level (across streets and hallways) in the Netherlands. In doing so, we account for regional agglomeration effects. We find that such local knowledge stocks have a small influence on innovation and are far outweighed by firm-specific characteristics. OI de Groot, Henri L.F./0000-0002-1794-5321; Smit, Martijn/0000-0001-7050-5934
WOS:000320079700002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="16">
<title>The New Geography of Contemporary Urbanization and the Environment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1146/annurev-environ-100809-125336</url>
<snippet>Contemporary urbanization differs from historical patterns of urban growth in terms of scale, rate, location, form, and function. This review discusses the characteristics of contemporary urbanization and the roles of urban planning, governance, agglomeration, and globalization forces in driving and shaping the relationship between urbanization and the environment. We highlight recent research on urbanization and global change in the context of sustainability as well as opportunities for bundling urban development efforts, climate mitigation, and adaptation strategies to create synergies to transition to sustainability. We conclude with an analysis of global greenhouse gas emissions under different scenarios of future urbanization growth and discuss their implications. RI Seto, Karen/C-2722-2008
WOS:000284721100007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="17">
<title>Complexity in Urban Development and Management</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1530-9290.2009.00123.x</url>
<snippet>Systems dynamics, cellular automata, agent-based modeling, and network analyses have been used in population, land use, and transport planning models. An overview of complex systems science as applied to urban development is presented, and examples are given of where the problems of housing people and anticipating their movements have been addressed with complex approaches, sometimes in concert with deterministic, large-scale urban models. Planning for cities today has additional environmental and social priorities in common with many topics that concern industrial ecology. The research agenda suggested here is that this, too, can be enriched with complex systems thinking and models to complement the often static assessment of environmental performance and better inform decision processes. RI Baynes, Timothy/D-4738-2011 OI Baynes, Timothy/0000-0001-8416-3365
WOS:000265252200006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="18">
<title>Down to Earth: Contextualizing the Anthropocene</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.gloenvcha.2015.11.004</url>
<snippet>The Anthropocene is now being used as a conceptual frame by different communities and in a variety of contexts to understand the evolving human environment relationship. However, as we argue in this paper, the notion of an Anthropos, or humanity, as global, unified geological force threatens to mask the diversity and differences in the actual conditions and impacts of humankind, and does not do justice to the diversity of local and regional contexts. For this reason, we interpret in this article the notion of an Anthropocene in a more context-dependent, localized and social understanding. We do this through illustrating examples from four issue domains, selected for their variation in terms of spatial and temporal scale, systems of governance and functional interdependencies: nitrogen cycle distortion (in particular as it relates to food security); ocean acidification; urbanization; and wildfires. Based on this analysis, we systematically address the consequences of the lens of the Anthropocene for the governance of social-ecological systems, focusing on the multi-level, functional and sectoral organization of governance, and possible redefinitions of governance systems and policy domains. We conclude that the notion of the Anthropocene, once seen in light of social inequalities and regional differences, allows for novel analysis of issue-based problems in the context of a global understanding, in both academic and political terms. This makes it a useful concept to help leverage and (re-)focus our efforts in a more innovative and effective way to transition towards sustainability. (C) 2015 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd. RI van der Hel, Sandra/R-1716-2016; Seto, Karen/C-2722-2008; Chen, Chen-Tung Arthur/C-8901-2011; Biermann, Frank/D-4175-2013; Bai, Xuemei/A-5443-2012 OI van der Hel, Sandra/0000-0001-6552-9616; Biermann, Frank/0000-0002-0292-0703; Bai, Xuemei/0000-0001-6556-8041; Lemos, Maria Carmen/0000-0001-6686-730X
WOS:000381165100032
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="19">
<title>Is there enough fertile soil to feed a planet of growing cities?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2014.10.048</url>
<snippet>We analyze a scaling law for the consumption of agricultural soil by cities. The nonlinear dependence of the size of the city on the number of inhabitants gives rise to an equation for population dynamics. We found the asymptotic limit of the solution for this equation, given by the carrying capacity in terms of number of inhabitants that can be fed. The carrying capacity as a function of the scaling law exponent is computed numerically, showing that the exponent must be very small to ensure a food sustainability. We suggest a bound for the value of this exponent and analyze the reliability of the scaling law for major cities. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000347017300071
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="20">
<title>A population biological approach to the collective dynamics of countries undergoing demographic transition</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jtbi.2010.04.008</url>
<snippet>Birth rates have been declining in higher-income countries since the middle of the 19th century. A growing number of other countries have entered this demographic transition to lower fertility, as socioeconomic development continues. Analyses of this demographic transition vary widely, but most analyze individual populations in isolation from others, and most come from fields outside the biological sciences. Here, we develop a population biological model of population dynamics in higher-income countries. Individual countries evolve through density-regulated growth, where gradual evolution toward higher population densities boosts productivity (and hence socioeconomic growth) through economics of agglomeration and scale, in turn reducing birth rates. The exchange of technology and capital between countries can further boost productivity gains in any given country, thus contributing to its demographic transition. As a result, countries can down-regulate one anothers population growth through mutual improvements in productivity. The model is fitted to time series data on population size, GDP per capita, and birth rates for the United States, the United Kingdom, and France. The metapopulation dynamics are also characterized across a range of parameter values close to the fitted values. This work may help advance population biological approaches to understanding the implications of the fertility demographic transition for modern human populations. This is relevant to developing long-term predictions of the earths total population size, which must be based upon a model that incorporates underlying mechanisms. 
WOS:000279116700008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="21">
<title>Scaling of patenting with urban population size: evidence from global metropolitan areas</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11192-013-0970-3</url>
<snippet>Larger agglomerations of individuals create a social environment can sustain a larger repertoire of intellectual capabilities, thereby facilitating the creation and recombination of ideas, and increasing the likelihood that interactions among individuals will occur through which new ideas are generated and shared. Relatedly, cities have long been the privileged setting for invention and innovation. These two phenomena are brought together in the superlinear scaling relationship whereby urban inventive output (measured through patenting) increases more than proportionally with increasing population size. We revisit the relationship between urban population size and patenting using data for a global set of metropolitan areas in the OECD and show, for the first time, that the superlinear scaling between patenting and population size observed for US metropolitan areas holds for urban areas across a variety of urban and economic systems. In fact the scaling relationships established for the US metropolitan system and for the global metropolitan system are remarkably similar.
WOS:000323437400011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="22">
<title>Sustainability of culture-driven population dynamics</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tpb.2010.01.004</url>
<snippet>We consider models of the interactions between human population dynamics and cultural evolution, asking whether they predict sustainable or unsustainable patterns of growth. Phenomenological models predict either unsustainable population growth or stabilization in the near future. The latter prediction, however, is based on extrapolation of current demographic trends and does not take into account causal processes of demographic and cultural dynamics. Most existing causal models assume (or derive from simplified models of the economy) a positive feedback between cultural evolution and demographic growth, and predict unlimited growth in both culture and population. We augment these models taking into account that: (1) cultural transmission is not perfect, i.e., culture can be lost; (2) culture does not always promote population growth. We show that taking these factors into account can cause radically different model behavior, such as population extinction rather than stability, and extinction rather than growth. We conclude that all models agree that a population capable of maintaining a large amount of culture, including a powerful technology, runs a high risk of being unsustainable. We suggest that future work must address more explicitly both the dynamics of resource consumption and the cultural evolution of beliefs implicated in reproductive behavior (e.g., ideas about the preferred family size) and in resource use (e.g., environmentalist stances). (C) 2010 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved. RI Perc, Matjaz/A-5148-2009 OI Perc, Matjaz/0000-0002-3087-541X; Ghirlanda, Stefano/0000-0002-7270-9612
WOS:000276751300005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="23">
<title>Common Scaling Laws fop City Highway Systems and the Mammalian Neocortex</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cplx.20288</url>
<snippet>
WOS:000273691800002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="24">
<title>Sustainable Development under Population Pressure: Lessons from Developed Land Consumption in the Conterminous US</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0119675</url>
<snippet>Population growth will result in a significant anthropogenic environmental change worldwide through increases in developed land (DL) consumption. DL consumption is an important environmental and socioeconomic process affecting humans and ecosystems. Attention has been given to DL modeling inside highly populated cities. However, modeling DL consumption should expand to non-metropolitan areas where arguably the environmental consequences are more significant. Here, we study all counties within the conterminous U.S. and based on satellite-derived product (National Land Cover Dataset 2001) we calculate the associated DL for each county. By using county population data from the 2000 census we present a comparative study on DL consumption and we propose a model linking population with expected DL consumption. Results indicate distinct geographic patterns of comparatively low and high consuming counties moving from east to west. We also demonstrate that the relationship of DL consumption with population is mostly linear, altering the notion that expected population growth will have lower DL consumption if added in counties with larger population. Added DL consumption is independent of a countys starting population and only dependent on whether the county belongs to a Metropolitan Statistical Area (MSA). In the overlapping MSA and non-MSA population range there is also a constant DL efficiency gain of approximately 20km(2) for a given population for MSA counties which suggests that transitioning from rural to urban counties has significantly higher benefits in lower populations. In addition, we analyze the socioeconomic composition of counties with extremely high or low DL consumption. High DL consumption counties have statistically lower Black/African American population, higher poverty rate and lower income per capita than average in both NMSA and MSA counties. Our analysis offers a baseline to investigate further land consumption strategies in anticipation of growing population pressures. OI Grekousis, George/0000-0003-2837-2335
WOS:000351880000035
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="25">
<title>Advancing understanding of the complex nature of urban systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolind.2016.03.054</url>
<snippet>Cities and urbanized regions are complex, dynamic, and highly integrated systems linking social, ecological, and technical infrastructure domains in ways that create deep challenges for good governance, policymaking, and planning. The combination of impacts from climate change in cities, air pollution, rapid population growth, multiple sources of development pressure and overall urban system complexity make it difficult for decision-makers to develop and guide development trajectories along more livable, equitable, and at the same time, more resilient pathways. Advancing urban sustainability and resilience agendas requires expanding the scope of inter- and trans-disciplinarity approaches, moving beyond the historically separate social-ecological and socio-technical approaches to jointly study social-ecological-technical infrastructure systems in cities. We take urban complexity as a given and suggest that in both research and practice we need to better capture and understand feedbacks, inter-dependencies, and non-linearities which create uncertainties and challenge the efficacy of governance practices to achieve normative goals for society. Here, we explore new methods, tools, and approaches to advance our understanding of urban system complexity through a series of journal special issue articles that examine urban structure-function relationships, urban sustainability transitions, green space availability, social-ecological memory, functional traits, and urban land use scenarios. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. OI Gren, Asa/0000-0002-9021-1033
WOS:000388785200051
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="26">
<title>Rates and patterns of urban expansion in China's 32 major cities over the past three decades</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10980-015-0211-7</url>
<snippet>Rates, patterns, and consequences of urban expansion are drawing increasing attention globally because of their profound impacts on socioeconomics, human life, and the environment. Horizontal comparative studies across multiple cities over large geographic regions are rare. We quantified and compared the magnitude and forms of urban expansion for China's 32 major cities, and examined the spatiotemporal evolution of urban growth and trajectory of patch structure formation. Multi-temporal Landsat data of circa 1978, 1990, 1995, 2000, 2005, and 2010, patch-based analyses, and urban growth metrics were used. These 32 major cities have experienced extensive expansion during the study period. Leapfrogging was the dominant urban expansion form, followed by edge-expansion and infilling in the early time periods. Interestingly, the fractions of infilling, edge-expansion, and leapfrogging has gradually reached a quasi-equilibrium condition with a ratio of 2:4:4 (the number) and 2:5:3 (the area) during recent years. Patch analysis suggested that these cities evolved under a nationally-consistent converged urban patch structure regardless of city size, location, and history. The dynamics of urban growth in China corresponded well with its socioeconomic and political geography and the phased implementation of various regional and national policies. Our results generally supported the continuum of diffusion-coalescence urbanization process and a spatial self-organization of urban land patches during urbanization. More studies are needed to test the generality of urban growth hypothesis and examine the universality of converged urban patch structure across regions and countries and to understand their implications to city organization, metabolism, and evolution.
WOS:000360673200014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="27">
<title>10 Years Later: Revisiting Priorities for Science and Society a Decade After the Millennium Ecosystem Assessment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/bs.aecr.2015.10.005</url>
<snippet>The study of ecological services (ESs) is fast becoming a cornerstone of mainstream ecology, largely because they provide a useful means of linking functioning to societal benefits in complex systems by connecting different organizational levels. In order to identify the main challenges facing current and future ES research, we analyzed the effects of the publication of the Millennium Ecosystem Assessment (MEA, 2005) on different disciplines. Within a set of topics framed around concepts embedded within the MEA, each co-author identified five key research challenges and, where feasible, suggested possible solutions. Concepts included those related to specific service types (i.e. provisioning, supporting, regulating, cultural, aesthetic services) as well as more synthetic issues spanning the natural and social sciences, which often linked a wide range of disciplines, as was the case for the application of network theory. By merging similar responses, and removing some of the narrower suggestions from our sample pool, we distilled the key challenges into a smaller subset. We review some of the historical context to the MEA and identify some of the broader scientific and philosophical issues that still permeate discourse in this field. Finally, we consider where the greatest advances are most likely to be made in the next decade and beyond. RI Mulder, Christian/N-4726-2015; Scherber, Christoph/B-6611-2009; Hines, Jes/L-7668-2016; Vonk, Jan Arie/B-1105-2009; Haughton, Alison/A-7769-2013; PASCUAL, UNAI/B-4766-2012; Cramer, Wolfgang/B-8221-2008; Wood, Stephen/A-1928-2017; Massol, Francois/D-9872-2013; Mancinelli, Giorgio/A-7679-2013 OI Mulder, Christian/0000-0001-5735-6989; Scherber, Christoph/0000-0001-7924-8911; Hines, Jes/0000-0002-9129-5179; Vonk, Jan Arie/0000-0002-8803-1148; Haughton, Alison/0000-0002-2852-5736; PASCUAL, UNAI/0000-0002-5696-236X; Cramer, Wolfgang/0000-0002-9205-5812; Wood, Stephen/0000-0002-9551-8165; Massol, Francois/0000-0002-4098-955X; Mancinelli, Giorgio/0000-0002-5833-7322; Bonkowski, Michael/0000-0003-2656-1183; Penuelas, Josep/0000-0002-7215-0150; Bohan, David/0000-0001-5656-775X; Sutherland, William/0000-0002-6498-0437; Vacher, Corinne/0000-0003-3023-6113; Setala, Heikki Martti/0000-0002-5230-4001; Eisenhauer, Nico/0000-0002-0371-6720
WOS:000376149300002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="28">
<title>Urban high-resolution fossil fuel CO2 emissions quantification and exploration of emission drivers for potential policy applications</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11252-016-0553-1</url>
<snippet>Fossil fuel carbon dioxide (FFCO2) emissions are the largest driver of anthropogenic climate change. Approximately three-quarters of the worlds fossil fuels carbon dioxide emissions are generated in urban areas. We used the Hestia high resolution approach to quantify FFCO2 for Salt Lake County, Utah, USA and demonstrate the importance of high resolution quantification to urban emissions mitigation policymaking. We focus on the residential and onroad sectors across both urbanized and urbanizing parts of the valley. Stochastic Impact by Regression on Population, Affluence, and Technology (STIRPAT) regression models using sociodemographic data at the census block group level shows that population, per capita income, and building age exhibit positive relationships while household size shows a negative relationship with FFCO2 emissions. Compact development shows little effect on FFCO2 emissions in this domain. FFCO2 emissions in high income block groups is twice as sensitive to income than low income block groups. Emissions are four times as sensitive to household size in low-income versus high-income block groups. These results suggest that policy options targeting personal responsibility or knowledge feedback loops may be the most effective strategies. Examples include utility bill performance comparison or publicly available energy maps identifying high-emitting areas. Within the onroad sector, high emissions density (FFCO2/km) is associated with primary roads, while high emissions intensity (FFCO2/VMT) is associated with secondary roads. Opportunities exist for alignment of public transportation extension with remaining high emission road segments, offering a prioritization of new onroad transportation policy in Salt Lake County. OI Buchert, Martin/0000-0001-5974-001X; Rao, Preeti/0000-0002-5549-0583; Song, Yang/0000-0002-7861-2918
WOS:000382670600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="29">
<title>A Network Representation of Raster Land-Cover Patches</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.14358/PERS.76.1.61</url>
<snippet>Network models, based on mathematical graph theory, are used in many fields, from chemistry and biology to ecology and sociology. A nominal-valued land-cover roster can be represented as a network in which patches are nodes connected by links if two patches are adjacent. Built with existing GIS technology, the system is applied to the largest patches of a raster for the Washington, D.C. area in order to provide a data structure that visualizes the gross spatial structure of the roster; provides information about the overall arrangement of the patches and their adjacencies; and generates new metrics about land-cover patterns, connectivity and spatial autocorrelation. The system facilitates the evaluation of land-cover classifications, the measurement of landscape change, comparisons of data from different regions, and the analysis of land/environmental interactions.
WOS:000273774600006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="30">
<title>Research Networks and Inventors' Mobility as Drivers of Innovation: Evidence from Europe</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00343404.2011.618803</url>
<snippet>Miguelez E. and Moreno R. Research networks and inventors mobility as drivers of innovation: evidence from Europe, Regional Studies. This paper investigates the importance of the labour mobility of inventors, as well as the scale, extent and density of their collaborative research networks, for regional innovation outcomes. To do so, a knowledge production function framework at the regional level is used. The empirical approach presented takes full account of spatial interactions by estimating a spatial lag model, together, where necessary, with a spatial error model. In addition, standard errors are calculated using spatial heteroskedasticity and autocorrelation consistent (SHAC) techniques. The results suggest the existence of a robust positive correlation between intra-regional labour mobility and regional innovation, whilst the relationship with networks is less clear. RI Moreno, Rosina/D-4723-2014; Miguelez, Ernest/A-1254-2017 OI Moreno, Rosina/0000-0002-3500-8622; Miguelez, Ernest/0000-0002-8224-6842
WOS:000326562000005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="31">
<title>WHY URBAN GEOCHEMISTRY?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2113/gselements.8.6.417</url>
<snippet>In a very short period of time, the majority of the human population has become urban, and by 2050 two out of every three people in the world will live in cities. Urban areas are extremely important socially, economically, and culturally, but they also have a profound impact on the environment. In that context, this issue of Elements considers the geochemical significance of 21st-century cities and some of the unprecedented challenges they face.
WOS:000313232200004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="32">
<title>Beyond the urban gradient: barriers and opportunities for timely studies of urbanization effects on aquatic ecosystems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1899/08-169.1</url>
<snippet>Many studies have shown that streams degrade in response to urbanization in the watershed. These studies often are based on use of biotic and abiotic variables to measure stream health across a gradient of land cover/land use. The results of these studies can be applied to other urban systems, but often fail to provide a mechanistic understanding of the urban impact, in part, because of the nature of the experimental design. We analyzed the advantages and disadvantages of using environmental gradient studies to further understanding of urban stream systems. We also evaluated alternative experimental design approaches, including best management practice monitoring, long-term watershed studies, paired-watershed studies, and before-after control-impact studies, which could be used to complement the gradient approach. We illustrate these theoretical discussions with an urban paired-watershed case study in the Etowah watershed in northern Georgia. Our goal is to move experimental designs in a direction that will further our mechanistic understanding of the effects of existing urbanization on aquatic ecosystems and will provide opportunities to evaluate stream responses to environmentally sensitive urban land cover. RI Rosemond, Amy/I-2688-2018; Pringle, Catherine/I-1841-2012 OI Rosemond, Amy/0000-0003-4299-9353; Jackson, C. Rhett/0000-0001-6165-3556
WOS:000273886000022
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="33">
<title>Historical Urban Land Use Transformation in Virtual Geo-Library</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi4031500</url>
<snippet>As countries become increasingly urbanized, understanding how urban areas are changing within the landscape becomes increasingly important. Urbanized areas are often the strongest indicators of human interaction with the environment, and understanding how urban areas develop through remotely sensed data allows for more sustainable practices. A Landsat satellite sensor which is a remote sensing platform, with its ability to analyze global data, rapidly present itself as being an invaluable tool for studying the growth of urban areas. In this study, we present the virtual geo-library as the geovisualization tools to provide the analytical studies of the urbanization process in Malang City, East Java, Indonesia, using images derived from Landsat sensor family (1989 to 2014). We provide a dynamic geovisualization through virtual geo-library, where users could understand and get valuable scientific information (e.g., urban area changes and land use transformation in higher land). This system is also equipped with the tools to enable users to create automatic cartographic maps and print the results out as a digital pdf format file. OI Ramdani, Fatwa/0000-0002-8645-354X
WOS:000364411500023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="34">
<title>The study of urban metabolism and its applications to urban planning and design</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2010.10.022</url>
<snippet>Following formative work in the 1970s. disappearance in the 1980s, and reemergence in the 1990s, a chronological review shows that the past decade has witnessed increasing interest in the study of urban metabolism. The review finds that there are two related, non-conflicting, schools of urban metabolism: one following Odum describes metabolism in terms of energy equivalents: while the second more broadly expresses a citys flows of water, materials and nutrients in terms of mass fluxes. Four example applications of urban metabolism studies are discussed: urban sustainability indicators; inputs to urban greenhouse gas emissions calculation; mathematical models of urban metabolism for policy analysis; and as a basis for sustainable urban design. Future directions include fuller integration of social, health and economic indicators into the urban metabolism framework, while tackling the great sustainability challenge of reconstructing cities. (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000292670800002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="35">
<title>What would dense atmospheric observation networks bring to the quantification of city CO2 emissions?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.5194/acp-16-7743-2016</url>
<snippet>Cities currently covering only a very small portion ( &lt; aEuro-3aEuro-&#37;) of the worlds land surface directly release to the atmosphere about 44aEuro-&#37; of global energy-related CO2, but they are associated with 71-76aEuro-&#37; of CO2 emissions from global final energy use. Although many cities have set voluntary climate plans, their CO2 emissions are not evaluated by the monitoring, reporting, and verification (MRV) procedures that play a key role for market- or policy-based mitigation actions. Here we analyze the potential of a monitoring tool that could support the development of such procedures at the city scale. It is based on an atmospheric inversion method that exploits inventory data and continuous atmospheric CO2 concentration measurements from a network of stations within and around cities to estimate city CO2 emissions. This monitoring tool is configured for the quantification of the total and sectoral CO2 emissions in the Paris metropolitan area (similar to aEuro-12 million inhabitants and 11.4aEuro-TgC emitted in 2010) during the month of January 2011. Its performances are evaluated in terms of uncertainty reduction based on observing system simulation experiments (OSSEs). They are analyzed as a function of the number of sampling sites (measuring at 25aEuro-maEuro-a.g.l.) and as a function of the network design. The instruments presently used to measure CO2 concentrations at research stations are expensive (typically similar to aEuro-EURaEuro-50aEuro-k per sensor), which has limited the few current pilot city networks to around 10 sites. Larger theoretical networks are studied here to assess the potential benefit of hypothetical operational lower-cost sensors. The setup of our inversion system is based on a number of diagnostics and assumptions from previous city-scale inversion experiences with real data. We find that, given our assumptions underlying the configuration of the OSSEs, with 10 stations only the uncertainty for the total city CO2 emission during 1 month is significantly reduced by the inversion by similar to aEuro-42aEuro-&#37;. It can be further reduced by extending the network, e.g., from 10 to 70 stations, which is promising for MRV applications in the Paris metropolitan area. With 70 stations, the uncertainties in the inverted emissions are reduced significantly over those obtained using 10 stations: by 32aEuro-&#37; for commercial and residential buildings, by 33aEuro-&#37; for road transport, by 18aEuro-&#37; for the production of energy by power plants, and by 31aEuro-&#37; for total emissions. These results indicate that such a high number of stations would be likely required for the monitoring of sectoral emissions in Paris using this observation-model framework. They demonstrate some high potential that atmospheric inversions can contribute to the monitoring and/or the verification of city CO2 emissions (baseline) and CO2 emission reductions (commitments) and the advantage that could be brought by the current developments of lower-cost medium precision (LCMP) sensors. RI Chevallier, Frederic/E-9608-2016 OI Chevallier, Frederic/0000-0002-4327-3813; Vogel, Felix/0000-0002-2548-3390
WOS:000379417300017
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="36">
<title>Sleepless in Seoul: 'The Ant and the Metrohopper'</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3938/jkps.57.823</url>
<snippet>One of Aesops (La Fontains) famous fables The Ant and the Grasshopper is widely known to give a moral lesson through comparison between the hard working ant and the party-loving grasshopper. Here we show a slightly different version of this fable, namely, "The Ant and the Metrohopper", which describes human mobility patterns in modern urban life. Numerous real transportation networks and the trajectory data have been studied in order to understand mobility patterns. We study trajectories of commuters on the public transportation of Metropolitan Seoul, Korea. Smart cards (Integrated Circuit Cards; ICCs) are used in the public transportation system, which allow collection of transit transaction data, including departure and arrival stations and time. This empirical analysis provides human mobility patterns, which impact traffic forecasting and transportation optimization, as well as urban planning. RI Jung, Woo-Sung/B-1251-2008 OI Jung, Woo-Sung/0000-0001-9590-3859; Choi, Hannah/0000-0002-8192-1121
WOS:000283108900023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="37">
<title>A comparative gradient approach as a tool for understanding and managing urban ecosystems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11252-012-0240-9</url>
<snippet>To meet the grand challenges of the urban century-such as climate change, biodiversity loss, and persistent poverty-urban and ecological theory must contribute to integrated frameworks that treat social and ecological dynamics as interdependent. A socio-ecological framework that encapsulates theory from the social and ecological sciences will improve understanding of metropolitan dynamics and generate science for improved, sustainable management of urban ecosystems. To date, most urban ecological research has focused on single cities. A comparative approach that uses gradients within and between cities is a useful tool for building urban ecological theory. We offer five hypotheses that are testable using a comparative, gradient approach: (i) the current size, configuration, and function of larger metropolitan ecosystems predicts the potential trajectory of smaller urban areas; (ii) timing of growth explains the greatest variance in urban ecosystem structure and function; (iii) form and function of urban ecosystems are converging over time; (iv) urban ecosystems become more segregated and fragmented as populations increase; and (v) larger cities are more innovative than smaller cities in managing urban ecosystems. RI Grimm, Nancy/D-2840-2009; Finch, Deborah/H-2876-2015; Hall, Sharon/K-7893-2012 OI Grimm, Nancy/0000-0001-9374-660X; Finch, Deborah/0000-0001-9118-7381;
WOS:000310586100002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="38">
<title>Race-Differentiated Outcomes in Multiple Special Healthcare Taxing Districts</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.amepre.2009.11.006</url>
<snippet>Background: Communities with locally generated special healthcare taxes have demonstrated a generally favorable association with selected population health status outcomes. Purpose: This research attempted to determine if that positive association with health outcomes is race differentiated. Methods: Florida counties with multiple special taxing districts were grouped and compared against counties that had either no special healthcare taxing authority or had such authority but were inactive (did not tax). Outcomes of interest were five combined groups and eight cause-specific mortality indicators and five categories of hospitalizations from the 6-year period 2000-2005 analyzed in 2007. Standard mortality ratios and standard hospitalization ratios were calculated separately for white and black populations in four age bands. Results: Compared to blacks and whites living in communities without special taxing districts, black residents of communities with such districts had larger reductions in mortality for chronic conditions such as cancers, diabetes, stroke, and pneumonia/influenza. The same holds true for hospitalizations for diabetes, congestive heart failure, hypertension, and asthma. These differences were not found in mortality due to HIV, homicide, or motor vehicle crashes. Some differences by taxing district were also age and race differentiated. Conclusions: In Communities with health-related taxing authorities, reductions in health disparities between whites and blacks can be demonstrated. These differences are not uniform and vary by the specific type of outcome, race, and age. These findings support the need for studies that prospectively determine whether implementing new taxing strategies may help reduce health disparities. (Am J Prev Med 2010;38(3):311-316) (C) 2010 American journal of Preventive Medicine
WOS:000275383100009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="39">
<title>Urban Scaling and the Production Function for Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0058407</url>
<snippet>The factors that account for the differences in the economic productivity of urban areas have remained difficult to measure and identify unambiguously. Here we show that a microscopic derivation of urban scaling relations for economic quantities vs. population, obtained from the consideration of social and infrastructural properties common to all cities, implies an effective model of economic output in the form of a Cobb-Douglas type production function. As a result we derive a new expression for the Total Factor Productivity (TFP) of urban areas, which is the standard measure of economic productivity per unit of aggregate production factors (labor and capital). Using these results we empirically demonstrate that there is a systematic dependence of urban productivity on city population size, resulting from the mismatch between the size dependence of wages and labor, so that in contemporary US cities productivity increases by about 11&#37; with each doubling of their population. Moreover, deviations from the average scale dependence of economic output, capturing the effect of local factors, including history and other local contingencies, also manifest surprising regularities. Although, productivity is maximized by the combination of high wages and low labor input, high productivity cities show invariably high wages and high levels of employment relative to their size expectation. Conversely, low productivity cities show both low wages and employment. These results shed new light on the microscopic processes that underlie urban economic productivity, explain the emergence of effective aggregate urban economic output models in terms of labor and capital inputs and may inform the development of economic theory related to growth. RI Strumsky, Deborah/F-5795-2013
WOS:000317480700005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="40">
<title>Urban policy and governance in a global environment: complex systems, scale mismatches and public participation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cosust.2010.05.008</url>
<snippet>The urbanization process and urban activities generate environmental impacts both within and beyond city boundaries. Urban policy plays an important role in shaping and changing the regional and global linkages of cities. Integrating regional and global environmental concerns into urban policy and management practices remains a challenging issue because of the inherent temporal, spatial and institutional scale mismatch between urban policies and regional and global environmental issues. This paper argues that firstly, urban policy has increasing relevance to regional and global environmental issues, and a systems approach is essential in urban policy making to maximize co-benefit and negotiate trade-offs and secondly, although the current institutional settings in urban policy making are not necessarily best suited for managing these issues, enhanced governance processes such as increased public participation and networking and learning across cities can be effective. RI McAllister, Ryan/A-4866-2008; Bai, Xuemei/A-5443-2012; Beaty, Robert/B-5504-2011; Bai, Xuemei/H-7072-2012; Taylor, Bruce/C-5771-2011 OI McAllister, Ryan/0000-0003-0080-7528; Bai, Xuemei/0000-0001-6556-8041;
WOS:000282613600002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="41">
<title>Metropolitan patenting, inventor agglomeration and social networks: A tale of two effects</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jue.2007.07.005</url>
<snippet>We investigate the separate effects on metropolitan patenting of inventor agglomeration and the structure of social networks linking inventors within and across metropolitan areas in the United States between 1977 and 2002. Using patent data we have been able to assign a metropolitan location to individual inventors, link inventors who have co-authored patents, and characterize the structural features of the networks linking inventors. Our main question concerns the relative importance of salient features of the social networks linking inventors on metropolitan patenting productivity. We find that agglomerative features of metropolitan areas are more important determinants of metropolitan patenting productivity than structural feature of the inventive networks. While the aggregation of isolated inventors correlates positively with patenting productivity, density of connections correlates negatively. (C) 2007 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved. RI Strumsky, Deborah/F-5795-2013
WOS:000255724900009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="42">
<title>A Spatial and Temporal Autocorrelated Growth Model for City Rank-Size Distribution</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0042098009348326</url>
<snippet>Rank-size distribution has been an important tool in characterising and analysing city size distributions across spatial and temporal scales. Zipfs law in city rank-size distribution has been observed in many analyses and is considered an important empirical regularity describing the organisation of cities. Based on analyses of the evolution of cities in Texas from 1850 to 2000, this paper documents spatial and temporal autocorrelation in city population growth rates. A modelling strategy has been developed that accounts for the spatial and temporal autocorrelated growth in Texas cities and is effective in reconstructing the empirical rank-size distribution. This study shows that it is necessary to take into account the interdependence among cities in simulating the city size distribution.
WOS:000273678900005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="43">
<title>The Origins of Scaling in Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.1235823</url>
<snippet>Despite the increasing importance of cities in human societies, our ability to understand them scientifically and manage them in practice has remained limited. The greatest difficulties to any scientific approach to cities have resulted from their many interdependent facets, as social, economic, infrastructural, and spatial complex systems that exist in similar but changing forms over a huge range of scales. Here, I show how all cities may evolve according to a small set of basic principles that operate locally. A theoretical framework was developed to predict the average social, spatial, and infrastructural properties of cities as a set of scaling relations that apply to all urban systems. Confirmation of these predictions was observed for thousands of cities worldwide, from many urban systems at different levels of development. Measures of urban efficiency, capturing the balance between socioeconomic outputs and infrastructural costs, were shown to be independent of city size and might be a useful means to evaluate urban planning strategies.
WOS:000320647000038
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="44">
<title>Is Denser Greener? An Evaluation of Higher Density Development as an Urban Stormwater-Quality Best Management Practice</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1752-1688.2009.00316.x</url>
<snippet>A simple spreadsheet model was used to evaluate potential water quality benefits of high-density development. The question was whether the reduced land consumed by higher density development (vs. standard suburban developments) would offset the worse water quality generated by a greater amount of impervious surface in the smaller area. Total runoff volume and per acre loadings of total phosphorous, total nitrogen, and total suspended solids increased with density as expected, but per capita loadings and runoff decreased markedly with density. For a constant or given population, then, higher density can result in dramatically lower total loadings than more diffuse suburban densities. The model showed that a simple doubling of standard suburban densities [to 8 dwelling units per acre (DUA) from about 3 to 5 DUA] in most cases could do more to reduce contaminant loadings associated with urban growth than many traditional stormwater best management practices (BMPs), and that higher densities such as those associated with transit-oriented development could outperform almost all traditional BMPs, in terms of reduced loadings per a constant population. Because higher density is associated with vibrant urban life, building a better city may be the best BMP to mitigate the water quality damage that will accompany the massive urban growth expected for the next several decades.
WOS:000266336100012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="45">
<title>Increasing the relevance of mathematical approaches to demographic history</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11135-007-9144-9</url>
<snippet>In this short paper we comment on recent efforts at formally modelling the interplay between demography and cultural evolution. We draw attention to the fact that, although these efforts are to be applauded, much work has already been done in this area, and that this work is being ignored. We build a case for tighter collaboration between different social science disciplines concerned with human behaviour and long-term demography, and argue that mathematical models must be paired with empirical data. OI Riede, Felix/0000-0002-4879-7157; Bentley, R. Alexander/0000-0001-9086-2197
WOS:000253202400006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="46">
<title>Ecology in an anthropogenic biosphere</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1890/14-2274.1</url>
<snippet>Humans, unlike any other multicellular species in Earths history, have emerged as a global force that is transforming the ecology of an entire planet. It is no longer possible to understand, predict, or successfully manage ecological pattern, process, or change without understanding why and how humans reshape these over the long term. Here, a general causal theory is presented to explain why human societies gained the capacity to globally alter the patterns, processes, and dynamics of ecology and how these anthropogenic alterations unfold over time and space as societies themselves change over human generational time. Building on existing theories of ecosystem engineering, niche construction, inclusive inheritance, cultural evolution, ultrasociality, and social change, this theory of anthroecological change holds that sociocultural evolution of subsistence regimes based on ecosystem engineering, social specialization, and non-kin exchange, or "sociocultural niche construction," is the main cause of both the long-term upscaling of human societies and their unprecedented transformation of the biosphere. Human sociocultural niche construction can explain, where classic ecological theory cannot, the sustained transformative effects of human societies on biogeography, ecological succession, ecosystem processes, and the ecological patterns and processes of landscapes, biomes, and the biosphere. Anthroecology theory generates empirically testable hypotheses on the forms and trajectories of long-term anthropogenic ecological change that have significant theoretical and practical implications across the subdisciplines of ecology and conservation. Though still at an early stage of development, anthroecology theory aligns with and integrates established theoretical frameworks including social-ecological systems, social metabolism, countryside biogeography, novel ecosystems, and anthromes. The "fluxes of nature" are fast becoming "cultures of nature." To investigate, understand, and address the ultimate causes of anthropogenic ecological change, not just the consequences, human sociocultural processes must become as much a part of ecological theory and practice as biological and geophysical processes are now. Strategies for achieving this goal and for advancing ecological science and conservation in an increasingly anthropogenic biosphere are presented. OI Ellis, Erle/0000-0002-2006-3362
WOS:000358731100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="47">
<title>Discerning Electricity Consumption Patterns from Urban Allometric Scaling</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/COMPENG.2010.29</url>
<snippet>Allometric scaling relations are characteristic of all living organisms. Metabolic and heart rates, lifespan and many other physiological properties vary with body mass in systematic and interrelated ways, which usually take the form of a power law. Scaling laws have been recently observed also in the metabolic rate of a particular kind of living system: the city. Scaling exponents of urban indicators present a remarkable variability, mainly associated with fundamentally different underlying dynamics. In this paper allometric scaling is used to detect dissimilar behaviors in one particularly important urban indicator: electricity consumption. Different scaling relations between electricity consumption and economical and social sectors found in southern Spain region of Andalucia, indicate variability in these sectors basal energy consumption processes. The usefulness of these findings for urban modeling is finally outlined and some practical implications are suggested. RI Valverde, Sergi/J-3275-2012; Rosas, Marti/M-2389-2014 OI Valverde, Sergi/0000-0002-2150-9610; Rosas, Marti/0000-0002-5243-2601
WOS:000278287100011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="48">
<title>A Comprehensive View on Urban Spatial Structure: Urban Density Patterns of German City Regions</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi5060076</url>
<snippet>Urban density must be considered a key concept in the description of a citys urban spatial structure. Countless studies have provided evidence of a close relationship between built density and activity densities, on the one hand, and urban environmental conditions or social practices, on the other hand. However, despite the concepts common use in urban research, urban density is a rather fuzzy and highly complex concept that is accompanied by a confusing variety of indicators and measurement approaches. To date, an internationally-accepted standard for the implementation of density indicators that permits a robust comparison of different countries, regions or cities is widely missing. This paper discusses the analytical opportunities that recent remote sensing data offer in regard to an objective and transparent measurement of built density patterns of city regions. It furthermore clarifies the interrelations between built and activity densities. We apply our approach to four German city regions to demonstrate the analytical capacity of spatially-refined density indicators for the purposes of comparative urban research at a regional scale. In so doing, we contribute to a more encompassing and robust understanding of the urban density concept when analyzing regional morphology. OI Taubenbock, Hannes/0000-0003-4360-9126
WOS:000379861200003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="49">
<title>The Energy for Growing and Maintaining Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s13280-012-0350-x</url>
<snippet>Herein we develop a means to differentiate between the energy required to expand and the energy required to maintain the economies of cities. A nonlinear model is tested against historical data for two cities, Hong Kong and Singapore. A robust fit is obtained for Hong Kong, with energy for maintenance close to that for growth, while Singapore, with a weaker fit, is growth dominated. The findings suggest that decreases in either of the per unit maintenance or growth demands can simultaneously cause gross domestic product (GDP) and total energy use to increase. Furthermore, increasing maintenance demands can significantly limit growth in energy demand and GDP. Thus, the low maintenance demands for Hong Kong, and especially Singapore, imply that, all other things being equal, GDP and energy use of these cities will continue to grow, though Singapores higher energy use for growth means it will require more energy than Hong Kong.
WOS:000313722400005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="50">
<title>Dynamic peer-to-peer competition</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2010.02.032</url>
<snippet>The dynamic behavior of a multiagent system in which the agent size si is variable it is studied along a Lotka-Volterra approach. The agent size has hereby the meaning of the fraction of a given market that an agent is able to capture (market share). A Lotka-Volterra system of equations for prey-predator problems is considered, the competition factor being related to the difference in size between the agents in a one-on-one competition. This mechanism introduces a natural self-organized dynamic competition among agents. In the competition factor, a parameter sigma is introduced for scaling the intensity of agent size similarity, which varies in each iteration cycle. The fixed points of this system are analytically found and their stability analyzed for small systems (with n = 5 agents). We have found that different scenarios are possible, from chaotic to non-chaotic motion with cluster formation as function of the a parameter and depending on the initial conditions imposed to the system. The present contribution aim is to show how a realistic though minimalist nonlinear dynamics model can be used to describe the market competition (companies, brokers, decision makers) among other opinion maker communities. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Caiafa, Cesar/A-6045-2010 OI Caiafa, Cesar/0000-0001-5437-6095
WOS:000277824800016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="51">
<title>More green infrastructure is required to maintain ecosystem services under current trends in land-use change in Europe</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10980-014-0083-2</url>
<snippet>Green infrastructure (GI), a network of nature, semi-natural areas and green space, delivers essential ecosystem services which underpin human well-being and quality of life. Maintaining ecosystem services through the development of GI is therefore increasingly recognized by policies as a strategy to cope with potentially changing conditions in the future. This paper assessed how current trends of land-use change have an impact on the aggregated provision of eight ecosystem services at the regional scale of the European Union, measured by the Total Ecosystem Services Index (TESI8). Moreover, the paper reports how further implementation of GI across Europe can help maintain ecosystem services at baseline levels. Current demographic, economic and agricultural trends, which affect land use, were derived from the so called Reference Scenario. This scenario is established by the European Commission to assess the impact of energy and climate policy up to 2050. Under the Reference Scenario, economic growth, coupled with the total population, stimulates increasing urban and industrial expansion. TESI8 is expected to decrease across Europe between 0 and 5 &#37; by 2020 and between 10 and 15 &#37; by 2050 relative to the base year 2010. Based on regression analysis, we estimated that every additional percent increase of the proportion of artificial land needs to be compensated with an increase of 2.2 &#37; of land that qualifies as green infrastructure in order to maintain ecosystem services at 2010 levels. OI Batista e Silva, Filipe/0000-0002-8752-6464; Jacobs-Crisioni, Chris/0000-0001-6225-4813; Barbosa, Ana/0000-0003-2706-0743; Vandecasteele, Ine/0000-0003-2087-0129; Maes, Joachim/0000-0002-8272-1607
WOS:000350227000011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="52">
<title>Urban Transitions: On Urban Resilience and Human-Dominated Ecosystems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s13280-010-0081-9</url>
<snippet>Urbanization is a global multidimensional process paired with increasing uncertainty due to climate change, migration of people, and changes in the capacity to sustain ecosystem services. This article lays a foundation for discussing transitions in urban governance, which enable cities to navigate change, build capacity to withstand shocks, and use experimentation and innovation in face of uncertainty. Using the three concrete case cities-New Orleans, Cape Town, and Phoenix-the article analyzes thresholds and cross-scale interactions, and expands the scale at which urban resilience has been discussed by integrating the idea from geography that cities form part of "system of cities" (i.e., they cannot be seen as single entities). Based on this, the article argues that urban governance need to harness social networks of urban innovation to sustain ecosystem services, while nurturing discourses that situate the city as part of regional ecosystems. The article broadens the discussion on urban resilience while challenging resilience theory when addressing human-dominated ecosystems. Practical examples of harnessing urban innovation are presented, paired with an agenda for research and policy. OI Elmqvist, Thomas/0000-0002-4617-6197; Ernstson, Henrik/0000-0002-6415-4821
WOS:000283502300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="53">
<title>Rethinking the Theory and Practice of Local Economic Development</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Scholars of urban law and policy tend to assume that local officials can exert some influence over city well-being More specifically, the literature assumes that government policies-either at the federal, state, or local level-can influence local economic growth and decline, the most Important determinants of a citys. health. This connection between policy and local economic outcomes implies a theory of how cities form and grow. however, and legal scholars have not adequately articulated such a theory. This Article argues that we need a better (and more self-conscious) account of city formation and local economic growth. The Article then tests our intuitions about the relationship between policy and economic development by considering a number of explanations for why cities have resurged over the last fifteen to twenty years. Finally, the Article contrasts two economic development policies that have been adopted in New York City one that preceded the recent financial crisis and one that followed it. The Article concludes that we do not know enough to be able to predict how one policy or another will affect city growth and decline.
WOS:000277960400013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="54">
<title>Earth Stewardship: science for action to sustain the human-earth system</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1890/ES11-00166.1</url>
<snippet>Human activities affect Earth's life support systems so profoundly as to threaten many of the ecological services that are essential to society. To address this challenge, a new science agenda is needed that integrates people with the rest of nature to help chart a more sustainable trajectory for the relationship between society and the biosphere. This paper describes Earth Stewardship, an initiative of the Ecological Society of America to provide the scientific basis for actively shaping trajectories of social-ecological change to enhance ecosystem resilience and human well-being. Principles for moving toward these goals include simultaneous attention to multiple scales and issues; consideration of both ecological and socioeconomic consequences; alignment of incentives with stewardship behavior; strengthening peoples' connections to valued places; and using demographic transitions as new opportunities for stewardship. Past experience provides guidelines for fostering Earth Stewardship. Early attention to sustainable pathways before problems emerge generally provides more cost-effective solutions than attempting to remediate entrenched problems. Defining sustainable pathways by assessing tradeoffs among alternative options requires careful attention to fine-scale processes, interactions, and feedbacks and to larger-scale controls and constraints. Many opportunities occur locally, through development of practices that match the properties of resources with the needs of their users. Substantial challenges remain at larger scales, including maintaining the diversity, productive capacity, and resilience of nature, which are essential for long-term human welfare. The knowledge needed to inform stewardship requires an interdisciplinary science that draws on the observations, skills, and creativity of a wide range of natural and social scientists, practitioners, and civil society. New questions and solutions will emerge when these groups work together to formulate the issues, design the research, and co-produce the observations, knowledge, and concepts that form the basis for solutions. The goal of Earth Stewardship is not to protect nature from people; rather it is to protect nature for human welfare. RI Collins, Scott/P-7742-2014 OI Collins, Scott/0000-0002-0193-2892; Duke, Clifford/0000-0002-8041-4267
WOS:000208810900003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="55">
<title>Urban Scaling and Its Deviations: Revealing the Structure of Wealth, Innovation and Crime across Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0013541</url>
<snippet>With urban population increasing dramatically worldwide, cities are playing an increasingly critical role in human societies and the sustainability of the planet. An obstacle to effective policy is the lack of meaningful urban metrics based on a quantitative understanding of cities. Typically, linear per capita indicators are used to characterize and rank cities. However, these implicitly ignore the fundamental role of nonlinear agglomeration integral to the life history of cities. As such, per capita indicators conflate general nonlinear effects, common to all cities, with local dynamics, specific to each city, failing to provide direct measures of the impact of local events and policy. Agglomeration nonlinearities are explicitly manifested by the superlinear power law scaling of most urban socioeconomic indicators with population size, all with similar exponents (similar to 1.15). As a result larger cities are disproportionally the centers of innovation, wealth and crime, all to approximately the same degree. We use these general urban laws to develop new urban metrics that disentangle dynamics at different scales and provide true measures of local urban performance. New rankings of cities and a novel and simpler perspective on urban systems emerge. We find that local urban dynamics display long-term memory, so cities under or outperforming their size expectation maintain such (dis)advantage for decades. Spatiotemporal correlation analyses reveal a novel functional taxonomy of U. S. metropolitan areas that is generally not organized geographically but based instead on common local economic models, innovation strategies and patterns of crime. RI Strumsky, Deborah/F-5795-2013
WOS:000284036800004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="56">
<title>Measuring social dynamics in a massive multiplayer online game</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2010.06.001</url>
<snippet>Quantification of human group-behavior has so far defied an empirical, falsifiable approach. This is due to tremendous difficulties in data acquisition of social systems. Massive multiplayer online games (MMOG) provide a fascinating new way of observing hundreds of thousands of simultaneously socially interacting individuals engaged in virtual economic activities. We have compiled a data set consisting of practically all actions of all players over a period of 3 years from a MMOG played by 300,000 people. This large-scale data set of a socio-economic unit contains all social and economic data from a single and coherent source. Players have to generate a virtual income through economic activities to survive and are typically engaged in a multitude of social activities offered within the game. Our analysis of high-frequency log files focuses on three types of social networks, and tests a series of social-dynamics hypotheses. In particular we study the structure and dynamics of friend-, enemy- and communication networks. We find striking differences in topological structure between positive (friend) and negative (enemy) tie networks. All networks confirm the recently observed phenomenon of network densification. We propose two approximate social laws in communication networks, the first expressing betweenness centrality as the inverse square of the overlap, the second relating communication strength to the cube of the overlap. These empirical laws provide strong quantitative evidence for the Weak ties hypothesis of Granovetter. Further, the analysis of triad significance profiles validates well-established assertions from social balance theory. We find overrepresentation (underrepresentation) of complete (incomplete) triads in networks of positive ties, and vice versa for networks of negative ties. Empirical transition probabilities between triad classes provide evidence for triadic closure with extraordinarily high precision. For the first time we provide empirical results for large-scale networks of negative social ties. Whenever possible we compare our findings with data from non-virtual human groups and provide further evidence that online game communities serve as a valid model for a wide class of human societies. With this setup we demonstrate the feasibility for establishing a socio-economic laboratory which allows to operate at levels of precision approaching those of the natural sciences. All data used in this study is fully anonymized: the authors have the written consent to publish from the legal department of the Medical University of Vienna. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Szell, Michael/H-5269-2011 OI Szell, Michael/0000-0003-3022-2483
WOS:000283402000006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="57">
<title>Positive visions for guiding urban transformations toward sustainable futures</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cosust.2017.04.004</url>
<snippet>Much of the discourse around urban and global futures tends to be dystopian with visions of environmental and societal collapse, and business as usual forecasts that challenge planning and policymaking for more optimistic urban futures. More recently, research and practice demonstrate the role of positives visions that allow exploration of alternative and desirable futures in developing positive plans and delivering desirable outcomes for cities. We review the role of positive visioning and associated future scenarios for transformations that can guide decision-making for plausible, desirable, and sustainable urban futures. We discuss key challenges and tensions in visioning processes and suggest paths forward for positive visioning as a key tool for resilience and sustainability planning and to guide implementation. RI Iwaniec, David/M-7993-2014 OI Iwaniec, David/0000-0002-0410-4152; Bai, Xuemei/0000-0001-6556-8041; McPhearson, Timon/0000-0002-9499-0791
WOS:000416098300006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="58">
<title>Toward a synthetic economic systems modeling tool for sustainable exploitation of ecosystems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.2010.05901.x</url>
<snippet>Environmental resources that underpin the basic human needs of water, energy, and food are predicted to become in such short supply by 2050 that global security and the well-being of millions will be under threat. These natural commodities have been allowed to reach crisis levels of supply because of a failure of economic systems to sustain them. This is largely because there have been no means of integrating their exploitation into any economic model that effectively addresses ecological systemic failures in a way that provides an integrated ecological-economic tool that can monitor and evaluate market and policy targets. We review the reasons for this and recent attempts to address the problem while identifying outstanding issues. The key elements of a policy-oriented economic model that integrates ecosystem processes are described and form the basis of a proposed new synthesis approach. The approach is illustrated by an indicative case study that develops a simple model for rainfed and irrigated food production in the Murray-Darling basin of southeastern Australia.
WOS:000288933600009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="59">
<title>Does Size Matter? Scaling of CO2 Emissions and US Urban Areas</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0064727</url>
<snippet>Urban areas consume more than 66&#37; of the worlds energy and generate more than 70&#37; of global greenhouse gas emissions. With the worlds population expected to reach 10 billion by 2100, nearly 90&#37; of whom will live in urban areas, a critical question for planetary sustainability is how the size of cities affects energy use and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions. Are larger cities more energy and emissions efficient than smaller ones? Do larger cities exhibit gains from economies of scale with regard to emissions? Here we examine the relationship between city size and CO2 emissions for U.S. metropolitan areas using a production accounting allocation of emissions. We find that for the time period of 1999-2008, CO2 emissions scale proportionally with urban population size. Contrary to theoretical expectations, larger cities are not more emissions efficient than smaller ones. RI Seto, Karen/C-2722-2008
WOS:000319961900015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="60">
<title>Spatial and Temporal Dimensions of Urban Expansion in China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.5b00065</url>
<snippet>The scale of urbanization in China during the past three decades is unprecedented in human history, and the processes are poorly understood. Here we present an effort to map the urban land expansion processes of 32 major cities in China from 1978 to 2010 using Landsat satellite data to understand the temporal and spatial characteristics. Results showed that the urban extent of the 32 cities expanded exponentially with very high annual rates varying from 3.2&#37; to 12.8&#37;. Temporal fluctuation in urban expansion rates in these 32 cities was obvious, with unexpected and alarming expansion rates from 2005 to 2010 that drastically exceeded their expectation, which was calculated from. the long-term trend between 1978 and 2005, by 45&#37;. Overall, we found that the growth rates of cities during the entire study period were inversely related to city size, contradicting the theory or Gibrats law, which states that the growth rate is independent of city size. More detailed analysis indicated that city growth in China has transitioned from contradicting to conforming to Gibrats law since 1995. Our study suggests that the urban expansion theory (i.e., Gibrats law) does not fit Chinese expansion consistently over time, and the exact causes are unknown. Exploring the causes in future research will improve our understanding of the theory and, more importantly, understand the feasibility of the theoretical relationship between city size and expansion rate in guiding contemporary urban expansion planning.
WOS:000359891700026
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="61">
<title>Allometric scaling of countries</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2010.06.059</url>
<snippet>As huge complex systems consisting of geographic regions, natural resources, people and economic entities, countries follow the allometric scaling law which is ubiquitous in ecological, and urban systems. We systematically investigated the allometric scaling relationships between a large number of macroscopic properties and geographic (area), demographic (population) and economic (GDP, gross domestic production) sizes of countries respectively. We found that most of the economic, trade, energy consumption, communication related properties have significant super-linear (the exponent is larger than 1) or nearly linear allometric scaling relations with the GDP. Meanwhile, the geographic (arable area, natural resources, etc.), demographic (labor force, military age population, etc.) and transportation-related properties (road length, airports) have significant and sub-linear (the exponent is smaller than 1) allometric scaling relations with area. Several differences of power law relations with respect to the population between countries and cities were pointed out. First, population increases sub-linearly with area in countries. Second, the GDP increases linearly in countries but not super-linearly as in cities. Finally, electricity or oil consumption per capita increases with population faster than cities. Crown Copyright (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Zhang, Jiang/A-3156-2012 OI Yu, Tongkui/0000-0001-7116-182X
WOS:000282241600045
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="62">
<title>Why are large cities faster? Universal scaling and self-similarity in urban organization and dynamics</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjb/e2008-00250-6</url>
<snippet>Cities have existed since the beginning of civilization and have always been intimately connected with humanitys cultural and technological development. Much about the human and social dynamics that takes place is cities is intuitively recognizable across time, space and culture; yet we still do not have a clear cut answer as to why cities exist or to what factors are critical to make them thrive or collapse. Here, we construct an extensive quantitative characterization of the variation of many urban indicators with city size, using large data sets for American, European and Chinese cities. We show that social and economic quantities, characterizing the creation of wealth and new ideas, show increasing returns to population scale, which appear quantitatively as a power law of city size with an exponent beta similar or equal to 1.15 &gt; 1. Concurrently, quantities characterizing material infrastructure typically show economies of scale, namely beta similar or equal to 0.8 &lt; 1. The existence of pervasive scaling relations across city size suggests a universal social dynamics common to all cities within an urban system. We sketch some of their general ingredients, which include the acceleration of social life and a restructuring of individual social networks as cities grow larger. We also build simple dynamical models to show that increasing returns in wealth and innovation can fuel faster than exponential growth, which inexorably lead to crises of urban organization. To avoid them we show that growth may proceed in cycles, separated by major urban adaptations, with the unintended consequence that the duration of such cycles decreases with larger urban population size and is now estimated to be shorter than a human lifetime.
WOS:000257333200002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="63">
<title>Information dynamics shape the sexual networks of Internet-mediated prostitution</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0914080107</url>
<snippet>Like many other social phenomena, prostitution is increasingly coordinated over the Internet. The online behavior affects the offline activity; the reverse is also true. We investigated the reported sexual contacts between 6,624 anonymous escorts and 10,106 sex buyers extracted from an online community from its beginning and six years on. These sexual encounters were also graded and categorized (in terms of the type of sexual activities performed) by the buyers. From the temporal, bipartite network of posts, we found a full feedback loop in which high grades on previous posts affect the future commercial success of the sex worker, and vice versa. We also found a peculiar growth pattern in which the turnover of community members and sex workers causes a sublinear preferential attachment. There is, moreover, a strong geographic influence on network structure-the network is geographically clustered but still close to connected, the contacts consistent with the inverse-square law observed in trading patterns. We also found that the number of sellers scales sublinearly with city size, so this type of prostitution does not, comparatively speaking, benefit much from an increasing concentration of people. RI Holme, Petter/A-7646-2008; Rocha, Luis/D-5333-2011; Liljeros, Fredrik/I-2667-2018 OI Holme, Petter/0000-0003-2156-1096; Liljeros, Fredrik/0000-0001-8642-6624; Correa Rocha, Luis Enrique/0000-0001-9046-8739
WOS:000276159500005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="64">
<title>Towards a comprehensive framework for modeling urban spatial dynamics</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10980-009-9353-9</url>
<snippet>The increasing availability of spatial micro data offers new potential for understanding the micro foundations of urban spatial dynamics. However, because urban systems are complex, induction alone is insufficient. Nonlinearities and path dependence imply that qualitatively new dynamics can emerge due to stochastic shocks or threshold effects. Given the policy needs for managing urban growth and decline and the growing desire for sustainable urban forms, models must be able not only to explain empirical regularities, but also characterize system-level dynamics and assess the plausible range of outcomes under alternative scenarios. Towards this end, we discuss a comprehensive modeling approach that is comprised of bottom-up and top-down models in which both inductive and deductive approaches are used to describe and explain urban spatial dynamics. We propose that this comprehensive modeling approach consists of three iterative tasks: (1) identify empirical regularities in the spatial pattern dynamics of key meso and macro variables; (2) explain these regularities with process-based micro models that link individual behavior to the emergence of meso and macro dynamics; and (3) determine the systems dynamical equations that characterize the relationships between micro processes and meso and macro pattern dynamics. Along the way, we also clarify types of complexity (input and output) and discuss dimensions of complexity (spatial, temporal, and behavioral). While no one to date has achieved this kind of comprehensive modeling, meaningful progress has been made in characterizing and explaining urban spatial dynamics. We highlight examples of this work from the recent literature and conclude with a discussion of key challenges. RI Munroe, Darla/D-2410-2012 OI Munroe, Darla/0000-0002-4175-9406
WOS:000270739000007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="65">
<title>Bigger Is Not Always Better: A Comparative Analysis of Cities and their Air Pollution Impact</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0042098011432557</url>
<snippet>This paper investigates the pressure placed by cities on their environment with respect to urban air pollution. The analysis employs a spatially explicit global dataset of emissions to estimate urban emissions of four pollutants from a sample of 8038 cities world-wide in 2005. A cross-sectional regression analysis is then conducted to examine the association of urban air pollution with socioeconomic and geographical factors. The results confirm that urban pollution is associated primarily, but not exclusively, with demographics. The results suggest that urban pollution is likely to increase with population growth and that economic modernisation is unlikely to provide much relief from the pressures placed by coming population growth. The findings suggest that policy-makers must focus on reducing the emissions intensity of production activities within cities, especially from the energy sector, if they are to avoid rapid growth in urban air pollution in coming decades. OI Sarzynski, Andrea/0000-0001-9941-5764
WOS:000309578200009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="66">
<title>The effectiveness of conservation interventions to overcome the urban-environmental paradox</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/nyas.12752</url>
<snippet>Globally, urbanization is rapidly growing cities and towns at a historically unprecedented rate, and this rapid urban growth is influencing many facets of the environment. This paper reviews the effectiveness of conservation interventions that are designed to increase urban sustainability. It presents evidence for an apparent urban-environmental paradox: while the process of urban growth converts natural habitat to other land covers and degrades natural resources and ecosystem function, the increase in human population can increase demand for natural resources and ecosystem services. The fundamental problem that many conservation interventions try to address is that most facets of the environment are common or public goods, and are hence undervalued in decision making (market failure). The paper presents a threefold classification of conservation interventions in cities: conservation in the city (protecting biodiversity), conservation by the city (reducing per capita resource and energy use), and conservation for cities (projects that maintain or enhance ecosystem services). It ends by discussing methods for spatially targeting conservation interventions of all three types and for quantifying the effectiveness of interventions retrospectively. OI McDonald, Robert/0000-0002-7273-6549
WOS:000369996800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="67">
<title>On the confluence of city living, energy saving behaviours and direct residential energy consumption</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.envsci.2016.07.003</url>
<snippet>The purpose of this study is to shed light on the connection between income, dwelling type, tenure type and city living, in terms of both a households energy saving behaviours and direct residential energy consumption. This study employs data from the Household Energy Consumption Survey, Australia. Using a seemingly unrelated regression (SUR) system of equations the results reveal some key mechanisms which may allow householders to realise lower levels of energy consumption and hence lower carbon emissions. The results indicate that there are characteristics unique to living in a city that are linked to higher levels of direct residential energy consumption. On a number of measures (e.g. household income, tenure type and dwelling type), the results point to a lower likelihood of engaging in energy saving behaviours in cities. Also, depending on the number of energy saving behaviours, these actions have the potential to more than offset higher direct residential energy consumption of householders residing in separate houses. Coupled with these findings renters, a more vulnerable social group, are found to be significantly disadvantaged, suffering from a much lower adaptive capacity. Specifically, householders who rent their home are 77&#37; less likely to have solar electricity. A result which may reflect differences in access to opportunity. Further, householders who rent are less likely to engage in energy saving actions. A finding which may reflect difference in ontological security and the greater psychological burden associated with undertaking energy saving behaviours (a barrier) borne by renters not shared with home owners. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. RI Poruschi, Lavinia/M-5115-2017 OI Poruschi, Lavinia/0000-0002-5109-9202; Ambrey, Christopher/0000-0002-3790-7509
WOS:000389089300036
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="68">
<title>Advancing Urban Ecology toward a Science of Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/biosci/biw002</url>
<snippet>Urban ecology is a field encompassing multiple disciplines and practical applications and has grown rapidly. However, the field is heterogeneous as a global inquiry with multiple theoretical and conceptual frameworks, variable research approaches, and a lack of coordination among multiple schools of thought and research foci. Here, we present an international consensus on how urban ecology can advance along multiple research directions. There is potential for the field to mature as a holistic, integrated science of urban systems. Such an integrated science could better inform decisionmakers who need increased understanding of complex relationships among social, ecological, economic, and built infrastructure systems. To advance the field requires conceptual synthesis, knowledge and data sharing; cross-city comparative research, new intellectual networks, and engagement with additional disciplines. We consider challenges and opportunities for understanding dynamics of urban systems. We suggest pathways for advancing urban ecology research to support the goals of improving urban sustainability and resilience, conserving urban biodiversity, and promoting human well-being on an urbanizing planet. RI Grimm, Nancy/D-2840-2009; Qureshi, Salman/A-4355-2009 OI Grimm, Nancy/0000-0001-9374-660X; Elmqvist, Thomas/0000-0002-4617-6197
WOS:000372045600007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="69">
<title>Emerging megaregions: A new spatial scale to explore urban sustainability</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.landusepol.2013.04.008</url>
<snippet>This paper aims to better understand the environmental implications of a new economic unit of analysis consisting of networks of cities called megaregions. We have tested the working hypothesis according to which those regions (European NUTS3) belonging to a megaregion present benefits of economic productivity (growth of GDP per capita) compared to regions that have not been incorporated into a megaregion or have done so recently. A multiple linear regression analysis has established significant relationships between economic, urban and ecological variables: the formation of networks of cities enables economies to concentrate knowledge, achieve greater efficiency in resource consumption (energy), higher productivity (GDP) and lower entropy (less CO2 emissions, better functional structure of the landscape). This pattern of relationships appears both statistically robust and sensitive at the time of incorporation of the European regions (NUTS3) into megaregions. This work contributes to the debate on the essential properties of a regional economy optimizing environmental performance at the level of the megaregion. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. RI Domene, Elena/H-5907-2015; Marull, Joan/O-8875-2014; Trullen, Joan/H-7581-2015; Galletto, Vittorio/H-5939-2015 OI Marull, Joan/0000-0002-7793-4165; Galletto, Vittorio/0000-0003-1709-8000
WOS:000320971800036
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
