<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Large cities get more for less: Water footprint efficiency across the US</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0202301</url>
<snippet>Many urban indicators and functional citywide properties have been shown to scale with population due to agglomeration effects. We hypothesize that scaling relations may also exist for water-related urban indicators such as the water footprint. The water footprint is an indicator of water use that measures humans appropriation of freshwater resources. We analyze the scaling of the water footprint for 65 mid- to large-sized US cities using both empirical estimates and a social interaction network model of city functioning. The network model is used to explain the presence of any scaling exponent in the empirical estimates of the urban water footprint by linking to previous theories of urban scaling. We find that the urban water footprint tends to approximately show sublinear scaling behavior with both population and gross domestic product. Thus, large cities tend to be more water footprint efficient and productive than mid-sized cities, where efficiency and productivity are quantified, in a broad sense, as deviations from a linear scaling exponent. We find the sublinear scaling may be linked to changes in urban economic structure with city size, which lead to large cities shifting water intensive economic activities to less populated regions. In addition, we find that green water contributes to the scaling both positively by transferring the dependence of food consumption on population into the water footprint and negatively by increasing heterogeneity. Overall, the proposed scaling relations allow for the comparison of water footprint efficiency and productivity of cities. Comparing these properties and identifying deviations from the expected behavior has implications for water resources and urban sustainability. OI Grady, Caitlin/0000-0002-9151-6664
WOS:000442202100024
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>Constitutive Explanations as a Methodological Framework for Integrating Thermodynamics and Economics</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/e18010018</url>
<snippet>The common approach to integrating thermodynamics and economics is subsuming thermodynamic aspects among the set of constraints under which economic activity takes place. The causal link between energy and growth is investigated via aggregate econometric analysis. This paper discusses methodological issues of aggregate analysis and proposes an alternative framework based on recent developments in philosophy of science, in particular of the life sciences. Constitutive explanations eschew the covering law approach to scientific explanation and concentrate on the identification of multi-level architectures of causal mechanisms that generate phenomena. This methodology has been productively employed to organize cross-disciplinary research, and I suggest that it can also provide a framework for integrating thermodynamics and economics, since this also requires the combination of several scientific disciplines. I present the example of the rebound effect as a kind of constitutive explanation and put it in the context of urbanization as a complex mechanism that is the defining feature of economic growth in physical terms. OI Herrmann-Pillath, Carsten/0000-0001-6078-0078
WOS:000369488800005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>URBAN STUDIES Diverse cities, successful cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41562-016-0022</url>
<snippet>
WOS:000418775900016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>The scaling of human interactions with city size</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2013.0789</url>
<snippet>The size of cities is known to play a fundamental role in social and economic life. Yet, its relation to the structure of the underlying network of human interactions has not been investigated empirically in detail. In this paper, we map society-wide communication networks to the urban areas of two European countries. We show that both the total number of contacts and the total communication activity grow superlinearly with city population size, according to well-defined scaling relations and resulting from a multiplicative increase that affects most citizens. Perhaps surprisingly, however, the probability that an individuals contacts are also connected with each other remains largely unaffected. These empirical results predict a systematic and scale-invariant acceleration of interaction-based spreading phenomena as cities get bigger, which is numerically confirmed by applying epidemiological models to the studied networks. Our findings should provide a microscopic basis towards understanding the superlinear increase of different socioeconomic quantities with city size, that applies to almost all urban systems and includes, for instance, the creation of new inventions or the prevalence of certain contagious diseases. OI grauwin, sebastian/0000-0002-2674-6498
WOS:000338519300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>A unified theory of urban living</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/467912a</url>
<snippet>
WOS:000283254700015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>Are there higher pedestrian fatalities in larger cities?: A scaling analysis of 115 to 161 largest cities in the United States</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15389588.2016.1162904</url>
<snippet>Objective: In 2012, 4,743 pedestrians were killed in the United States, representing 14&#37; of total traffic fatalities. The number of pedestrians injured was higher at 76,000. Therefore, 36 out of 52 of the largest cities in the United States have adopted a citywide target of reducing pedestrian fatalities. The number of cities adopting the reduction goal during 2011 and 2012 increased rapidly with 8 more cities. We examined the scaling relationship of pedestrian fatality counts as a function of the population size of 115 to 161 large U.S. cities during the period of 1994 to 2011. We also examined the scaling relationship of nonpedestrian and total traffic fatality counts as a function of the population size.Methods: For the data source of fatality measures we used Traffic Safety Facts Fatality Analysis Reporting System/General Estimates System annual reports published each year from 1994 to 2011 by the NHTSA. Using the data source we conducted both annual cross-sectional and panel data bivariate and multivariate regression models. In the construction of the estimated functional relationship between traffic fatality measures and various factors, we used the simple power function for urban scaling used by Bettencourt etal. (2007, 2010) and the refined STIRPAT (stochastic impacts by regression on population, affluence, and technology) model used in Dietz and Rosa (1994, 1997) and York etal. (2003).Results: We found that the scaling relationship display diseconomies of scale or sublinear for pedestrian fatalities. However, the relationship displays a superlinear relationship in case of nonpedestrian fatalities. The scaling relationship for total traffic fatality counts display a nearly linear pattern. When the relationship was examined by the 4 subgroups of cities with different population sizes, the most pronounced sublinear scaling relationships for all 3 types of fatality counts was discovered for the subgroup of megacities with a population of more than 1 million.Conclusions: The scaling patterns of traffic fatalities of subgroups of cities depend on population sizes of the cities in subgroups. In particular, 9 megacities with populations of more than 1 million are significantly different from the remaining cities and should be viewed as a totally separate group. Thus, analysis of the patterns of traffic fatalities needs to be conducted within the group of megacities separately from the other cities with smaller population sizes for devising prevention policies to reduce traffic fatalities in both megacities and smaller cities.
WOS:000384322100010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>Standardized Analysis of Urban Form</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Despite the availability of detailed data for describing cities, there is a shortage of tools that enable standardized analyses of urban areas, and the associated resource consumption. The objective of this research is to contribute to the development of a standardized method for analysis, so that material and energy consumption can be quantified. Analyzing the resource consumption of the built environment is particularly relevant in cities that are rapidly growing, as short-term planning decisions will have long-term consequences for both the quality of life of the inhabitants, and the future energy and material use of the urban area.
WOS:000297353100077
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>High Modularity Creates Scaling Laws</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-27236-0</url>
<snippet>Scaling laws have been observed in many natural and engineered systems. Their existence can give useful information about the growth or decay of one quantitative feature in terms of another. For example, in the field of city analytics, it is has been fruitful to compare some urban attribute, such as energy usage or wealth creation, with population size. In this work, we use network science and dynamical systems perspectives to explain that the observed scaling laws, and power laws in particular, arise naturally when some feature of a complex system is measured in terms of the system size. Our analysis is based on two key assumptions that may be posed in graph theoretical terms. We assume (a) that the large interconnection network has a well-defined set of communities and (b) that the attribute under study satisfies a natural continuity-type property. We conclude that precise mechanistic laws are not required in order to explain power law effects in complex systems-very generic network-based rules can reproduce the behaviors observed in practice. We illustrate our results using Twitter interaction between accounts geolocated to the city of Bristol, UK.
WOS:000436396600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>THE USES OF BIG DATA IN CITIES</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1089/big.2013.0042</url>
<snippet>There is much enthusiasm currently about the possibilities created by new and more extensive sources of data to better understand and manage cities. Here, I explore how big data can be useful in urban planning by formalizing the planning process as a general computational problem. I show that, under general conditions, new sources of data coordinated with urban policy can be applied following fundamental principles of engineering to achieve new solutions to important age-old urban problems. I also show that comprehensive urban planning is computationally intractable (i.e., practically impossible) in large cities, regardless of the amounts of data available. This dilemma between the need for planning and coordination and its impossibility in detail is resolved by the recognition that cities are first and foremost self-organizing social networks embedded in space and enabled by urban infrastructure and services. As such, the primary role of big data in cities is to facilitate information flows and mechanisms of learning and coordination by heterogeneous individuals. However, processes of self-organization in cities, as well as of service improvement and expansion, must rely on general principles that enforce necessary conditions for cities to operate and evolve. Such ideas are the core of a developing scientific theory of cities, which is itself enabled by the growing availability of quantitative data on thousands of cities worldwide, across different geographies and levels of development. These three uses of data and information technologies in cities constitute then the necessary pillars for more successful urban policy and management that encourages, and does not stifle, the fundamental role of cities as engines of development and innovation in human societies.
WOS:000209646400005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="10">
<title>Allometric scaling, size distribution and pattern formation of natural cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1057/palcomms.2015.17</url>
<snippet>There has been a strong interest in more cogent definitions on economies of scale to reveal general urban growth laws and to develop urban performance metrics. Unstructured data, including satellite images, will provide us with new sources to do so by defining cities as aggregates of human activities. Such a uniform definition on the basis of nighttime light clusters is more consistent and economically meaningful than administrative or official boundaries. In comparison with patterns of city systems found in traditional census data, we examined the allometric scaling, size distribution and fractal geometry of natural cities. It can be concluded from our empirical analysis on regional, country and continental scales that a super-linear scaling between lightness and area with a stable exponent across different low light threshold levels generally holds for natural cities. But Zipf's Law does not always apply over the whole range of lightness thresholds. Furthermore, we build a model based on the simple geometric matching mechanism to reproduce the self-organized formation process of nighttime light patterns. The statistical properties including allometries, size distributions and fractal geometries generated by our model are in good agreement with empirical evidence. These findings have profound implications for understanding the effects of simple aggregation behaviour in primitive stages of city formation and the urbanization process.
WOS:000453320600021
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="11">
<title>Characterisation and comparison of spatial patterns in urban systems: A case study of US cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jocs.2017.12.001</url>
<snippet>Understanding the morphology of an urban system is an important step towards unveiling the dynamical processes of its growth and development, which can be achieved through a study of its transportation system. Without doubt, transportation is the foundation of every urban system, and it is a crucial component that enables diverse social and economic functions within a city. In this paper, we studied the spatial pattern of 53 cities in the U.S. by analysing its distribution of public transport points, using a method based upon clusters of percolation known in statistical physics. Our analysis revealed that different spatial distributions of points can generally be classified into four groups with distinctive features: clustered, dispersed, or regularly distributed. From visual inspection, we observed that cities with regularly distributed patterns do not have apparent centre. This is in contrast to the other two types where monocentric (or star-node structure) can be clearly observed. In particular, our results provide quantitative evidence on the existence of two different forms of urban system: well-planned and organically grown. In addition, we had also investigated into the spatial distribution of another important urban entity the amenities, and found that it possessed universal properties regardless of the citys spatial pattern type. This result has an important implication: urban dynamics cannot be controlled at the local scale even though regulation has been meted out at the scale of the entire urban system. Furthermore, interesting relationships between the distribution of amenities within the city and its spatial pattern are detailed in the paper. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. OI Huynh, Nguyen/0000-0002-8432-7435
WOS:000426412200004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="12">
<title>Growth Patterns and Scaling Laws Governing AIDS Epidemic in Brazilian Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0111015</url>
<snippet>Brazil holds approximately 1/3 of population living infected with AIDS (acquired immunodeficiency syndrome) in Central and South Americas, and it was also the first developing country to implement a large-scale control and intervention program against AIDS epidemic. In this scenario, we investigate the temporal evolution and current status of the AIDS epidemic in Brazil. Specifically, we analyze records of annual absolute frequency of cases for more than 5000 cities for the first 33 years of the infection in Brazil. We found that (i) the annual absolute frequencies exhibit a logistic-type growth with an exponential regime in the first few years of the AIDS spreading; (ii) the actual reproduction number decaying as a power law; (iii) the distribution of the annual absolute frequencies among cities decays with a power law behavior; (iv) the annual absolute frequencies and the number of inhabitants have an allometric relationship; (v) the temporal evolution of the annual absolute frequencies have different profile depending on the average annual absolute frequencies in the cities. These findings yield a general quantitative description of the AIDS infection dynamics in Brazil since the beginning. They also provide clues about the effectiveness of treatment and control programs against the infection, that has had a different impact depending on the number of inhabitants of cities. In this framework, our results give insights into the overall dynamics of AIDS epidemic, which may contribute to select empirically accurate models. RI Antonio, Fernando/D-3024-2016 OI Antonio, Fernando/0000-0001-6931-3046
WOS:000343662800079
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="13">
<title>Competitive dynamics between criminals and law enforcement explains the super-linear scaling of crime in cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1057/palcomms.2015.22</url>
<snippet>While cities have been the engine for innovation and growth for many millennia, they have also endured disproportionately more crime than smaller cities. Similarly to other urban sociological quantities, such as income, gross domestic product (GDP) and number of granted patents, it has been observed that crime scales super-linearly with city size. The default assumption is that super-linear scaling of crime, like other urban attributes, derives from agglomerative effects (that is, increasing returns from potentially more productive connections among criminals). However, crime initiation appears to be generated linearly with the population of a city, and the number of law enforcement officials scales sublinearly with city population. We hypothesize that the observed scaling exponent for net crime in a city is the result of competing dynamics between criminals and law enforcement, each with different scaling exponents, and where criminals win in the numbers game. We propose a simple dynamical model able to accommodate these empirical observations, as well as the potential multiple scaling regimes emerging from the competitive dynamics between crime and law enforcement. Our model is also general enough to be able to correctly account for crime in universities, where university crime does not scale super-linearly, but linearly with enrolment size.
WOS:000453320600026
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="14">
<title>Unveiling patterns of international communities in a global city using mobile phone data</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjds/s13688-015-0041-5</url>
<snippet>We analyse a large mobile phone activity dataset provided by Telecom Italia for the Telecom Big Data Challenge contest. The dataset reports the international country codes of every call/SMS made and received by mobile phone users in Milan, Italy, between November and December 2013, with a spatial resolution of about 200 meters. We first show that the observed spatial distribution of international codes well matches the distribution of international communities reported by official statistics, confirming the value of mobile phone data for demographic research. Next, we define an entropy function to measure the heterogeneity of the international phone activity in space and time. By comparing the entropy function to empirical data, we show that it can be used to identify the citys hotspots, defined by the presence of points of interests. Eventually, we use the entropy function to characterize the spatial distribution of international communities in the city. Adopting a topological data analysis approach, we find that international mobile phone users exhibit some robust clustering patterns that correlate with basic socio-economic variables. Our results suggest that mobile phone records can be used in conjunction with topological data analysis tools to study the geography of migrant communities in a global city. RI Tizzoni, Michele/H-6442-2016 OI Tizzoni, Michele/0000-0001-7246-2341; Petri, Giovanni/0000-0003-1847-5031
WOS:000368069900003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="15">
<title>Human diffusion and city influence</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2015.0473</url>
<snippet>Cities are characterized by concentrating population, economic activity and services. However, not all cities are equal and a natural hierarchy at local, regional or global scales spontaneously emerges. In this work, we introduce a method to quantify city influence using geolocated tweets to characterize human mobility. Rome and Paris appear consistently as the cities attracting most diverse visitors. The ratio between locals and non-local visitors turns out to be fundamental for a city to truly be global. Focusing only on urban residents mobility flows, a city-to-city network can be constructed. This network allows us to analyse centrality measures at different scales. New York and London play a central role on the global scale, while urban rankings suffer substantial changes if the focus is set at a regional level. RI Ramasco, Jose J/F-2860-2010; Goncalves, Bruno/A-8541-2009 OI Ramasco, Jose J/0000-0003-2499-6095; Goncalves, Bruno/0000-0001-5644-3749
WOS:000361084200010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="16">
<title>A population biological approach to the collective dynamics of countries undergoing demographic transition</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jtbi.2010.04.008</url>
<snippet>Birth rates have been declining in higher-income countries since the middle of the 19th century. A growing number of other countries have entered this demographic transition to lower fertility, as socioeconomic development continues. Analyses of this demographic transition vary widely, but most analyze individual populations in isolation from others, and most come from fields outside the biological sciences. Here, we develop a population biological model of population dynamics in higher-income countries. Individual countries evolve through density-regulated growth, where gradual evolution toward higher population densities boosts productivity (and hence socioeconomic growth) through economics of agglomeration and scale, in turn reducing birth rates. The exchange of technology and capital between countries can further boost productivity gains in any given country, thus contributing to its demographic transition. As a result, countries can down-regulate one anothers population growth through mutual improvements in productivity. The model is fitted to time series data on population size, GDP per capita, and birth rates for the United States, the United Kingdom, and France. The metapopulation dynamics are also characterized across a range of parameter values close to the fitted values. This work may help advance population biological approaches to understanding the implications of the fertility demographic transition for modern human populations. This is relevant to developing long-term predictions of the earths total population size, which must be based upon a model that incorporates underlying mechanisms. 
WOS:000279116700008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="17">
<title>Spatial Data Analysis of Complex Urban Systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Cities are complex systems that are constantly evolving to better allow people to connect with one another. Moreover, and similar to countless natural phenomena, cities exhibit inherent orders that can be captured and expressed through complex analyses of their components. Using a variety of large datasets, this work offers a ring-buffer approach to analyze the spatial characteristics of four components of Chicago urban system, namely: roads, intersections, buildings, and population+ employment. The complex nature of these four components manifests itself in power-law relationships, represented by their fractal dimensions. Results show that road length and number of intersections, and to a larger degree, population+ employment count and building gross floor area exhibit significantly similar properties. The proposed method could further be used to analyze large demographic, socio-economic, and other geospatial datasets with the aim to study their impacts on relevant urban systems characteristics, including mobility, connectivity, and accessibility to name a few.
WOS:000380462900202
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="18">
<title>Urban scaling in Europe</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2016.0005</url>
<snippet>Over the last few decades, in disciplines as diverse as economics, geography and complex systems, a perspective has arisen proposing that many properties of cities are quantitatively predictable due to agglomeration or scaling effects. Using new harmonized definitions for functional urban areas, we examine to what extent these ideas apply to European cities. We show that while most large urban systems in Western Europe (France, Germany, Italy, Spain, UK) approximately agree with theoretical expectations, the small number of cities in each nation and their natural variability preclude drawing strong conclusions. We demonstrate how this problem can be overcome so that cities from different urban systems can be pooled together to construct larger datasets. This leads to a simple statistical procedure to identify urban scaling relations, which then clearly emerge as a property of European cities. We compare the predictions of urban scaling to Zipfs law for the size distribution of cities and show that while the former holds well the latter is a poor descriptor of European cities. We conclude with scenarios for the size and properties of future pan-European megacities and their implications for the economic productivity, technological sophistication and regional inequalities of an integrated European urban system.
WOS:000374960100009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="19">
<title>Constrained pathways to a creative urban economy</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0042098015616892</url>
<snippet>Creative (knowledge-intensive) occupations are now widely seen as a basis for urban economic prosperity. Yet the transitional pathways from a citys current economy to a more creative economy are often difficult to discern or to navigate. Here we use a network perspective of occupational interdependencies to address questions of urban transitions to a creative economy. This perspective allows us to assess alternative pathways and to compare cities with regard to their progress along these pathways. We find that US urban areas follow a general trajectory towards a creative economy that requires them to increasingly specialise, not only in creative occupations, but also in non-creative ones - presumably because certain non-creative occupations complement the tasks performed by related creative occupations. This creates a pull towards non-creative occupations that becomes ever stronger as a city moves more towards a creative economy. All in all, cities with the most creative economies must undergo an overall diversification of specialised occupations, with a greater diversification rate for creative occupations, and maintain those creative specialisations despite the pull towards a non-creative economy.
WOS:000387499700005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="20">
<title>On Singularities and Black Holes in Combination-Driven Models of Technological Innovation Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0146180</url>
<snippet>It has been suggested that innovations occur mainly by combination: the more inventions accumulate, the higher the probability that new inventions are obtained from previous designs. Additionally, it has been conjectured that the combinatorial nature of innovations naturally leads to a singularity: at some finite time, the number of innovations should diverge. Although these ideas are certainly appealing, no general models have been yet developed to test the conditions under which combinatorial technology should become explosive. Here we present a generalised model of technological evolution that takes into account two major properties: the number of previous technologies needed to create a novel one and how rapidly technology ages. Two different models of combinatorial growth are considered, involving different forms of ageing. When long-range memory is used and thus old inventions are available for novel innovations, singularities can emerge under some conditions with two phases separated by a critical boundary. If the ageing has a characteristic time scale, it is shown that no singularities will be observed. Instead, a "black hole" of old innovations appears and expands in time, making the rate of invention creation slow down into a linear regime. RI Sole, Ricard/I-3379-2015
WOS:000369528400004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="21">
<title>Sustainable Development under Population Pressure: Lessons from Developed Land Consumption in the Conterminous US</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0119675</url>
<snippet>Population growth will result in a significant anthropogenic environmental change worldwide through increases in developed land (DL) consumption. DL consumption is an important environmental and socioeconomic process affecting humans and ecosystems. Attention has been given to DL modeling inside highly populated cities. However, modeling DL consumption should expand to non-metropolitan areas where arguably the environmental consequences are more significant. Here, we study all counties within the conterminous U.S. and based on satellite-derived product (National Land Cover Dataset 2001) we calculate the associated DL for each county. By using county population data from the 2000 census we present a comparative study on DL consumption and we propose a model linking population with expected DL consumption. Results indicate distinct geographic patterns of comparatively low and high consuming counties moving from east to west. We also demonstrate that the relationship of DL consumption with population is mostly linear, altering the notion that expected population growth will have lower DL consumption if added in counties with larger population. Added DL consumption is independent of a countys starting population and only dependent on whether the county belongs to a Metropolitan Statistical Area (MSA). In the overlapping MSA and non-MSA population range there is also a constant DL efficiency gain of approximately 20km(2) for a given population for MSA counties which suggests that transitioning from rural to urban counties has significantly higher benefits in lower populations. In addition, we analyze the socioeconomic composition of counties with extremely high or low DL consumption. High DL consumption counties have statistically lower Black/African American population, higher poverty rate and lower income per capita than average in both NMSA and MSA counties. Our analysis offers a baseline to investigate further land consumption strategies in anticipation of growing population pressures. OI Grekousis, George/0000-0003-2837-2335
WOS:000351880000035
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="22">
<title>Network Centrality of Metro Systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0040575</url>
<snippet>Whilst being hailed as the remedy to the worlds ills, cities will need to adapt in the 21st century. In particular, the role of public transport is likely to increase significantly, and new methods and technics to better plan transit systems are in dire need. This paper examines one fundamental aspect of transit: network centrality. By applying the notion of betweenness centrality to 28 worldwide metro systems, the main goal of this paper is to study the emergence of global trends in the evolution of centrality with network size and examine several individual systems in more detail. Betweenness was notably found to consistently become more evenly distributed with size (i.e. no "winner takes all") unlike other complex network properties. Two distinct regimes were also observed that are representative of their structure. Moreover, the share of betweenness was found to decrease in a power law with size (with exponent 1 for the average node), but the share of most central nodes decreases much slower than least central nodes (0.87 vs. 2.48). Finally the betweenness of individual stations in several systems were examined, which can be useful to locate stations where passengers can be redistributed to relieve pressure from overcrowded stations. Overall, this study offers significant insights that can help planners in their task to design the systems of tomorrow, and similar undertakings can easily be imagined to other urban infrastructure systems (e.g., electricity grid, water/wastewater system, etc.) to develop more sustainable cities.
WOS:000306461800108
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="23">
<title>Simple spatial scaling rules behind complex cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41467-017-01882-w</url>
<snippet>Although most of wealth and innovation have been the result of human interaction and cooperation, we are not yet able to quantitatively predict the spatial distributions of three main elements of cities: population, roads, and socioeconomic interactions. By a simple model mainly based on spatial attraction and matching growth mechanisms, we reveal that the spatial scaling rules of these three elements are in a consistent framework, which allows us to use any single observation to infer the others. All numerical and theoretical results are consistent with empirical data from ten representative cities. In addition, our model can also provide a general explanation of the origins of the universal super- and sub-linear aggregate scaling laws and accurately predict kilometre-level socioeconomic activity. Our work opens a new avenue for uncovering the evolution of cities in terms of the interplay among urban elements, and it has a broad range of applications. OI Stanley, H./0000-0003-2800-4495; Li, Ruiqi/0000-0002-3290-9476
WOS:000416399900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="24">
<title>Urban road networks - spatial networks with universal geometric features? A case study on Germany's largest cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjb/e2011-10889-3</url>
<snippet>Urban road networks have distinct geometric properties that are partially determined by their (quasi-) two-dimensional structure. In this work, we study these properties for 20 of the largest German cities. We find that the small-scale geometry of all examined road networks is extremely similar. The object-size distributions of road segments and the resulting cellular structures are characterised by heavy tails. As a specific feature, a large degree of rectangularity is observed in all networks, with link angle distributions approximately described by stretched exponential functions. We present a rigorous statistical analysis of the main geometric characteristics and discuss their mutual interrelationships. Our results demonstrate the fundamental importance of cost-efficiency constraints for the time evolution of urban road networks. RI Donner, Reik/F-4400-2017 OI Donner, Reik/0000-0001-7023-6375
WOS:000298099800008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="25">
<title>Power Law Distributions of Patents as Indicators of Innovation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0049501</url>
<snippet>The total number of patents produced by a country (or the number of patents produced per capita) is often used as an indicator for innovation. Here we present evidence that the distribution of patents amongst applicants within many countries is well-described by power laws with exponents that vary between 1.66 (Japan) and 2.37 (Poland). We suggest that this exponent is a useful new metric for studying innovation. Using simulations based on simple preferential attachment-type rules that generate power laws, we find we can explain some of the variation in exponents between countries, with countries that have larger numbers of patents per applicant generally exhibiting smaller exponents in both the simulated and actual data. Similarly we find that the exponents for most countries are inversely correlated with other indicators of innovation, such as research and development intensity or the ubiquity of export baskets. This suggests that in more advanced economies, which tend to have smaller values of the exponent, a greater proportion of the total number of patents are filed by large companies than in less advanced countries. Citation: ONeale DRJ, Hendy SC (2012) Power Law Distributions of Patents as Indicators of Innovation. PLoS ONE 7(12): e49501. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0049501 RI Hendy, Shaun/A-9776-2008 OI Hendy, Shaun/0000-0003-3468-6517; O'Neale, Dion/0000-0002-3827-3480
WOS:000312588200007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="26">
<title>From global scaling to the dynamics of individual cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1718690115</url>
<snippet>Scaling has been proposed as a powerful tool to analyze the properties of complex systems and in particular for cities where it describes how various properties change with population. The empirical study of scaling on a wide range of urban datasets displays apparent nonlinear behaviors whose statistical validity and meaning were recently the focus of many debates. We discuss here another aspect, which is the implication of such scaling forms on individual cities and how they can be used for predicting the behavior of a city when its population changes. We illustrate this discussion in the case of delay due to traffic congestion with a dataset of 101 US cities in the years 1982-2014. We show that the scaling form obtained by agglomerating all of the available data for different cities and for different years does display a nonlinear behavior, but which appears to be unrelated to the dynamics of individual cities when their population grows. In other words, the congestion-induced delay in a given city does not depend on its population only, but also on its previous history. This strong path dependency prohibits the existence of a simple scaling form valid for all cities and shows that we cannot always agglomerate the data for many different systems. More generally, these results also challenge the use of transversal data for understanding longitudinal series for cities.
WOS:000426671900054
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="27">
<title>Spatial Data Analysis of Complex Urban Systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Cities are complex systems that are constantly evolving to better allow people to connect with one another. Moreover, and similar to countless natural phenomena, cities exhibit inherent orders that can be captured and expressed through complex analyses of their components. Using a variety of large datasets, this work offers a ring-buffer approach to analyze the spatial characteristics of four components of Chicago urban system, namely: roads, intersections, buildings, and population+ employment. The complex nature of these four components manifests itself in power-law relationships, represented by their fractal dimensions. Results show that road length and number of intersections, and to a larger degree, population+ employment count and building gross floor area exhibit significantly similar properties. The proposed method could further be used to analyze large demographic, socio-economic, and other geospatial datasets with the aim to study their impacts on relevant urban systems characteristics, including mobility, connectivity, and accessibility to name a few.
WOS:000380462900229
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="28">
<title>Multinational teams and diseconomies of scale in collaborative research</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.1500211</url>
<snippet>Collaborative research has become the mainstay in knowledge production across many domains of science and is widely promoted as a means of cultivating research quality, enhanced resource utilization, and high impact. An accurate appraisal of the value of collaborative research efforts is necessary to inform current funding and research policies. We reveal contemporary trends in collaborative research spanning multiple subject fields, with a particular focus on interactions between nations. We also examined citation outcomes of research teams and confirmed the accumulative benefits of having additional authors and unique countries involved. However, when per capita citation rates were analyzed to disambiguate the effects of authors and countries, decreasing returns in citations were noted with increasing authors among large research teams. In contrast, an increasing number of unique countries had a persistent additive citation effect. We also assessed the placement of foreign authors relative to the first author in paper bylines of biomedical research articles, which demonstrated a significant citation advantage of having an international presence in the second-to-last author position, possibly occupied by foreign primary co-investigators. Our analyses highlight the evolution and functional impact of team dynamics in research and suggest empirical strategies to evaluate team science.
WOS:000216596900021
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="29">
<title>Social Media Fingerprints of Unemployment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0128692</url>
<snippet>Recent widespread adoption of electronic and pervasive technologies has enabled the study of human behavior at an unprecedented level, uncovering universal patterns underlying human activity, mobility, and interpersonal communication. In the present work, we investigate whether deviations from these universal patterns may reveal information about the socio-economical status of geographical regions. We quantify the extent to which deviations in diurnal rhythm, mobility patterns, and communication styles across regions relate to their unemployment incidence. For this we examine a country-scale publicly articulated social media dataset, where we quantify individual behavioral features from over 19 million geo-located messages distributed among more than 340 different Spanish economic regions, inferred by computing communities of cohesive mobility fluxes. We find that regions exhibiting more diverse mobility fluxes, earlier diurnal rhythms, and more correct grammatical styles display lower unemployment rates. As a result, we provide a simple model able to produce accurate, easily interpretable reconstruction of regional unemployment incidence from their social-media digital fingerprints alone. Our results show that cost-effective economical indicators can be built based on publicly-available social media datasets. OI MORO, ESTEBAN/0000-0003-2894-1024; Garcia-Herranz, Manuel/0000-0002-4252-4975
WOS:000355187300120
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="30">
<title>Impact of Changing Technology on the Evolution of Complex Informational Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JPROC.2014.2367132</url>
<snippet>We live in an era of increasing connectivity in human societies and in technology. These structural changes in the ways we interact with each other and with increasingly ubiquitous computational and communication devices have been formalized in research across several disciplines through the dynamics of complex informational networks. Complex networks are (mathematical) graphs, connecting nodes (people, computers) via edges (relationships, wires). While much progress in methods for network analysis has been achieved, the fundamental principles that drive network growth in human societies and in worldwide computer networks remain rather obscure. Mechanistic models for the origin of certain structural graph elements have now become common, but the formal connection between large empirical studies of network evolution and fundamental concepts of information, learning, and social theory remains only latent. To address these issues, I argue here that the most interesting aspect of the dynamics of informational networks in complex systems is that they are the physical manifestations of processes of evolution, inference, and learning, from natural ecosystems, to cities and to online environments. I formalize the general problem of learning and computation in network environments in terms of average structural network changes and propose a conceptual framework to explain the transition from initially static, undifferentiated, and information-poor environments to dynamical, richly diverse, and interconnected systems. I illustrate these ideas empirically by providing examples from cities, and from global computer networks and webs of documents. I finish with an overview of expected changes to urban form and function and to computational hardware under likely technological scenarios.
WOS:000345524100003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="31">
<title>Elementary processes governing the evolution of road networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep00296</url>
<snippet>Urbanisation is a fundamental phenomenon whose quantitative characterisation is still inadequate. We report here the empirical analysis of a unique data set regarding almost 200 years of evolution of the road network in a large area located north of Milan (Italy). We find that urbanisation is characterised by the homogenisation of cell shapes, and by the stability throughout time of high-centrality roads which constitute the backbone of the urban structure, confirming the importance of historical paths. We show quantitatively that the growth of the network is governed by two elementary processes: (i) densification, corresponding to an increase in the local density of roads around existing urban centres and (ii) exploration, whereby new roads trigger the spatial evolution of the urbanisation front. The empirical identification of such simple elementary mechanisms suggests the existence of general, simple properties of urbanisation and opens new directions for its modelling and quantitative description. RI Nicosia, Vincenzo/C-7890-2013; strano, emanuele/J-3002-2015 OI Nicosia, Vincenzo/0000-0003-0636-3278; Latora, Vito/0000-0002-0984-8038; Porta, Sergio/0000-0003-1458-9517
WOS:000300954300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="32">
<title>Historical Urban Land Use Transformation in Virtual Geo-Library</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi4031500</url>
<snippet>As countries become increasingly urbanized, understanding how urban areas are changing within the landscape becomes increasingly important. Urbanized areas are often the strongest indicators of human interaction with the environment, and understanding how urban areas develop through remotely sensed data allows for more sustainable practices. A Landsat satellite sensor which is a remote sensing platform, with its ability to analyze global data, rapidly present itself as being an invaluable tool for studying the growth of urban areas. In this study, we present the virtual geo-library as the geovisualization tools to provide the analytical studies of the urbanization process in Malang City, East Java, Indonesia, using images derived from Landsat sensor family (1989 to 2014). We provide a dynamic geovisualization through virtual geo-library, where users could understand and get valuable scientific information (e.g., urban area changes and land use transformation in higher land). This system is also equipped with the tools to enable users to create automatic cartographic maps and print the results out as a digital pdf format file. OI Ramdani, Fatwa/0000-0002-8645-354X
WOS:000364411500023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="33">
<title>POWER-LAW DISTRIBUTIONS BASED ON EXPONENTIAL DISTRIBUTIONS: LATENT SCALING, SPURIOUS ZIPF'S LAW, AND FRACTAL RABBITS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1142/S0218348X15500097</url>
<snippet>The difference between the inverse power function and the negative exponential function is significant. The former suggests a complex distribution, while the latter indicates a simple distribution. However, the association of the power-law distribution with the exponential distribution has been seldom researched. This paper is devoted to exploring the relationships between exponential laws and power laws from the angle of view of urban geography. Using mathematical derivation and numerical experiments, I reveal that a power-law distribution can be created through a semi-moving average process of an exponential distribution. For the distributions defined in a one-dimension space (e.g. Zipfs law), the power exponent is 1; while for those defined in a two-dimension space (e.g. Clarks law), the power exponent is 2. The findings of this study are as follows. First, the exponential distributions suggest a hidden scaling, but the scaling exponents suggest a Euclidean dimension. Second, special power-law distributions can be derived from exponential distributions, but they differ from the typical power-law distributions. Third, it is the real power-law distributions that can be related with fractal dimension. This study discloses an inherent link between simplicity and complexity. In practice, maybe the result presented in this paper can be employed to distinguish the real power laws from spurious power laws (e.g. the fake Zipf distribution).
WOS:000355379400009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="34">
<title>A comparative gradient approach as a tool for understanding and managing urban ecosystems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11252-012-0240-9</url>
<snippet>To meet the grand challenges of the urban century-such as climate change, biodiversity loss, and persistent poverty-urban and ecological theory must contribute to integrated frameworks that treat social and ecological dynamics as interdependent. A socio-ecological framework that encapsulates theory from the social and ecological sciences will improve understanding of metropolitan dynamics and generate science for improved, sustainable management of urban ecosystems. To date, most urban ecological research has focused on single cities. A comparative approach that uses gradients within and between cities is a useful tool for building urban ecological theory. We offer five hypotheses that are testable using a comparative, gradient approach: (i) the current size, configuration, and function of larger metropolitan ecosystems predicts the potential trajectory of smaller urban areas; (ii) timing of growth explains the greatest variance in urban ecosystem structure and function; (iii) form and function of urban ecosystems are converging over time; (iv) urban ecosystems become more segregated and fragmented as populations increase; and (v) larger cities are more innovative than smaller cities in managing urban ecosystems. RI Grimm, Nancy/D-2840-2009; Finch, Deborah/H-2876-2015; Hall, Sharon/K-7893-2012 OI Grimm, Nancy/0000-0001-9374-660X; Finch, Deborah/0000-0001-9118-7381;
WOS:000310586100002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="35">
<title>Organization and scaling in water supply networksnn</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.96.062317</url>
<snippet>Public water supply is one of the societys most vital resources and most costly infrastructures. Traditional concepts of these networks capture their engineering identity as isolated, deterministic hydraulic units, but overlook their physics identity as related entities in a probabilistic, geographic ensemble, characterized by size organization and property scaling. Although discoveries of allometric scaling in natural supply networks (organisms and rivers) raised the prospect for similar findings in anthropogenic supplies, so far such a finding has not been reported in public water or related civic resource supplies. Examining an empirical ensemble of large number and wide size range, we show that water supply networks possess self-organized size abundance and theory-explained allometric scaling in spatial, infrastructural, and resource-and emission-flow properties. These discoveries establish scaling physics for water supply networks and may lead to novel applications in resource and jurisdiction-scale water governance.
WOS:000419014700004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="36">
<title>The mathematical relationship between Zipf's law and the hierarchical scaling law</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2011.12.031</url>
<snippet>The empirical studies of city-size distribution show that Zipfs law and the hierarchical scaling law are linked in many ways. The rank-size scaling and hierarchical scaling seem to be two different sides of the same coin, but their relationship has never been revealed by strict mathematical proof. In this paper, the Zipfs distribution of cities is abstracted as a q-sequence. Based on this sequence, a self-similar hierarchy consisting of many levels is defined and the numbers of cities in different levels form a geometric sequence. An exponential distribution of the average size of cities is derived from the hierarchy. Thus we have two exponential functions, from which follows a hierarchical scaling equation. The results can be statistically verified by simple mathematical experiments and observational data of cities. A theoretical foundation is then laid for the conversion from Zipfs law to the hierarchical scaling law, and the latter can show more information about city development than the former. Moreover, the self-similar hierarchy provides a new perspective for studying networks of cities as complex systems. A series of mathematical rules applied to cities such as the allometric growth law, the 2(n) principle and Paretos law can be associated with one another by the hierarchical organization. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000302423700027
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="37">
<title>Increased access to nearby green-blue areas associated with greater metropolitan population well-being</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/ldr.3083</url>
<snippet>Numerous cities in the world have to handle and support increasing populations, with questions remaining concerning good planning strategies for their growth and development. Among these questions, access to nature for urban residents has been the subject of increased scrutiny in recent years. We here propose and apply a generally applicable new approach to quantitatively investigate the role of close access to natural or nature-based green-blue areas for the well-being of urban populations. A key novel aspect of this approach is to use income level as a measure of peoples ability to choose their nearby living environment such that it provides them with the highest affordable level of well-being. Based on this measure, we concretely investigate possible trends in local green-blue area access with increasing local income level in the case-study example of the Stockholm Metropolitan region in Sweden. For this regional case, we find clear relationships between income level (and related degree of nationality homogeneity) and share of natural/nature-based green-blue areas and man-made grey areas within walksheds of different population segments. The results point at the importance of maintaining and restoring nearby natural and nature-based green-blue areas as key solutions for increased well-being of urban populations and call for further testing and comparative investigations of local-scale associations between socio-economic descriptors and physical environment in other parts of the world. OI Goldenberg, Romain/0000-0002-3549-3453; Destouni, Georgia/0000-0001-9408-4425
WOS:000447651700032
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="38">
<title>Urban Scaling and the Production Function for Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0058407</url>
<snippet>The factors that account for the differences in the economic productivity of urban areas have remained difficult to measure and identify unambiguously. Here we show that a microscopic derivation of urban scaling relations for economic quantities vs. population, obtained from the consideration of social and infrastructural properties common to all cities, implies an effective model of economic output in the form of a Cobb-Douglas type production function. As a result we derive a new expression for the Total Factor Productivity (TFP) of urban areas, which is the standard measure of economic productivity per unit of aggregate production factors (labor and capital). Using these results we empirically demonstrate that there is a systematic dependence of urban productivity on city population size, resulting from the mismatch between the size dependence of wages and labor, so that in contemporary US cities productivity increases by about 11&#37; with each doubling of their population. Moreover, deviations from the average scale dependence of economic output, capturing the effect of local factors, including history and other local contingencies, also manifest surprising regularities. Although, productivity is maximized by the combination of high wages and low labor input, high productivity cities show invariably high wages and high levels of employment relative to their size expectation. Conversely, low productivity cities show both low wages and employment. These results shed new light on the microscopic processes that underlie urban economic productivity, explain the emergence of effective aggregate urban economic output models in terms of labor and capital inputs and may inform the development of economic theory related to growth. RI Strumsky, Deborah/F-5795-2013
WOS:000317480700005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="39">
<title>A Tale of Many Cities: Universal Patterns in Human Urban Mobility</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0037027</url>
<snippet>The advent of geographic online social networks such as Foursquare, where users voluntarily signal their current location, opens the door to powerful studies on human movement. In particular the fine granularity of the location data, with GPS accuracy down to 10 meters, and the worldwide scale of Foursquare adoption are unprecedented. In this paper we study urban mobility patterns of people in several metropolitan cities around the globe by analyzing a large set of Foursquare users. Surprisingly, while there are variations in human movement in different cities, our analysis shows that those are predominantly due to different distributions of places across different urban environments. Moreover, a universal law for human mobility is identified, which isolates as a key component the rank-distance, factoring in the number of places between origin and destination, rather than pure physical distance, as considered in some previous works. Building on our findings, we also show how a rank-based movement model accurately captures real human movements in different cities. OI Lambiotte, Renaud/0000-0002-0583-4595; Mascolo, Cecilia/0000-0001-9614-4380
WOS:000305349600008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="40">
<title>Crime prediction through urban metrics and statistical learning</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2018.03.084</url>
<snippet>Understanding the causes of crime is a longstanding issue in researchers agenda. While it is a hard task to extract causality from data, several linear models have been proposed to predict crime through the existing correlations between crime and urban metrics. However, because of non-Gaussian distributions and multicollinearity in urban indicators, it is common to find controversial conclusions about the influence of some urban indicators on crime. Machine learning ensemble-based algorithms can handle well such problems. Here, we use a random forest regressor to predict crime and quantify the influence of urban indicators on homicides. Our approach can have up to 97&#37; of accuracy on crime prediction, and the importance of urban indicators is ranked and clustered in groups of equal influence, which are robust under slightly changes in the data sample analyzed. Our results determine the rank of importance of urban indicators to predict crime, unveiling that unemployment and illiteracy are the most important variables for describing homicides in Brazilian cities. We further believe that our approach helps in producing more robust conclusions regarding the effects of urban indicators on crime, having potential applications for guiding public policies for crime control. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Ribeiro, Haroldo/C-8614-2012; Cepid, CeMEAI/J-2417-2015 OI Ribeiro, Haroldo/0000-0002-9532-5195;
WOS:000437061000039
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="41">
<title>A Spatial and Temporal Autocorrelated Growth Model for City Rank-Size Distribution</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0042098009348326</url>
<snippet>Rank-size distribution has been an important tool in characterising and analysing city size distributions across spatial and temporal scales. Zipfs law in city rank-size distribution has been observed in many analyses and is considered an important empirical regularity describing the organisation of cities. Based on analyses of the evolution of cities in Texas from 1850 to 2000, this paper documents spatial and temporal autocorrelation in city population growth rates. A modelling strategy has been developed that accounts for the spatial and temporal autocorrelated growth in Texas cities and is effective in reconstructing the empirical rank-size distribution. This study shows that it is necessary to take into account the interdependence among cities in simulating the city size distribution.
WOS:000273678900005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="42">
<title>The Origins of Scaling in Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.1235823</url>
<snippet>Despite the increasing importance of cities in human societies, our ability to understand them scientifically and manage them in practice has remained limited. The greatest difficulties to any scientific approach to cities have resulted from their many interdependent facets, as social, economic, infrastructural, and spatial complex systems that exist in similar but changing forms over a huge range of scales. Here, I show how all cities may evolve according to a small set of basic principles that operate locally. A theoretical framework was developed to predict the average social, spatial, and infrastructural properties of cities as a set of scaling relations that apply to all urban systems. Confirmation of these predictions was observed for thousands of cities worldwide, from many urban systems at different levels of development. Measures of urban efficiency, capturing the balance between socioeconomic outputs and infrastructural costs, were shown to be independent of city size and might be a useful means to evaluate urban planning strategies.
WOS:000320647000038
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="43">
<title>Is this scaling nonlinear?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.150649</url>
<snippet>One of the most celebrated findings in complex systems in the last decade is that different indexes y (e. g. patents) scale nonlinearly with the population x of the cities in which they appear, i. e. y similar to x(beta), beta not equal 1. More recently, the generality of this finding has been questioned in studies that used new databases and different definitions of city boundaries. In this paper, we investigate the existence of nonlinear scaling, using a probabilistic framework in which fluctuations are accounted for explicitly. In particular, we show that this allows not only to (i) estimate beta and confidence intervals, but also to (ii) quantify the evidence in favour of beta not equal 1 and (iii) test the hypothesis that the observations are compatible with the nonlinear scaling. We employ this framework to compare five different models to 15 different datasets and we find that the answers to points (i)-(iii) crucially depend on the fluctuations contained in the data, on how they are modelled, and on the fact that the city sizes are heavy-tailed distributed. RI Gerlach, Martin/D-7230-2016; Altmann, Eduardo/A-3320-2009 OI Gerlach, Martin/0000-0002-0879-7865; Altmann, Eduardo/0000-0002-1932-3710; Miotto, Jose Maria/0000-0002-5850-3394
WOS:000384409400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="44">
<title>Mediating Effects Between Objective and Subjective Indicators of Urban Quality of Life: Testing Specific Models for Safety and Access</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11205-014-0682-y</url>
<snippet>Enhancing the urban quality of life (QoL) is an explicit policy goal of many countries, yet it is rarely studied using models that relate objective measures of the urban environment to the subjective evaluations of residents. It thus often remains unclear how planning interventions in the urban environment may influence residents satisfaction with their living conditions. In particular, during periods of significant urban growth, such as those recently observed in Switzerland, which result in diverse, unwanted threats to the local QoL (e.g., loss of green spaces, traffic congestions, and fear of crime). This study uses data from a sample of 1,693 residents that participated in a postal survey about urban QoL. The responses were combined with objective attributes of residential conditions, using geographic information systems. Structural equation models were calibrated to examine the direct and indirect effects of important indicators of urban QoL, namely safety in public spaces and access to central urban facilities. The study sheds further light on the mediating effects between objective characteristics and subjective evaluations that influence the urban QoL. The results showed predominantly low correlations between objective characteristics and subjective evaluations of urban QoL, which confirmed the findings of the few previous studies on this topic. Surprisingly, this study also found a strong link between objective access and perceived accessibility. This relation was explained by the spatial scope of the study region and suggested that the scale discordance theory should be tested in future research. The findings implied that variations in objective measures do not reliably represent differences as evaluated by residents. RI Stauffacher, Michael/A-1504-2009 OI Stauffacher, Michael/0000-0001-9724-6741
WOS:000352228900011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="45">
<title>Superlinear and sublinear urban scaling in geographical networks modeling cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.90.022803</url>
<snippet>Using a geographical scale-free network to describe relations between people in a city, we explain both superlinear and sublinear allometric scaling of urban indicators that quantify activities or performances of the city. The urban indicator Y(N) of a city with the population size N is analytically calculated by summing up all individual activities produced by person-to-person relationships. Our results show that the urban indicator scales superlinearly with the population, namely, Y(N) alpha N-beta with beta &gt; 1, if Y(N) represents a creative productivity and the indicator scales sublinearly (beta &lt; 1) if Y(N) is related to the degree of infrastructure development. These results coincide with allometric scaling observed in real-world urban indicators. We also show how the scaling exponent beta depends on the strength of the geographical constraint in the network formation.
WOS:000340003700009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="46">
<title>Ecology in an anthropogenic biosphere</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1890/14-2274.1</url>
<snippet>Humans, unlike any other multicellular species in Earths history, have emerged as a global force that is transforming the ecology of an entire planet. It is no longer possible to understand, predict, or successfully manage ecological pattern, process, or change without understanding why and how humans reshape these over the long term. Here, a general causal theory is presented to explain why human societies gained the capacity to globally alter the patterns, processes, and dynamics of ecology and how these anthropogenic alterations unfold over time and space as societies themselves change over human generational time. Building on existing theories of ecosystem engineering, niche construction, inclusive inheritance, cultural evolution, ultrasociality, and social change, this theory of anthroecological change holds that sociocultural evolution of subsistence regimes based on ecosystem engineering, social specialization, and non-kin exchange, or "sociocultural niche construction," is the main cause of both the long-term upscaling of human societies and their unprecedented transformation of the biosphere. Human sociocultural niche construction can explain, where classic ecological theory cannot, the sustained transformative effects of human societies on biogeography, ecological succession, ecosystem processes, and the ecological patterns and processes of landscapes, biomes, and the biosphere. Anthroecology theory generates empirically testable hypotheses on the forms and trajectories of long-term anthropogenic ecological change that have significant theoretical and practical implications across the subdisciplines of ecology and conservation. Though still at an early stage of development, anthroecology theory aligns with and integrates established theoretical frameworks including social-ecological systems, social metabolism, countryside biogeography, novel ecosystems, and anthromes. The "fluxes of nature" are fast becoming "cultures of nature." To investigate, understand, and address the ultimate causes of anthropogenic ecological change, not just the consequences, human sociocultural processes must become as much a part of ecological theory and practice as biological and geophysical processes are now. Strategies for achieving this goal and for advancing ecological science and conservation in an increasingly anthropogenic biosphere are presented. OI Ellis, Erle/0000-0002-2006-3362
WOS:000358731100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="47">
<title>Explaining the prevalence, scaling and variance of urban phenomena</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41562-016-0012</url>
<snippet>The prevalence of many urban phenomena changes systematically with population size(1). We propose a theory that unifies models of economic complexity(2,3) and cultural evolution(4) to derive urban scaling. The theory accounts for the difference in scaling exponents and average prevalence across phenomena, as well as the difference in the variance within phenomena across cities of similar size. The central ideas are that a number of necessary complementary factors must be simultaneously present for a phenomenon to occur, and that the diversity of factors is logarithmically related to population size. The model reveals that phenomena that require more factors will be less prevalent, scale more superlinearly and show larger variance across cities of similar size. The theory applies to data on education, employment, innovation, disease and crime, and it entails the ability to predict the prevalence of a phenomenon across cities, given information about the prevalence in a single city. OI Gomez-Lievano, Andres/0000-0001-8320-0857
WOS:000418775900022
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="48">
<title>Professional diversity and the productivity of cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep05393</url>
<snippet>Attempts to understand the relationship between diversity, productivity and scale have remained limited due to the scheme-dependent nature of the taxonomies describing complex systems. We analyze the diversity of US metropolitan areas in terms of profession diversity and employment to show how this frequency distribution takes a universal scale-invariant form, common to all cities, in the limit of infinite resolution of occupational taxonomies. We show that this limit is obtained under general conditions that follow from the analysis of the variation of the occupational frequency across taxonomies at different resolutions in a way analogous to finite-size scaling in statistical physical systems. We propose a theoretical framework that derives the form and parameters of the limiting distribution of professions based on the appearance, in urban social networks, of new occupations as the result of specialization and coordination of labor. By deriving classification scheme-independent measures of functional diversity and modeling cities as social networks embedded in infrastructural space, these results show how standard economic arguments of division and coordination of labor can be articulated in detail in cities and provide a microscopic basis for explaining increasing returns to population scale observed at the level of entire metropolitan areas. OI Youn, Hyejin/0000-0002-6190-4412
WOS:000337888600007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="49">
<title>The distance-decay function of geographical gravity model: Power law or exponential law?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.chaos.2015.05.022</url>
<snippet>The distance-decay function of the geographical gravity model is originally an inverse power law, which suggests a scaling process in spatial interaction. However, the distance exponent of the model cannot be reasonably explained with the ideas from Euclidean geometry. This results in a dimension dilemma in geographical analysis. Consequently, a negative exponential function was used to replace the inverse power function to serve for a distance-decay function. But a new puzzle arose that the exponential-based gravity model goes against the first law of geography. This paper is devoted for solving these kinds of problems by mathematical reasoning and empirical analysis. New findings are as follows. First, the distance exponent of the gravity model is demonstrated to be a fractal dimension using the geometric measure relation. Second, the similarities and differences between the gravity models and spatial interaction models are revealed using allometric relations. Third, a four-parameter gravity model possesses a symmetrical expression, and we need dual gravity models to describe spatial flows. The observational data of Chinas cities and regions (29 elements indicative of 841 data points) in 2010 are employed to verify the theoretical inferences. A conclusion can be reached that the geographical gravity model based on power-law decay is more suitable for analyzing large, complex, and scale-free regional and urban systems. This study lends further support to the suggestion that the underlying rationale of fractal structure is entropy maximization. Moreover, it suggests that many dimensional dilemmas of spatial modeling can be solved using the concepts from fractal geometry. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000358970500019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="50">
<title>Entropic Cities The Paradox of Urbanism in Ancient Mesopotamia</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1086/695983</url>
<snippet>The growth of cities in antiquity is paradoxical: before modern health and sanitation standards, early urban dwellers suffered high mortality as a result of epidemics and chronic diseases arising, respectively, from propinquity and poor sanitation. At the same time, lower-status individuals within those cities would have endured depressed birth rates because, typically, many toiled in partially or fully dependent occupations not conducive to early marriage or stable families. The interplay between these compounding forces implies that early cities would not have been viable over the long term and could not have grown without a continual flow of immigrants. The early cities of Mesopotamia were no exception. In an earlier publication, I argued that the growth of the first centers that emerged in the alluvial lowlands of the Tigris and Euphrates Rivers during the fourth millennium BC was predicated on migratory inflows that took place, in part, in the context of self-amplifying cycles whereby the replacement of imported commodities with locally made, mass-produced substitutes catalyzed increases in specialization, employment, market size, and trade (Smithian growth). In this article, I expand on these ideas, explore their applicability to later periods of Mesopotamian history, and consider further iterations of substitution-fueled growth cycles in those periods.
WOS:000424209100002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="51">
<title>Constructing cities, deconstructing scaling laws</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2014.0745</url>
<snippet>Cities can be characterized and modelled through different urban measures. Consistency within these observables is crucial in order to advance towards a science of cities. Bettencourt et al. have proposed that many of these urban measures can be predicted through universal scaling laws. We develop a framework to consistently define cities, using commuting to work and population density thresholds, and construct thousands of realizations of systems of cities with different boundaries for England and Wales. These serve as a laboratory for the scaling analysis of a large set of urban indicators. The analysis shows that population size alone does not provide us enough information to describe or predict the state of a city as previously proposed, indicating that the expected scaling laws are not corroborated. We found that most urban indicators scale linearly with city size, regardless of the definition of the urban boundaries. However, when nonlinear correlations are present, the exponent fluctuates considerably. RI Hatna, Erez/D-9665-2015
WOS:000345500000003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="52">
<title>Heterogeneity and scale of sustainable development in cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1606033114</url>
<snippet>Rapid worldwide urbanization is at once the main cause and, potentially, the main solution to global sustainable development challenges. The growth of cities is typically associated with increases in socioeconomic productivity, but it also creates strong inequalities. Despite a growing body of evidence characterizing these heterogeneities in developed urban areas, not much is known systematically about their most extreme forms in developing cities and their consequences for sustainability. Here, we characterize the general patterns of income and access to services in a large number of developing cities, with an emphasis on an extensive, high-resolution analysis of the urban areas of Brazil and South Africa. We use detailed census data to construct sustainable development indices in hundreds of thousands of neighborhoods and show that their statistics are scale-dependent and point to the critical role of large cities in creating higher average incomes and greater access to services within their national context. We then quantify the general statistical trajectory toward universal basic service provision at different scales to show that it is characterized by varying levels of inequality, with initial increases in access being typically accompanied by growing disparities over characteristic spatial scales. These results demonstrate how extensions of these methods to other goals and data can be used over time and space to produce a simple but general quantitative assessment of progress toward internationally agreed sustainable development goals. OI Bettencourt, Luis/0000-0001-6176-5160; Brelsford, Christa/0000-0002-3490-8020
WOS:000408095300037
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="53">
<title>Revealing centrality in the spatial structure of cities from human activity patterns</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0042098015601599</url>
<snippet>Identifying changes in the spatial structure of cities is a prerequisite for the development and validation of adequate planning strategies. Nevertheless, current methods of measurement are becoming ever more challenged by the highly diverse and intertwined ways of how people actually make use of urban space. Here, we propose a new quantitative measure for the centrality of locations, taking into account not only the numbers of people attracted to different locations, but also the diversity of the activities they are engaged in. This centrality index allows for the identification of functional urban centres and for a systematic tracking of their relative importance over time, thus contributing to our understanding of polycentricity. We demonstrate the proposed index using travel survey data in Singapore for different years between 1997 and 2012. It is shown that, on the one hand, the city-state has been developing rapidly towards a polycentric urban form that compares rather closely with the official urban development plan. On the other hand, however, the downtown core has strongly gained in its importance, and this can be partly attributed to the recent extension of the public transit system.
WOS:000397164500007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="54">
<title>Urban Transitions: On Urban Resilience and Human-Dominated Ecosystems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s13280-010-0081-9</url>
<snippet>Urbanization is a global multidimensional process paired with increasing uncertainty due to climate change, migration of people, and changes in the capacity to sustain ecosystem services. This article lays a foundation for discussing transitions in urban governance, which enable cities to navigate change, build capacity to withstand shocks, and use experimentation and innovation in face of uncertainty. Using the three concrete case cities-New Orleans, Cape Town, and Phoenix-the article analyzes thresholds and cross-scale interactions, and expands the scale at which urban resilience has been discussed by integrating the idea from geography that cities form part of "system of cities" (i.e., they cannot be seen as single entities). Based on this, the article argues that urban governance need to harness social networks of urban innovation to sustain ecosystem services, while nurturing discourses that situate the city as part of regional ecosystems. The article broadens the discussion on urban resilience while challenging resilience theory when addressing human-dominated ecosystems. Practical examples of harnessing urban innovation are presented, paired with an agenda for research and policy. OI Elmqvist, Thomas/0000-0002-4617-6197; Ernstson, Henrik/0000-0002-6415-4821
WOS:000283502300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="55">
<title>Urban Scaling of Cities in the Netherlands</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0146775</url>
<snippet>We investigated the socioeconomic scaling behavior of all cities with more than 50,000 inhabitants in the Netherlands and found significant superlinear scaling of the gross urban product with population size. Of these cities, 22 major cities have urban agglomerations and urban areas defined by the Netherlands Central Bureau of Statistics. For these major cities we investigated the superlinear scaling for three separate modalities: the cities defined as municipalities, their urban agglomerations and their urban areas. We find superlinearity with power-law exponents of around 1.15. But remarkably, both types of agglomerations underperform if we compare for the same size of population an agglomeration with a city as a municipality. In other words, an urban system as one formal municipality performs better as compared to an urban agglomeration with the same population size. This effect is larger for the second type of agglomerations, the urban areas. We think this finding has important implications for urban policy, in particular municipal reorganizations. A residual analysis suggests that cities with a municipal reorganization recently and in the past decades have a higher probability to perform better than cities without municipal restructuring.
WOS:000367888100150
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="56">
<title>Urban and RuralPopulation and Energy Consumption Dynamics in Local Authorities within England and Wales</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/buildings6030034</url>
<snippet>The formulation of feasible and pragmatic policies that mitigate climate change would require a thorough understanding of the interconnectivity that exists between environment, energy, and the composition of our settlements both urban and rural. This study explores the patterns of energy consumption in England and Wales by investigating consumption behavior within domestic and transport sectors as a function of city characteristics, such as population, density, and density distribution for 346 Local Authority Units (LAU). Patterns observed linking energetic behavior of these LAUs to their respective population and area characteristics highlight some distinctly contrasting consumption behaviors within urban and rural zones. This provides an overview of the correlation between urban/rural status, population, and energy consumption and highlights points of interest for further research and policy intervention. The findings show that energy consumption across cities follows common power law scaling increasing sub-linearly with their population regardless of their urban/rural classification. However, when considering per capita and sector specific consumptions, decreasing per capita consumption patterns are observed for growing population densities within more uniformly populated urban LAUs. This is while rural and sparsely populated LAUs exhibit sharply different patterns for gas, electricity, and transport per capita consumption. OI Arbabi, Hadi/0000-0001-8518-9022
WOS:000385532700010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="57">
<title>Cities as nuclei of sustainability?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0265813516638340</url>
<snippet>We have assembled CO2 emission figures from collections of urban GHG emission estimates published in peer-reviewed journals or reports from research institutes and non-governmental organizations. Analyzing the scaling with population size, we find that the exponent is development dependent with a transition from super- to sub-linear scaling. From the climate change mitigation point of view, the results suggest that urbanization is desirable in developed countries. Further, we compare this analysis with a second scaling relation, namely the fundamental allometry between city population and area, and propose that density might be a decisive quantity too. Last, we derive the theoretical country-wide urban emissions by integration and obtain a dependence on the size of the largest city. OI Rybski, Diego/0000-0001-6125-7705; Kropp, Juergen/0000-0001-7791-3420
WOS:000400907700003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="58">
<title>Urban Scaling and Its Deviations: Revealing the Structure of Wealth, Innovation and Crime across Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0013541</url>
<snippet>With urban population increasing dramatically worldwide, cities are playing an increasingly critical role in human societies and the sustainability of the planet. An obstacle to effective policy is the lack of meaningful urban metrics based on a quantitative understanding of cities. Typically, linear per capita indicators are used to characterize and rank cities. However, these implicitly ignore the fundamental role of nonlinear agglomeration integral to the life history of cities. As such, per capita indicators conflate general nonlinear effects, common to all cities, with local dynamics, specific to each city, failing to provide direct measures of the impact of local events and policy. Agglomeration nonlinearities are explicitly manifested by the superlinear power law scaling of most urban socioeconomic indicators with population size, all with similar exponents (similar to 1.15). As a result larger cities are disproportionally the centers of innovation, wealth and crime, all to approximately the same degree. We use these general urban laws to develop new urban metrics that disentangle dynamics at different scales and provide true measures of local urban performance. New rankings of cities and a novel and simpler perspective on urban systems emerge. We find that local urban dynamics display long-term memory, so cities under or outperforming their size expectation maintain such (dis)advantage for decades. Spatiotemporal correlation analyses reveal a novel functional taxonomy of U. S. metropolitan areas that is generally not organized geographically but based instead on common local economic models, innovation strategies and patterns of crime. RI Strumsky, Deborah/F-5795-2013
WOS:000284036800004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="59">
<title>Productive knowledge, scaling, enterprise richness and poverty in a group of small U.S. counties</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/23311886.2018.1560883</url>
<snippet>The socioeconomic and entrepreneurial characteristics of a group of 68 small (fewer than 120000 persons) U.S. counties exhibit extensive orderliness. There is a geographically-insensitive log-log (power law) relationship between the number of enterprises and enterprise richness (the number of enterprise types) in the counties. Enterprise richness is used as a proxy for productive knowledge, i.e., the explicit and tacit knowledge to produce and deliver things and services. Enterprise richness quantifies the number of times a new business idea is successfully introduced. The numbers of population, enterprises, employees in enterprises, total county employees, and higher-educated persons all scale super-linearly in relation to levels of productive knowledge. Thus, there are significant agglomeration effects associated with increases/decreases of productive knowledge. The ratios between two entrepreneurial types i.e., new and existing entrepreneurs, have been quantified in relation to the size of the counties. Smaller counties have a greater need for new entrepreneurs than for existing entrepreneurs, and the opposite is the case for larger counties. The notion that the level of poverty is related to the level of productive knowledge in countries, led to exploration of the relationship of various characteristics to poverty levels in the selected counties. Poverty is an important moderating factor in the entrepreneurial wellbeing of the 68 counties. The demographic-socioeconomic-entrepreneurial nexus of U.S. counties deserves further research attention. OI Toerien, Daan/0000-0001-6989-395X
WOS:000454432500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="60">
<title>Urban sustainable transportation planning strategies for livable City's quality of life</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.habitatint.2018.10.002</url>
<snippet>Urban planning and its relevant transportation deploying have a particularly profound influence on the sustainability and livability of a city, and which also be crucial to the quality of life to urban residents at the same time. It was also suggested that the conception of livability should be extended to embrace the concerns associated with the sustainability. However, planning frameworks or assessment patterns that address the dynamics of urban planning and demand for transportation deploying are relatively rare; there also few public policies in related research fields have discussed the effects of the changes in various assessment indicators over time. Furthermore, following the rising advancements in social communication and computer technologies in modern society, the data collection, storage, and processing capabilities of people have improved substantially. And, the emergence of big data or extendible open data facilitates analysis and prediction availability, and enabled people to find immediate solutions to numerous dilemmas encountered. Therefore, based on the aforementioned intention, treating the city as a dynamic process with the trying of introducing the big data or extendible open data for facilitating urban sustainability and livability is undoubtedly worth to explore in further. The present study intends to initially examine the application of big data in sustainable and livable transportation strategies in Taipei City, Taiwan. Firstly, we investigate previous research on transportation sustain ability in various countries to generalize our preliminary list of transportation sustainability indices that satisfy the principles of livable cities. And, key indices were then selected through the Fuzzy Delphi Method by administering a questionnaire to six experts from industrial, governmental, and academic sectors respectively. The research results were applied to develop decision-making strategies for responding to the environmental dynamics of Taipei City's transportation infrastructure system by using the analytic network process combined with a data-mining technique. Thus, big data pertaining to urban transportation were analyzed to predict the future dynamic trends of the key indices and prioritize the sustainable transportation strategies for a livable city under dynamic temporal and spatial changes. Ultimately, the policy implications of this study can not only offer a solution for current needs related to urban planning but also serve as a more transparent decision-making or well selection basis for developing sustainable and livable urban life in near future.
WOS:000452565000002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="61">
<title>Settlement scaling and economic change in the Central Andes</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jas.2016.07.012</url>
<snippet>There is a longstanding debate in anthropology and history regarding the extent to which the determinants of past economic change are similar in any specific ways to those that operate today. In this paper, we examine the extent to which increasing returns to settlement scale in material outputs, which are apparent in contemporary urban systems, also operated in the Late Pre-Hispanic Tarma and Mantaro drainages of the Peruvian Central Andes. Proxy measures for material outputs across settlements and households show that this region experienced a marked economic expansion following its incorporation into the Inka Empire ca. 1450 CE. We argue that these changes in living standards are consistent with expectations of an emerging framework known as settlement scaling theory that specifies relationships between human aggregation, social connectivity and material outputs. Our results suggest that intensification of human social connectivity and material flows as measured through settlement size distributions can be sufficient to raise living standards even in the absence of markets. (C) 2016 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd. This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license.
WOS:000383525300009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="62">
<title>Spatial and Temporal Dimensions of Urban Expansion in China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.5b00065</url>
<snippet>The scale of urbanization in China during the past three decades is unprecedented in human history, and the processes are poorly understood. Here we present an effort to map the urban land expansion processes of 32 major cities in China from 1978 to 2010 using Landsat satellite data to understand the temporal and spatial characteristics. Results showed that the urban extent of the 32 cities expanded exponentially with very high annual rates varying from 3.2&#37; to 12.8&#37;. Temporal fluctuation in urban expansion rates in these 32 cities was obvious, with unexpected and alarming expansion rates from 2005 to 2010 that drastically exceeded their expectation, which was calculated from. the long-term trend between 1978 and 2005, by 45&#37;. Overall, we found that the growth rates of cities during the entire study period were inversely related to city size, contradicting the theory or Gibrats law, which states that the growth rate is independent of city size. More detailed analysis indicated that city growth in China has transitioned from contradicting to conforming to Gibrats law since 1995. Our study suggests that the urban expansion theory (i.e., Gibrats law) does not fit Chinese expansion consistently over time, and the exact causes are unknown. Exploring the causes in future research will improve our understanding of the theory and, more importantly, understand the feasibility of the theoretical relationship between city size and expansion rate in guiding contemporary urban expansion planning.
WOS:000359891700026
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="63">
<title>The Pre-History of Urban Scaling</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0087902</url>
<snippet>Cities are increasingly the fundamental socio-economic units of human societies worldwide, but we still lack a unified characterization of urbanization that captures the social processes realized by cities across time and space. This is especially important for understanding the role of cities in the history of human civilization and for determining whether studies of ancient cities are relevant for contemporary science and policy. As a step in this direction, we develop a theory of settlement scaling in archaeology, deriving the relationship between population and settled area from a consideration of the interplay between social and infrastructural networks. We then test these models on settlement data from the Pre-Hispanic Basin of Mexico to show that this ancient settlement system displays spatial scaling properties analogous to those observed in modern cities. Our data derive from over 1,500 settlements occupied over two millennia and spanning four major cultural periods characterized by different levels of agricultural productivity, political centralization and market development. We show that, in agreement with theory, total settlement area increases with population size, on average, according to a scale invariant relation with an exponent in the range 2/3 &lt;= alpha &lt;= 5/6. As a consequence, we are able to infer aggregate socioeconomic properties of ancient societies from archaeological measures of settlement organization. Our findings, from an urban settlement system that evolved independently from its old-world counterparts, suggest that principles of settlement organization are very general and may apply to the entire range of human history. OI Cabaniss, Andrew/0000-0003-0884-9503
WOS:000331262600020
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="64">
<title>Multi-scaling allometric analysis for urban and regional development</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2016.08.008</url>
<snippet>The concept of allometric growth is based on scaling relations, and it has been applied to urban and regional analysis for a long time. However, most allometric analyses were devoted to the single proportional relation between two elements of a geographical system. Few researches focus on the allometric scaling of multielements. In this paper, a process of multiscaling allometric analysis is developed for the studies on spatio-temporal evolution of complex systems. By means of linear algebra, general system theory, and by analogy with the analytical hierarchy process, the concepts of allometric growth can be integrated with the ideas from fractal dimension. Thus a new methodology of geo-spatial analysis and the related theoretical models emerge. Based on the least squares regression and matrix operations, a simple algorithm is proposed to solve the multiscaling allometric equation. Applying the analytical method of multielement allometry to Chinese cities and regions yields satisfying results. A conclusion is reached that the multiscaling allometric analysis can be employed to make a comprehensive evaluation for the relative levels of urban and regional development, and explain spatial heterogeneity. The notion of multiscaling allometry may enrich the current theory and methodology of spatial analyses of urban and regional evolution. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000386411700066
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="65">
<title>Energy distribution and economic growth</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.reseneeco.2011.04.004</url>
<snippet>This research examines the physical constraints on the growth process. In order to run, maintain and build capital energy is required to be distributed to geographically dispersed sites where investments are deemed profitable. We capture this aspect of physical reality by a network theory of electricity distribution. The model leads to a supply relation according to which feasible electricity consumption per capita rises with the size of the economy, as measured by capital per capita. Specifically, the relation is a simple power law with an exponent assigned to capital that is bounded between 1/2 and 3/4, depending on the efficiency of the network. Together with an energy conservation equation, capturing instantaneous aggregate demand for electricity, we are able to provide a metabolic-energetic founded law of motion for capital per capita that is mathematically isomorphic to the one emanating from the Solow growth model. Using data for the 50 US states 1960-2000, we examine the determination of growth in electricity consumption per capita and test the model structurally. The model fits the data well. The exponent in the power law connecting capital and electricity is 2/3. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. OI Strulik, Holger/0000-0002-5615-2412
WOS:000295751100002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="66">
<title>Zipf's law, 1/f noise, and fractal hierarchy</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.chaos.2011.10.001</url>
<snippet>Fractals, 1/f noise, and Zipfs laws are frequently observed within the natural living world as well as in social institutions, representing three signatures of complex systems. All these observations are associated with scaling laws and therefore have created much research interest in many diverse scientific circles. However, the inherent relationships between these scaling phenomena are not yet clear. In this paper, theoretical demonstration and mathematical experiments based on urban studies are employed to reveal the analogy between fractal patterns, 1/f spectra, and the Zipf distribution. First, the multifractal process empirically suggests the Zipf distribution. Second, a 1/f spectrum is mathematically identical to Zipfs law. Third, both spectra and Zipfs law can be converted into a self-similar hierarchy. Fourth, fractals, 1/f spectra, Zipfs law can be rescaled with similar exponential laws and power laws. The self-similar hierarchy is a more general scaling method which can be used to unify different scaling phenomena and rules in both physical and social systems such as cities, rivers, earthquakes, fractals, 1/f noise, and rank-size distributions. The mathematical laws of this hierarchical structure can provide us with a holistic perspective of looking at complexity and complex systems. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000300595500007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="67">
<title>CO2 emissions in relation to street-network configuration and city size</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.trd.2014.11.025</url>
<snippet>The street-network efficiency of tens of British cities in relation to transport fuel consumption and CO2 emissions are analyzed. The results show a strong linear positive correlation between length entropy and average street length, and a negative correlation between entropy and street density. Also, the results suggest that in a large city the street network is used more efficiently than in a small city, as indicated by the sublinear relations between city size (population) and the number of streets, total length of streets, and the area covered by the street network. The sublinear relation means that these parameters grow more slowly than the city size. By contrast, because a larger fraction of the street network is used at close to full capacity during considerable part of the time in a large city than a small one, the fuel consumption and the CO2 emissions show a linear relation with city size and superlinear relation with total street length. The superlinear relation means that the CO2 emissions increase faster than the total street length, a measure of the network size. Thus, large cities may be less energy efficient and environmentally friendly than small cities. In every city the street network needs to interconnect all the buildings, which requires a certain minimum size. In a small city, however, the network is used to a low capacity most of the time so that its relations to fuel consumption and the CO2 emissions are more favorable than those in a large city. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000350525300009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="68">
<title>Do Physicists Have Geography Envy? And What Can Geographers Learn from It?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00045608.2015.1039105</url>
<snippet>Recent years have seen an increasing amount of work by physicists on topics outside their traditional research domain, including geography. We explore the scope of this development, place it in a historical context dating back at least to statistical physics in the nineteenth century and trace the origins of more recent developments to the roots of computational science after World War II. Our primary purpose is not historical, however. Instead, we are concerned with understanding what geographers can learn from the many recent contributions by physicists to understanding spatiotemporal systems. Drawing on examples of work in this tradition by physicists, we argue that two apparently different modes of investigation are common: model-driven and data-driven approaches. The former is associated with complexity science, whereas the latter is more commonly associated with the fourth paradigm, more recently known as "big data." Both modes share technical strengths and, more important, a capacity for generalization, which is absent from much work in geography. We argue that although some of this research lacks an appreciation of previous geographical contributions, when assessed critically, it nevertheless brings useful new perspectives, new methods, and new ideas to bear on topics central to geography, yet neglected in the discipline. We conclude with some suggestions for how geographers can build on these new approaches, both inside and outside the discipline. OI Manson, Steven/0000-0001-7697-5339
WOS:000359478600005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="69">
<title>Fluctuation Scaling, Taylor's Law, and Crime</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0109004</url>
<snippet>Fluctuation scaling relationships have been observed in a wide range of processes ranging from internet router traffic to measles cases. Taylors law is one such scaling relationship and has been widely applied in ecology to understand communities including trees, birds, human populations, and insects. We show that monthly crime reports in the UK show complex fluctuation scaling which can be approximated by Taylors law relationships corresponding to local policing neighborhoods and larger regional and countrywide scales. Regression models applied to local scale data from Derbyshire and Nottinghamshire found that different categories of crime exhibited different scaling exponents with no significant difference between the two regions. On this scale, violence reports were close to a Poisson distribution (alpha = 1.057 +/- 0.026) while burglary exhibited a greater exponent (alpha = 1.292 +/- 0.029) indicative of temporal clustering. These two regions exhibited significantly different pre-exponential factors for the categories of anti-social behavior and burglary indicating that local variations in crime reports can be assessed using fluctuation scaling methods. At regional and countrywide scales, all categories exhibited scaling behavior indicative of temporal clustering evidenced by Taylors law exponents from 1.43 +/- 0.12 (Drugs) to 2.094 +/- 0081 (Other Crimes). Investigating crime behavior via fluctuation scaling gives insight beyond that of raw numbers and is unique in reporting on all processes contributing to the observed variance and is either robust to or exhibits signs of many types of data manipulation. OI Hanley, Quentin/0000-0002-8189-9550; Dyer, Rachel-May/0000-0002-5577-6864
WOS:000343729600086
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="70">
<title>Understanding the systemic nature of cities to improve health and climate change mitigation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2016.04.014</url>
<snippet>Understanding cities comprehensively as systems is a costly challenge and is typically not feasible for policy makers. Nevertheless, focusing on some key systemic characteristics of cities can give useful insights for policy to advance health and well-being outcomes. Moreover, if we take a coevolutionary systems view of cities, some conventional assumptions about the nature of urban development (e.g. the growth in private vehicle use with income) may not stand up. We illustrate this by examining the coevolution of urban transport and land use systems, and institutional change, giving examples of policy implications. At a high level, our concern derives from the need to better understand the dynamics of urban change, and its implications for health and well-being. At a practical level, we see opportunities to use stylised findings about urban systems to underpin policy experiments. While it is now not uncommon to view cities as systems, policy makers appear to have made little use so far of a systems approach to inform choice of policies with consequences for health and well-being. System insights can be applied to intelligently anticipate change - for example, as cities are subjected to increasing natural system reactions to climate change, they must find ways to mitigate and adapt to it. Secondly, systems insights around policy cobenefits are vital for better informing horizontal policy integration. Lastly, an implication of system complexity is that rather than seeking detailed, 'full' knowledge about urban issues and policies, cities would be well advised to engage in policy experimentation to address increasingly urgent health and climate change issues. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. OI Chapman, Ralph/0000-0002-3437-8525
WOS:000382339000040
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="71">
<title>Why Do Cities Grow? Insights from Nonequilibrium Thermodynamics at the Urban and Global Scales</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jiec.12239</url>
<snippet>This forum article explores thermodynamic understanding of the growth of cities, including theoretical foundations, observations, and analysis. The general theory of nonequilibrium thermodynamics is reviewed, recognizing differences in interpretation between Prigogine and Schneider and Kay as well as discussing the hypothesis of maximum entropy production. Calculations of exergy gradients in a few cities and settlements, along with measures of anthropogenic heat loss in further cities, support the notion that cities are dissipative structures. The observation that primary energy use per capita increases in Singapore and Hong Kong as they grow is further evidence to support the thermodynamic understanding of the growth of cities, indicative of an increasing rate of entropy production. At the global scale, the strong linear relationship between global urban population and total global energy use, and the distribution of city sizes according to Zipfs law, can be understood as emergent results based on thermodynamics. Parallel results might be derived from models that represent underlying microscale processes, several of which are reviewed. Issues for future research include: development of nonequilibrium thermodynamic models specific to city growth; further study of exergy flows of cities with consistent methodology, including attention to solar energy exchanges in cities; and further exploration of links between thermodynamic and economic models of urban growth.
WOS:000353243300007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="72">
<title>Urban transitions: scaling complex cities down to human size</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.08.030</url>
<snippet>Complexity science has become prominent in studying cities as concepts like "smart city" and "big data" indicate. In particular network analysis has allowed to studying various aspects of cities in new ways. As such these analyses are often disconnected and subsequent business models often remain disembedded. However, complexity science can also compare various patterns extending over different scales (scaling) if they belong to the same entity (allometry). Such relationships pertain to cities too suggesting that buildings, infrastructure and traffic amongst other things develop interdependently and, that across specific city systems scaling phenomena can be compared according to cities population size. The article argues that while many scaling phenomena of physical and social networks can indeed inform urban transition research the proposed central role of cities population size is highly ambivalent. This is particularly true for economic indicators like GDP, which do not reflect the need for sustainability. Still, network and scaling analysis of the built environment can contribute to transition theory if explanatory social mechanisms relating human behaviours and social institutions to existing scaling phenomena are provided. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000368207500063
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="73">
<title>The scaling of crime concentration in cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0183110</url>
<snippet>Crime is a major threat to societys well-being but lacks a statistical characterization that could lead to uncovering some of its underlying mechanisms. Evidence of nonlinear scaling of urban indicators in cities, such as wages and serious crime, has motivated the understanding of cities as complex systems-a perspective that offers insights into resources limits and sustainability, but that usually neglects details of the indicators themselves. Notably, since the nineteenth century, criminal activities have been known to occur unevenly within a city; crime concentrates in such way that most of the offenses take place in few regions of the city. Though confirmed by different studies, this concentration lacks broad analyses on its characteristics, which hinders not only the comprehension of crime dynamics but also the proposal of sounding counter-measures. Here, we developed a framework to characterize crime concentration which divides cities into regions with the same population size. We used disaggregated criminal data from 25 locations in the U.S. and the U.K., spanning from 2 to 15 years of longitudinal data. Our results confirmed that crime concentrates regardless of city and revealed that the level of concentration does not scale with city size. We found that the distribution of crime in a city can be approximated by a power-law distribution with exponent a that depends on the type of crime. In particular, our results showed that thefts tend to concentrate more than robberies, and robberies more than burglaries. Though criminal activities present regularities of concentration, we found that criminal ranks have the tendency to change continuously over time-features that support the perspective of crime as a complex system and demand analyses and evolving urban policies covering the city as a whole. OI Menezes, Ronaldo/0000-0002-6479-6429
WOS:000407431800054
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="74">
<title>The anatomy of urban social networks and its implications in the searchability problem</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep10265</url>
<snippet>The appearance of large geolocated communication datasets has recently increased our understanding of how social networks relate to their physical space. However, many recurrently reported properties, such as the spatial clustering of network communities, have not yet been systematically tested at different scales. In this work we analyze the social network structure of over 25 million phone users from three countries at three different scales: country, provinces and cities. We consistently find that this last urban scenario presents significant differences to common knowledge about social networks. First, the emergence of a giant component in the network seems to be controlled by whether or not the network spans over the entire urban border, almost independently of the population or geographic extension of the city. Second, urban communities are much less geographically clustered than expected. These two findings shed new light on the widely-studied searchability in self-organized networks. By exhaustive simulation of decentralized search strategies we conclude that urban networks are searchable not through geographical proximity as their country-wide counterparts, but through an homophily-driven community structure. RI Gonzalez, Marta/E-9456-2011 OI Gonzalez, Marta/0000-0002-8482-0318; BENITO ZAFRILLA, ROSA MARIA/0000-0003-3949-8232; Smoreda, Zbigniew/0000-0002-4047-7597
WOS:000355608200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="75">
<title>Living in a Network of Scaling Cities and Finite Resources</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11538-014-9949-3</url>
<snippet>Many urban phenomena exhibit remarkable regularity in the form of nonlinear scaling behaviors, but their implications on a system of networked cities has never been investigated. Such knowledge is crucial for our ability to harness the complexity of urban processes to further sustainability science. In this paper, we develop a dynamical modeling framework that embeds population-resource dynamics-a generalized Lotka-Volterra system with modifications to incorporate the urban scaling behaviors-in complex networks in which cities may be linked to the resources of other cities and people may migrate in pursuit of higher welfare. We find that isolated cities (i.e., no migration) are susceptible to collapse if they do not have access to adequate resources. Links to other cities may help cities that would otherwise collapse due to insufficient resources. The effects of inter-city links, however, can vary due to the interplay between the nonlinear scaling behaviors and network structure. The long-term population level of a city is, in many settings, largely a function of the citys access to resources over which the city has little or no competition. Nonetheless, careful investigation of dynamics is required to gain mechanistic understanding of a particular city-resource network because cities and resources may collapse and the scaling behaviors may influence the effects of inter-city links, thereby distorting what topological metrics really measure.
WOS:000349331100010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="76">
<title>On the confluence of city living, energy saving behaviours and direct residential energy consumption</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.envsci.2016.07.003</url>
<snippet>The purpose of this study is to shed light on the connection between income, dwelling type, tenure type and city living, in terms of both a households energy saving behaviours and direct residential energy consumption. This study employs data from the Household Energy Consumption Survey, Australia. Using a seemingly unrelated regression (SUR) system of equations the results reveal some key mechanisms which may allow householders to realise lower levels of energy consumption and hence lower carbon emissions. The results indicate that there are characteristics unique to living in a city that are linked to higher levels of direct residential energy consumption. On a number of measures (e.g. household income, tenure type and dwelling type), the results point to a lower likelihood of engaging in energy saving behaviours in cities. Also, depending on the number of energy saving behaviours, these actions have the potential to more than offset higher direct residential energy consumption of householders residing in separate houses. Coupled with these findings renters, a more vulnerable social group, are found to be significantly disadvantaged, suffering from a much lower adaptive capacity. Specifically, householders who rent their home are 77&#37; less likely to have solar electricity. A result which may reflect differences in access to opportunity. Further, householders who rent are less likely to engage in energy saving actions. A finding which may reflect difference in ontological security and the greater psychological burden associated with undertaking energy saving behaviours (a barrier) borne by renters not shared with home owners. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. RI Poruschi, Lavinia/M-5115-2017 OI Poruschi, Lavinia/0000-0002-5109-9202; Ambrey, Christopher/0000-0002-3790-7509
WOS:000389089300036
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="77">
<title>An allometric scaling relation based on logistic growth of cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.chaos.2014.04.017</url>
<snippet>The relationships between urban area and population size have been empirically demonstrated to follow the scaling law of allometric growth. This allometric scaling is based on exponential growth of city size and can be termed "exponential allometry", which is associated with the concepts of fractals. However, both city population and urban area comply with the course of logistic growth rather than exponential growth. In this paper, I will present a new allometric scaling based on logistic growth to solve the above mentioned problem. The logistic growth is a process of replacement dynamics. Defining a pair of replacement quotients as new measurements, which are functions of urban area and population, we can derive an allometric scaling relation from the logistic processes of urban growth, which can be termed "logistic allometry". The exponential allometric relation between urban area and population is the approximate expression of the logistic allometric equation when the city size is not large enough. The proper range of the allometric scaling exponent value is reconsidered through the logistic process. Then, a medium-sized city of Henan Province, China, is employed as an example to validate the new allometric relation. The logistic allometry is helpful for further understanding the fractal property and self-organized process of urban evolution in the right perspective. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000338602500008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="78">
<title>Defining city size</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1068/b3805ed</url>
<snippet>
WOS:000297236900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="79">
<title>Statistical Signs of Social Influence on Suicides</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep06239</url>
<snippet>By treating the suicide as a social fact, Durkheim envisaged that suicide rates should be determined by the connections between people and society. Under the same framework, he considered that crime is bound up with the fundamental conditions of all social life. The social effect on the occurrence of homicides has been previously substantiated, and confirmed here, in terms of a superlinear scaling relation: by doubling the population of a Brazilian city results in an average increment of 135&#37; in the number of homicides, rather than the expected isometric increase of 100&#37;, as found, for example, for the mortality due to car crashes. Here we present statistical signs of the social influence on the suicide occurrence in cities. Differently from homicides (superlinear) and fatal events in car crashes (isometric), we find sublinear scaling behavior between the number of suicides and city population, with allometric power-law exponents, beta = 0.84 +/- 0.02 and 0.87 +/- 0.01, for all cities in Brazil and US counties, respectively. Also for suicides in US, but using the Metropolitan Statistical Areas (MSAs), we obtain beta = 0.88 +/- 0.01. RI UFC, DF/E-1564-2017; Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/J-4630-2016; Andrade, Jose/C-5451-2013; Moreira, Andre Auto/C-5290-2013 OI Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/0000-0002-9247-6780; Andrade, Jose/0000-0002-5571-7610; Moreira, Andre Auto/0000-0003-1046-5218
WOS:000341441400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="80">
<title>What Is a Complex Innovation System?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0156150</url>
<snippet>Innovation systems are sometimes referred to as complex systems, something that is intuitively understood but poorly defined. A complex system dynamically evolves in non-linear ways giving it unique properties that distinguish it from other systems. In particular, a common signature of complex systems is scale-invariant emergent properties. A scale-invariant property can be identified because it is solely described by a power law function, f(x) = kx(alpha), where the exponent, a, is a measure of scale-invariance. The focus of this paper is to describe and illustrate that innovation systems have properties of a complex adaptive system. In particular scale-invariant emergent properties indicative of their complex nature that can be quantified and used to inform public policy. The global research system is an example of an innovation system. Peer-reviewed publications containing knowledge are a characteristic output. Citations or references to these articles are an indirect measure of the impact the knowledge has on the research community. Peer-reviewed papers indexed in Scopus and in the Web of Science were used as data sources to produce measures of sizes and impact. These measures are used to illustrate how scale-invariant properties can be identified and quantified. It is demonstrated that the distribution of impact has a reasonable likelihood of being scale-invariant with scaling exponents that tended toward a value of less than 3.0 with the passage of time and decreasing group sizes. Scale-invariant correlations are shown between the evolution of impact and size with time and between field impact and sizes at points in time. The recursive or self-similar nature of scale-invariance suggests that any smaller innovation system within the global research system is likely to be complex with scale-invariant properties too.
WOS:000377369700040
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="81">
<title>Does environmental policy affect scaling laws between population and pollution? Evidence from American metropolitan areas</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0181407</url>
<snippet>Modern cities are engines of production, innovation, and growth. However, urbanization also increases both local and global pollution from household consumption and firms production. Do emissions change proportionately to city size or does pollution tend to outpace or lag urbanization? Do emissions scale differently with population versus economic growth or are emissions, population, and economic growth inextricably linked? How are the scaling relationships between emissions, population, and economic growth affected by environmental regulation? This paper examines the link between urbanization, economic growth and pollution using data from Metropolitan Statistical Areas (MSAs) in the United States between 1999 and 2011. We find that the emissions of local air pollution in these MSAs scale according to a power law with both population size and gross domestic product (GDP). However, the monetary damages from these local emissions scale linearly with both population and GDP. Counties that have previously been out of attainment with the local air quality standards set by the Clean Air Act show an entirely different relationship: local emissions scale according to the square root of population, while the monetary damages from local air pollution follow a 2/3 rds power law with population. Counties out of attainment are subject to more stringent emission controls; we argue based on this that enforcement of the Clean Air Act induces sublinear scaling between emissions, damages, and city size. In contrast, we find that metropolitan GDP scales super-linearly with population in all MSAs regardless of attainment status. Summarizing, our findings suggest that environmental policy limits the adverse effects of urbanization without interfering with the productivity benefits that manifest in cities. OI Muller, Nicholas/0000-0003-1712-6526
WOS:000407196700010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="82">
<title>Innovation Topologies: Modelling Knowledge Diffusion with Cellular Automaton</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>As an extract of an ongoing cooperative project of Wroclaw University of Technology and TU Dresden, the paper explores the emergence of innovation and asks whether innovation can be to any extent predicted spatially. Cellular Automata (CA) have been chosen for this study as the spatial modelling tool. The goal is to understand the nature of the spread of innovations in a limited space, and to equip the CA with information needed to calibrate it to actual, real-world processes. The CA spaces are formed by cells with specific characteristics concerning their absorptivity, or attractiveness for innovators. In addition, information is given how the agents behave and act depending on the nature of their innovation. Purpose - The final goal of the research is to examine the possibilities of forecasting the appearance of innovations with the use of spatial, architectural, and economic data. Design/methodology/approach - Cellular automata were created and tested. As input, categorised data of selected entities were gathered and organised into a matrix. The CA were calibrated in order to recreate the historical processes described in the antecedent research. Originality/value - The assumption of the study is that well-calibrated CA can model real-world knowledge diffusion processes with acceptable precision. This methodology allows for credible - numerical and spatial - estimation of the likelihood of the appearance of innovation inside a specified branch of economy and inside a specified area. Practical implications -As a starting point for extended research, the study wants to establish a scientific basis for knowledge and innovation-based spatial planning, having implications for economic development, urban management, and policy-making.
WOS:000357262300027
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="83">
<title>Size, connectivity, and tipping in spatial networks: Theory and empirics</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compenvurbsys.2015.08.004</url>
<snippet>We study the impact of settlement sizes on network connectivity in a spatial setting. First, we develop a model of geometric urban networks that posits a positive relationship between connectivity and size. Empirical evidence is then presented validating the model prediction that local links exhibit super-linear scaling with the exponent greater than 1, while long-range connections scale linearly with the unit exponent The scaling exponents thus suggest that the impact of population size on connectivity is stronger within cities than between cities. We next combine the geometric framework with a computational model of interacting agents to generate a realistic settlement distribution and urban networks from the bottom-up. Calibrated simulation results demonstrate the consistency between hierarchical rank-size distribution and scale-free connectivity. Finally, coupling the spatial network with a tipping diffusion model allows us to consolidate the evolution of network connectivity, city sizes, and social practices in a unified computational framework. (C) 2015 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.
WOS:000368306700037
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="84">
<title>SETTLEMENT SCALING IN MIDDLE-RANGE SOCIETIES</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/aaq.2017.42</url>
<snippet>The contemporary relevance of archaeology would be greatly enhanced if archaeologists could develop theory that frames human societies of all scales in the same terms. We present evidence that an approach known as settlement scaling theory can contribute to such a framework. The theory proposes that a variety of aggregate socioeconomic properties of human networks emerge from individuals arranging themselves in space so as to balance the costs of movement with the benefits of social interactions. This balancing leads to settlements that concentrate human interactions and their products in space and time in an open-ended way. The parameters and processes embedded in settlement scaling models are very basic, and this suggests that scaling phenomena should be observable in the archaeological record of middle-range societies just as readily as they have been observed in contemporary first-world nations. In this paper, we show that quantitative scaling relationships observed for modern urban systems, and more recently for early civilizations, are also apparent in settlement data from the Central Mesa Verde and northern Middle Missouri regions of North America. These findings suggest that settlement scaling theory may help increase the practical relevance of archaeology for present-day concerns. La relevancia contemporanea de la arqueologia seria mucho mayor si los arqueologos pudieran desarrollar una teoria que enmarcara las sociedades humanas de todas las escalas en los mismos terminos. Presentamos evidencia de que un enfoque conocido como teoria de escalamiento de asentamientos puede contribuir a este marco. La teoria propone que una variedad de propiedades socioeconomicas agregadas de las redes humanas surgen de la organizacion de individuos en el espacio con el fin de equilibrar los costos del movimiento con los beneficios de las interacciones sociales. Esta busqueda de un equilibrio lleva a desarrollar asentamientos que concentran las interacciones humanas y sus productos en el espacio y el tiempo de una manera abierta. Los parametros y procesos incluidos en los modelos de escalamiento de asentamientos son muy basicos y esto sugiere que los fenomenos de escalamiento deben ser tan facilmente observables en el registro arqueologico de las sociedades de rango medio como se han observado en las naciones contemporaneas del primer mundo. En este articulo se muestra que las relaciones cuantitativas de escalamiento que han sido observadas para los sistemas urbanos modernos y, mas recientemente, para las civilizaciones tempranas, tambien son evidentes en los datos de asentamientos de las regiones de la Mesa Verde Central y el Missouri Medio, ambas en Norteamerica. Estos hallazgos sugieren que la teoria de escalamiento de asentamientos puede ayudar a aumentar la relevancia practica de la arqueologia para cuestiones actuales.
WOS:000413170200003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="85">
<title>Scaling and universality in urban economic diversification</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2015.0937</url>
<snippet>Understanding cities is central to addressing major global challenges from climate change to economic resilience. Although increasingly perceived as fundamental socio-economic units, the detailed fabric of urban economic activities is only recently accessible to comprehensive analyses with the availability of large datasets. Here, we study abundances of business categories across US metropolitan statistical areas, and provide a framework for measuring the intrinsic diversity of economic activities that transcends scales of the classification scheme. A universal structure common to all cities is revealed, manifesting self-similarity in internal economic structure as well as aggregated metrics (GDP, patents, crime). We present a simple mathematical derivation of the universality, and provide a model, together with its economic implications of open-ended diversity created by urbanization, for understanding the observed empirical distribution. Given the universal distribution, scaling analyses for individual business categories enable us to determine their relative abundances as a function of city size. These results shed light on the processes of economic differentiation with scale, suggesting a general structure for the growth of national economies as integrated urban systems. OI Youn, Hyejin/0000-0002-6190-4412
WOS:000374959000012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="86">
<title>The rank-size scaling law and entropy-maximizing principle</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2011.07.010</url>
<snippet>The rank-size regularity known as Zipfs law is one of the scaling laws and is frequently observed in the natural living world and social institutions. Many scientists have tried to derive the rank-size scaling relation through entropy-maximizing methods, but they have not been entirely successful. By introducing a pivotal constraint condition. I present here a set of new derivations based on the self-similar hierarchy of cities. First. I derive a pair of exponent laws by postulating local entropy maximizing. From the two exponential laws follows a general hierarchical scaling law, which implies the general form of Zipfs law. Second. I derive a special hierarchical scaling law with the exponent equal to 1 by postulating global entropy maximizing, and this implies the pure form of Zipfs law. The rank-size scaling law has proven to be one of the special cases of the hierarchical scaling law, and the derivation suggests a certain scaling range with the first or the last data point as an outlier. The entropy maximization of social systems differs from the notion of entropy increase in thermodynamics. For urban systems, entropy maximizing suggests the greatest equilibrium between equity for parts/individuals and efficiency of the whole. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000297779500036
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="87">
<title>Spatial correlations, clustering and percolation-like transitions in homicide crimes</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1209/0295-5075/111/18002</url>
<snippet>The spatial dynamics of criminal activities has been recently studied through statistical physics methods; however, models and results have been focusing on local scales (city level) and much less is known about these patterns at larger scales, e.g. at a country level. Here we report on a characterization of the spatial dynamics of the homicide crimes along the Brazilian territory using data from all cities (similar to 5000) in a period of more than thirty years. Our results show that the spatial correlation function in the per capita homicides decays exponentially with the distance between cities and that the characteristic correlation length displays an acute increasing trend in the latest years. We also investigate the formation of spatial clusters of cities via a percolation-like analysis, where clustering of cities and a phase-transition-like behavior describing the size of the largest cluster as a function of a homicide threshold are observed. This transition-like behavior presents evolutive features characterized by an increasing in the homicide threshold (where the transitions occur) and by a decreasing in the transition magnitudes (length of the jumps in the cluster size). We believe that our work sheds new light on the spatial patterns of criminal activities at large scales, which may contribute for better political decisions and resources allocation as well as opens new possibilities for modeling criminal activities by setting up fundamental empirical patterns at large scales. Copyright (C) EPLA, 2015 RI Alves, Luiz/H-3389-2013; Mendes, Renio/F-9261-2017; Ribeiro, Haroldo/C-8614-2012 OI Alves, Luiz/0000-0001-6204-5552; Ribeiro, Haroldo/0000-0002-9532-5195; Lenzi, Ervin/0000-0003-3853-1790
WOS:000359722700025
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="88">
<title>Down to Earth: Contextualizing the Anthropocene</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.gloenvcha.2015.11.004</url>
<snippet>The Anthropocene is now being used as a conceptual frame by different communities and in a variety of contexts to understand the evolving human environment relationship. However, as we argue in this paper, the notion of an Anthropos, or humanity, as global, unified geological force threatens to mask the diversity and differences in the actual conditions and impacts of humankind, and does not do justice to the diversity of local and regional contexts. For this reason, we interpret in this article the notion of an Anthropocene in a more context-dependent, localized and social understanding. We do this through illustrating examples from four issue domains, selected for their variation in terms of spatial and temporal scale, systems of governance and functional interdependencies: nitrogen cycle distortion (in particular as it relates to food security); ocean acidification; urbanization; and wildfires. Based on this analysis, we systematically address the consequences of the lens of the Anthropocene for the governance of social-ecological systems, focusing on the multi-level, functional and sectoral organization of governance, and possible redefinitions of governance systems and policy domains. We conclude that the notion of the Anthropocene, once seen in light of social inequalities and regional differences, allows for novel analysis of issue-based problems in the context of a global understanding, in both academic and political terms. This makes it a useful concept to help leverage and (re-)focus our efforts in a more innovative and effective way to transition towards sustainability. (C) 2015 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd. RI van der Hel, Sandra/R-1716-2016; Seto, Karen/C-2722-2008; Chen, Chen-Tung Arthur/C-8901-2011; Biermann, Frank/D-4175-2013; Bai, Xuemei/A-5443-2012 OI van der Hel, Sandra/0000-0001-6552-9616; Biermann, Frank/0000-0002-0292-0703; Bai, Xuemei/0000-0001-6556-8041; Lemos, Maria Carmen/0000-0001-6686-730X
WOS:000381165100032
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="89">
<title>Urban chaos and replacement dynamics in nature and society</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2014.06.060</url>
<snippet>Replacements resulting from competition are ubiquitous phenomena in both nature and society. The evolution of a self-organized system is always a physical process substituting one type of components for another type of components. A logistic model of replacement dynamics has been proposed in terms of technical innovation and urbanization, but it fails to arouse widespread attention in the academia. This paper is devoted to laying the foundations of general replacement principle by using analogy and induction. The empirical base of this study is urban replacement, including urbanization and urban growth. The sigmoid functions can be employed to model various processes of replacement. Many mathematical methods such as allometric scaling and head/tail breaks can be applied to analyzing the processes and patterns of replacement. Among varied sigmoid functions, the logistic function is the basic and the simplest model of replacement dynamics. A new finding is that replacement can be associated with chaos in a nonlinear system, e.g., urban chaos is just a part of replacement dynamics. The aim of developing replacement theory is at understanding complex interaction and conversion. This theory provides a new way of looking at urbanization, technological innovation and diffusion, Volterra Lotkas predator prey interaction, man land relation, and dynastic changes resulting from peasant uprising, and all that. Especially, the periodic oscillations and chaos of replacement dynamics can be used to explain and predict the catastrophic occurrences in the physical and human systems. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000340977700040
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="90">
<title>Is there enough fertile soil to feed a planet of growing cities?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2014.10.048</url>
<snippet>We analyze a scaling law for the consumption of agricultural soil by cities. The nonlinear dependence of the size of the city on the number of inhabitants gives rise to an equation for population dynamics. We found the asymptotic limit of the solution for this equation, given by the carrying capacity in terms of number of inhabitants that can be fed. The carrying capacity as a function of the scaling law exponent is computed numerically, showing that the exponent must be very small to ensure a food sustainability. We suggest a bound for the value of this exponent and analyze the reliability of the scaling law for major cities. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000347017300071
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="91">
<title>Rich and Poor Cities in Europe. An Urban Scaling Approach to Mapping the European Economic Transition</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0159465</url>
<snippet>Recent advances in the urban science make broad use of the notion of scaling. We focus here on the important scaling relationship between the gross metropolitan product (GMP) of a city and its population (pop). It has been demonstrated that GMP alpha Y Ypop(beta) with beta always greater than 1 and close to 1.2. This fundamental finding highlights a universal rule that holds across countries and cultures and might explain the very nature of cities. However, in an increasingly connected world, the hypothesis that the economy of a city solely depends on its population might be questionable. Using data for 248 cities in the European Union between 2005 and 2010, we found a double GMP/pop scaling regime. For West EU cities, beta = 1 over the whole the period, while for post-communist cities beta &gt; 1 and increases from similar to 1.2 to similar to 1.4. The evolution of the scaling exponent describes the convergence of postcommunist European cities to open and liberal economies. We propose a simple model of economic convergence in which, under stable political conditions, a linear GMP/pop scaling is expected for all cities. The results suggest that the GMP/pop super-linear scaling represents a phase of economic growth rather than a steady, universal urban feature. The results also suggest that relationships between cities are embedded in their political and economic context and cannot be neglected in explanations of cities, urbanization and urban economics.
WOS:000381768800006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="92">
<title>Scaling tunable network model to reproduce the density-driven superlinear relation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.5023736</url>
<snippet>Previous works have shown the universality of allometric scaling under total and density values at the city level, but our understanding of the size effects of regions on the universality of allometric scaling remains inadequate. Here, we revisit the scaling relations between the gross domestic production (GDP) and the population based on the total and density values and first reveal that the allometric scaling under density values for different regions is universal. The scaling exponent beta under the density value is in the range of (1.0, 2.0], which unexpectedly exceeds the range observed by Pan et al. [Nat. Commun. 4, 1961 (2013)]. For the wider range, we propose a network model based on a 2D lattice space with the spatial correlation factor alpha as a parameter. Numerical experiments prove that the generated scaling exponent beta in our model is fully tunable by the spatial correlation factor alpha. Our model will furnish a general platform for extensive urban and regional studies. Published by AIP Publishing.
WOS:000428818800025
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="93">
<title>Spatio-temporal variations in the urban rhythm: the travelling waves of crime</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjds/s13688-018-0158-4</url>
<snippet>In the last decades, the notion that cities are in a state of equilibrium with a centralised organisation has given place to the viewpoint of cities in disequilibrium and organised from bottom to up. In this perspective, cities are evolving systems that exhibit emergent phenomena built from local decisions. While urban evolution promotes the emergence of positive social phenomena such as the formation of innovation hubs and the increase in cultural diversity, it also yields negative phenomena such as increases in criminal activity. Yet, we are still far from understanding the driving mechanisms of these phenomena. In particular, approaches to analyse urban phenomena are limited in scope by neglecting both temporal non-stationarity and spatial heterogeneity. In the case of criminal activity, we know for more than one century that crime peaks during specific times of the year, but the literature still fails to characterise the mobility of crime. Here we develop an approach to describe the spatial, temporal, and periodic variations in urban quantities. With crime data from 12 cities, we characterise how the periodicity of crime varies spatially across the city over time. We confirm one-year criminal cycles and show that this periodicity occurs unevenly across the city. These waves of crime keep travelling across the city: while cities have a stable number of regions with a circannual period, the regions exhibit non-stationary series. Our findings support the concept of cities in a constant change, influencing urban phenomena-in agreement with the notion of cities not in equilibrium.
WOS:000445676700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="94">
<title>10 Years Later: Revisiting Priorities for Science and Society a Decade After the Millennium Ecosystem Assessment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/bs.aecr.2015.10.005</url>
<snippet>The study of ecological services (ESs) is fast becoming a cornerstone of mainstream ecology, largely because they provide a useful means of linking functioning to societal benefits in complex systems by connecting different organizational levels. In order to identify the main challenges facing current and future ES research, we analyzed the effects of the publication of the Millennium Ecosystem Assessment (MEA, 2005) on different disciplines. Within a set of topics framed around concepts embedded within the MEA, each co-author identified five key research challenges and, where feasible, suggested possible solutions. Concepts included those related to specific service types (i.e. provisioning, supporting, regulating, cultural, aesthetic services) as well as more synthetic issues spanning the natural and social sciences, which often linked a wide range of disciplines, as was the case for the application of network theory. By merging similar responses, and removing some of the narrower suggestions from our sample pool, we distilled the key challenges into a smaller subset. We review some of the historical context to the MEA and identify some of the broader scientific and philosophical issues that still permeate discourse in this field. Finally, we consider where the greatest advances are most likely to be made in the next decade and beyond. RI Mulder, Christian/N-4726-2015; Scherber, Christoph/B-6611-2009; Hines, Jes/L-7668-2016; Vonk, Jan Arie/B-1105-2009; Haughton, Alison/A-7769-2013; PASCUAL, UNAI/B-4766-2012; Cramer, Wolfgang/B-8221-2008; Wood, Stephen/A-1928-2017; Massol, Francois/D-9872-2013; Mancinelli, Giorgio/A-7679-2013 OI Mulder, Christian/0000-0001-5735-6989; Scherber, Christoph/0000-0001-7924-8911; Hines, Jes/0000-0002-9129-5179; Vonk, Jan Arie/0000-0002-8803-1148; Haughton, Alison/0000-0002-2852-5736; PASCUAL, UNAI/0000-0002-5696-236X; Cramer, Wolfgang/0000-0002-9205-5812; Wood, Stephen/0000-0002-9551-8165; Massol, Francois/0000-0002-4098-955X; Mancinelli, Giorgio/0000-0002-5833-7322; Bonkowski, Michael/0000-0003-2656-1183; Penuelas, Josep/0000-0002-7215-0150; Bohan, David/0000-0001-5656-775X; Sutherland, William/0000-0002-6498-0437; Vacher, Corinne/0000-0003-3023-6113; Setala, Heikki Martti/0000-0002-5230-4001; Eisenhauer, Nico/0000-0002-0371-6720
WOS:000376149300002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="95">
<title>A developmental approach to ancient innovation The potter's wheel in the Bronze Age east Mediterranean</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1075/pc.22.1.04kna</url>
<snippet>In this paper, we view creativity through the lens of innovation, a concept familiar to archaeologists across a range of contexts and theoretical perspectives. Most attempts to understand ancient innovation thus far, we argue, have been limited by their lack of capacity to cope with the multiple scales of innovation: Those that track widespread changes, like the beginnings of metallurgy, fail to account for the changes experiences by individual craftspeople; those that do justice to the details of the micro-scale, with 'thick' description, cannot well explain the regional adoption of new practices. Here we develop an intermediary position, at the meso-scale, which we hope can serve to integrate these different scales. It is based on the notions that all innovation entails learning (and hence cognitive transformations) and that learning is very often supported at this meso-scale, through 'communities of practice'. Drawing on the ethno-archaeological literature in particular, we emphasise how learning is a process of embodied cognition. Our archaeological case study is then drawn from the Bronze Age east Mediterranean, where a striking innovation in pottery making - the use of rotative kinetic energy via the potter's wheel - sees a very uneven uptake from region to region over the course of many centuries. We propose certain differences in community organization from one region to another that might account for such variation in the adoption of an innovation, with the island of Crete in particular seeing a much more stable trajectory of adoption than many of its neighbouring areas.
WOS:000209567100005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="96">
<title>The effect of scaling and connection on the sustainability of a socio-economic resource system</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolecon.2012.02.017</url>
<snippet>Policy makers dealing with complex systems oftentimes rely on "linear thinking." This is understandable due to the ease and convenience offered by the simplicity of such conceptualization. Although this line of thinking may help facilitate decision making processes, it is only as defensible as the degree at which the system under consideration behaves linearly. Recent work shows that diverse properties of cities exhibit power-law relationships with population size. Such relationships may invalidate the reliance on linear thinking. Furthermore, in the era of globalization, resources and people move virtually freely through bounds of any confines used to define a system. We incorporate into a simple resource-population model the power-law scaling behavior and the influence of import and immigration, and investigate their effects on sustainable growth of communities. We explore through bifurcation analysis the different scenarios of how an unsustainable system could be sustained. Import can be effective if: the import exceeds a critical level and a critical mass of people populates the system. In contrast, increasing immigration alone can rescue the intrinsically unsustainable system, both directly through people entering the system and indirectly by increasing its harvesting ability, although critical values exist that cause the population to sharply rise or shrink. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000304583200013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="97">
<title>The scaling structure of the global road network</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.170590</url>
<snippet>Because of increasing global urbanization and its immediate consequences, including changes in patterns of food demand, circulation and land use, the next century will witness a major increase in the extent of paved roads built worldwide. To model the effects of this increase, it is crucial to understand whether possible self-organized patterns are inherent in the global road network structure. Here, we use the largest updated database comprising all major roads on the Earth, together with global urban and cropland inventories, to suggest that road length distributions within croplands are indistinguishable from urban ones, once rescaled to account for the difference in mean road length. Such similarity extends to road length distributions within urban or agricultural domains of a given area. We find two distinct regimes for the scaling of the mean road length with the associated area, holding in general at small and at large values of the latter. In suitably large urban and cropland domains, we find that mean and total road lengths increase linearly with their domain area, differently from earlier suggestions. Scaling regimes suggest that simple and universal mechanisms regulate urban and cropland road expansion at the global scale. As such, our findings bear implications for global road infrastructure growth based on land-use change and for planning policies sustaining urban expansions. OI Giometto, Andrea/0000-0002-0544-6023
WOS:000413965600016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="98">
<title>Scaling laws in the dynamics of crime growth rate</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2013.02.002</url>
<snippet>The increasing number of crimes in areas with large concentrations of people have made cities one of the main sources of violence. Understanding characteristics of how crime rate expands and its relations with the cities size goes beyond an academic question, being a central issue for contemporary society. Here, we characterize and analyze quantitative aspects of murders in the period from 1980 to 2009 in Brazilian cities. We find that the distribution of the annual, biannual and triannual logarithmic homicide growth rates exhibit the same functional form for distinct scales, that is, a scale invariant behavior. We also identify asymptotic power-law decay relations between the standard deviations of these three growth rates and the initial size. Further, we discuss similarities with complex organizations. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Ribeiro, Haroldo/C-8614-2012; Alves, Luiz/H-3389-2013; Mendes, Renio/F-9261-2017 OI Ribeiro, Haroldo/0000-0002-9532-5195; Alves, Luiz/0000-0001-6204-5552;
WOS:000317699400006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="99">
<title>WHY URBAN GEOCHEMISTRY?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2113/gselements.8.6.417</url>
<snippet>In a very short period of time, the majority of the human population has become urban, and by 2050 two out of every three people in the world will live in cities. Urban areas are extremely important socially, economically, and culturally, but they also have a profound impact on the environment. In that context, this issue of Elements considers the geochemical significance of 21st-century cities and some of the unprecedented challenges they face.
WOS:000313232200004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="100">
<title>Empirical analysis on the connection between power-law distributions and allometries for urban indicators</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2014.04.046</url>
<snippet>We report on the existing connection between power-law distributions and allometries. As it was first reported in Gomez-Lievano et al. (2012) for the relationship between homicides and population, when these urban indicators present asymptotic power-law distributions, they can also display specific allometries among themselves. Here, we present an extensive characterization of this connection when considering all possible pairs of relationships from twelve urban indicators of Brazilian cities (such as child labor, illiteracy, income, sanitation and unemployment). Our analysis reveals that all our urban indicators are asymptotically distributed as power laws and that the proposed connection also holds for our data when the allometric relationship displays enough correlations. We have also found that not all allometric relationships are independent and that they can be understood as a consequence of the allometric relationship between the urban indicator and the population size. We further show that the residuals fluctuations surrounding the allometries are characterized by an almost constant variance and log-normal distributions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Mendes, Renio/F-9261-2017; Alves, Luiz/H-3389-2013; Ribeiro, Haroldo/C-8614-2012 OI Alves, Luiz/0000-0001-6204-5552; Ribeiro, Haroldo/0000-0002-9532-5195; Lenzi, Ervin/0000-0003-3853-1790
WOS:000338616100020
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="101">
<title>Settlement-Size Scaling among Prehistoric Hunter-Gatherer Settlement Systems in the New World</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0140127</url>
<snippet>Settlement size predicts extreme variation in the rates and magnitudes of many social and ecological processes in human societies. Yet, the factors that drive human settlement-size variation remain poorly understood. Size variation among economically integrated settlements tends to be heavy tailed such that the smallest settlements are extremely common and the largest settlements extremely large and rare. The upper tail of this size distribution is often formalized mathematically as a power-law function. Explanations for this scaling structure in human settlement systems tend to emphasize complex socioeconomic processes including agriculture, manufacturing, and warfare-behaviors that tend to differentially nucleate and disperse populations hierarchically among settlements. But, the degree to which heavy-tailed settlement-size variation requires such complex behaviors remains unclear. By examining the settlement patterns of eight prehistoric New World hunter-gatherer settlement systems spanning three distinct environmental contexts, this analysis explores the degree to which heavy-tailed settlement-size scaling depends on the aforementioned socioeconomic complexities. Surprisingly, the analysis finds that power-law models offer plausible and parsimonious statistical descriptions of prehistoric hunter-gatherer settlement-size variation. This finding reveals that incipient forms of hierarchical settlement structure may have preceded socioeconomic complexity in human societies and points to a need for additional research to explicate how mobile foragers came to exhibit settlement patterns that are more commonly associated with hierarchical organization. We propose that hunter-gatherer mobility with preferential attachment to previously occupied locations may account for the observed structure in site-size variation. OI Haas, Randall/0000-0002-7742-2127
WOS:000364298400017
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="102">
<title>Size rules life, but does it in the assessment of medical vigilance best practice? Towards a testable hypothesis</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2018.03.048</url>
<snippet>The goal of this paper is to infer the applicability of scaling concepts to haemovigilance based on the study of the relationship between severe adverse reactions and events (SARE) and blood transfusions (BT). We hypothesize that in a haemovigilance operating optimally, SARE should be a power-law function of BT as SARE = alpha BT beta. We investigated the relationship between yearly BT and the related SARE reported in 12 French hospitals of the Picardie State from 2004 to 2015. First we found that when integrated over the whole period 2004-2015, SARE were significantly described by a power-law function SARE BT1.51 for 10 of the 12 hospitals considered. The numbers of SARE in these two hospitals is drastically over-estimated by this power-law, that is 1.9- to 4.3-fold lower than those predicted by the power-law. When considered on a yearly basis, we consistently found that SARE was also significantly described by a power-law function of the form SARE alpha BT1.44 for 10 of the 12 hospitals considered. In turn, the occurrence of SARE in the two other hospitals was strongly over-estimated by this power-law, though it is also significantly described by another power-law, SARE alpha BT1.11. We specified these results through separate yearly analyses and found the relationship between SARE and BT was best described by a power law with beta = 0.90 in 2004, a linear relationship from 2005 to 2007 and a power-law with beta ranging from 1.49 and 1.92 from 2008 to 2014. Finally, in 2015, the relationship between SARE and BT was significantly described by a power-law SARE alpha BT1.17 for the 12 hospitals considered. Overall, our results suggest that hospitals performing more blood transfusions are more efficient as the observed negative effects of blood transfusions increase relatively slower than in hospitals performing less transfusions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000437061000062
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="103">
<title>Spatial patterns of dengue cases in Brazil</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0180715</url>
<snippet>Dengue infection plays a central role in our society, since it is the most prevalent vector-borne viral disease affecting humans. We statistically investigated patterns concerning the spatial spreading of dengue epidemics in Brazil, as well as their temporal evolution in all Brazilian municipalities for a period of 12 years. We showed that the distributions of cases in municipalities follow power laws persistent in time and that the infection scales linearly with the population of the municipalities. We also found that the average number of dengue cases does not have a clear dependence on the longitudinal position of municipalities. On the other hand, we found that the average distribution of cases varies with the latitudinal position of municipalities, displaying an almost constant growth from high latitudes until reaching the Tropic of Capricorn leveling to a plateau closer to the Equator. We also characterized the spatial correlation of the number of dengue cases between pairs of municipalities, where our results showed that the spatial correlation function decays with the increase of distance between municipalities, following a power-law with an exponential cut-off. This regime leads to a typical dengue traveling distance. Finally, we considered modeling this last behaviour within the framework of a Edwards-Wilkinson equation with a fractional derivative on space.
WOS:000443975500016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="104">
<title>How Much Is the Whole Really More than the Sum of Its Parts? 1 boxed plus 1=2.5: Superlinear Productivity in Collective Group Actions</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0103023</url>
<snippet>In a variety of open source software projects, we document a superlinear growth of production intensity (R similar to c(beta)) as a function of the number of active developers c, with a median value of the exponent beta similar or equal to 4/3, with large dispersions of beta from slightly less than 1 up to 3. For a typical project in this class, doubling of the group size multiplies typically the output by a factor 2(beta)=2.5, explaining the title. This superlinear law is found to hold for group sizes ranging from 5 to a few hundred developers. We propose two classes of mechanisms, interaction-based and large deviation, along with a cascade model of productive activity, which unifies them. In this common framework, superlinear productivity requires that the involved social groups function at or close to criticality, or in a "superradiance" mode, in the sense of the appearance of a cooperative process and order involving a collective mode of developers defined by the build up of correlation between the contributions of developers. In addition, we report the first empirical test of the renormalization of the exponent of the distribution of the sizes of first generation events into the renormalized exponent of the distribution of clusters resulting from the cascade of triggering over all generation in a critical branching process in the non-meanfield regime. Finally, we document a size effect in the strength and variability of the superlinear effect, with smaller groups exhibiting widely distributed superlinear exponents, some of them characterizing highly productive teams. In contrast, large groups tend to have a smaller superlinearity and less variability.
WOS:000339819800014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="105">
<title>Small cities face greater impact from automation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2017.0946</url>
<snippet>The city has proved to be the most successful form of human agglomeration and provides wide employment opportunities for its dwellers. As advances in robotics and artificial intelligence revive concerns about the impact of automation on jobs, a question looms: how will automation affect employment in cities? Here, we provide a comparative picture of the impact of automation across US urban areas. Small cities will undertake greater adjustments, such as worker displacement and job content substitutions. We demonstrate that large cities exhibit increased occupational and skill specialization due to increased abundance of managerial and technical professions. These occupations are not easily automatable, and, thus, reduce the potential impact of automation in large cities. Our results pass several robustness checks including potential errors in the estimation of occupational automation and subsampling of occupations. Our study provides the first empirical law connecting two societal forces: urban agglomeration and automations impact on employment. OI /0000-0001-9487-9359; Youn, Hyejin/0000-0002-6190-4412; Sun, Lijun/0000-0001-9488-0712
WOS:000426464000019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="106">
<title>Quantifying long-term evolution of intra-urban spatial interactions</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2014.1089</url>
<snippet>Understanding the long-term impact that changes in a city's transportation infrastructure have on its spatial interactions remains a challenge. The difficulty arises from the fact that the real impact may not be revealed in static or aggregated mobility measures, as these are remarkably robust to perturbations. More generally, the lack of longitudinal, cross-sectional data demonstrating the evolution of spatial interactions at a meaningful urban scale also hinders us from evaluating the sensitivity of movement indicators, limiting our capacity to understand the evolution of urban mobility in depth. Using very large mobility records distributed over 3 years, we quantify the impact of the completion of a metro line extension: the Circle Line (CCL) in Singapore. We find that the commonly used movement indicators are almost identical before and after the project was completed. However, in comparing the temporal community structure across years, we do observe significant differences in the spatial reorganization of the affected geographical areas. The completion of CCL enables travellers to re-identify their desired destinations collectively with lower transport cost, making the community structure more consistent. These changes in locality are dynamic and characterized over short timescales, offering us a different approach to identify and analyse the long-term impact of new infrastructures on cities and their evolution dynamics. RI Jin, Jian Gang/G-5636-2012; Sun, Lijun/E-8170-2015; Lee, Der-Horng/H-7080-2012 OI Jin, Jian Gang/0000-0002-8507-1435; Sun, Lijun/0000-0001-9488-0712; Lee, Der-Horng/0000-0001-5428-8810
WOS:000209931100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="107">
<title>Universal scaling laws in metro area election results</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0192913</url>
<snippet>We explain the anomaly of election results between large cities and rural areas in terms of urban scaling in the 1948-2016 US elections and in the 2016 EU referendum of the UK. The scaling curves are all universal and depend on a single parameter only, and one of the parties always shows superlinear scaling and drives the process, while the sublinear exponent of the other party is merely the consequence of probability conservation. Based on the recently developed model of urban scaling, we give a microscopic model of voter behavior in which we replace diversity characterizing humans in creative aspects with social diversity and tolerance. The model can also predict new political developments such as the fragmentation of the left and the immigration paradox. OI Szallasi, Zoltan/0000-0001-5395-7509
WOS:000425831000022
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="108">
<title>Great cities look small</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2015.0315</url>
<snippet>Great cities connect people; failed cities isolate people. Despite the fundamental importance of physical, face-to-face social ties in the functioning of cities, these connectivity networks are not explicitly observed in their entirety. Attempts at estimating them often rely on unrealistic over-simplifications such as the assumption of spatial homogeneity. Here we propose a mathematical model of human interactions in terms of a local strategy of maximizing the number of beneficial connections attainable under the constraint of limited individual travelling-time budgets. By incorporating census and openly available online multi-modal transport data, we are able to characterize the connectivity of geometrically and topologically complex cities. Beyond providing a candidate measure of greatness, this model allows one to quantify and assess the impact of transport developments, population growth, and other infrastructure and demographic changes on a city. Supported by validations of gross domestic product and human immunodeficiency virus infection rates across US metropolitan areas, we illustrate the effect of changes in local and city-wide connectivities by considering the economic impact of two contemporary inter- and intra-city transport developments in the UK: High Speed 2 and London Crossrail. This derivation of the model suggests that the scaling of different urban indicators with population size has an explicitly mechanistic origin. RI Barahona, Mauricio/C-3638-2008 OI Barahona, Mauricio/0000-0002-1089-5675
WOS:000361084200013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="109">
<title>The size distribution of employment centers within the US Metropolitan Areas</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1068/b39038</url>
<snippet>This study tackles the description of the size distribution of urban employment centers or, in other words, the size of areas within cities with significantly high densities of workers. Certainly, there exists a branch of urban economics that has paid substantial attention to urban employment centers, but the efforts have been focused on identification methodologies. In this paper we build on such body of research and combine it with insights from the latest contributions in the sister subfield of city size distributions to push the agenda forward in terms of the understanding of these phenomena. We consider the 359 Metropolitan Statistical Areas (MSAs) in the United States in the year 2000 and reach three main conclusions: first, employment center sizes are more unevenly distributed than city sizes; second, the two functions that best describe city size distributions, namely the lognormal and the double Pareto-lognormal, also offer a good fit for the case of centers, particularly the latter; and third, several interesting statistically significant relationships (correlations) between variables related to centers and MSAs are deduced. Further experiments with a different technique of center identification suggest that the results are fairly robust to the method of choice. RI Ramos, Arturo/E-5745-2015 OI Ramos, Arturo/0000-0003-2618-1535; Sanz Gracia, Fernando/0000-0003-3725-0022
WOS:000352382900003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="110">
<title>Comparing and modelling land use organization in cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.150449</url>
<snippet>The advent of geolocated information and communication technologies opens the possibility of exploring how people use space in cities, bringing an important new tool for urban scientists and planners, especially for regions where data are scarce or not available. Here we apply a functional network approach to determine land use patterns from mobile phone records. The versatility of the method allows us to run a systematic comparison between Spanish cities of various sizes. The method detects four major land use types that correspond to different temporal patterns. The proportion of these types, their spatial organization and scaling show a strong similarity between all cities that breaks down at a very local scale, where land use mixing is specific to each urban area. Finally, we introduce a model inspired by Schellings segregation, able to explain and reproduce these results with simple interaction rules between different land uses. RI San Miguel, Maxi/G-3224-2015; Ramasco, Jose J/F-2860-2010 OI San Miguel, Maxi/0000-0001-6237-425X; Ramasco, Jose J/0000-0003-2499-6095; Louail, Thomas/0000-0001-8563-6881
WOS:000377968100014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="111">
<title>Modeling Network Growth with Scaling Laws in a Linear Monocentric City</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3141/2466-15</url>
<snippet>Scaling relationships have been observed across urban systems and appear to reveal global emergent properties that may help to characterize, understand, and predict urban growth. Empirical urban studies that show scaling laws relating the growth in population to that of the transportation network warrant theoretical investigation. Such scaling phenomena are considered in the context of a linear monocentric city. Commuters are distributed from the city boundary to the common destination (the central business district), and two modes (railway and car) are available along the corridor. Two scenarios of urban growth are considered: vertical and horizontal. Road capacity and corridor length both increase alongside the population growth. Within these scenarios, growth is constrained to follow a scaling law and the evolution of network performance is examined. The results suggest that different long-term evolution trajectories may exist depending on the scaling-law and network features. On this basis, theoretical limits need to be investigated on the possible evolutionary pathways for a city whose growth is dependent on its transport system.
WOS:000352118300016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="112">
<title>Spatial analysis of the Surface Urban Heat Island</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/12.2501441</url>
<snippet>In this paper, we present a novel framework to characterize the complex spatial structure of the intra-urban heat island. Cities are known to be warmer than its surrounding areas because of the Urban Heat Island (UHI) phenomenon. However, due to the diverse and complex spatial geometries of cities themselves, the temperatures within vary widely. We take advantage of the well-established notion of fractal properties of cities, to characterize the complex structure of these hotspots. As a demonstrative case study, Land Surface Temperatures (LST) for Atlanta, GA, derived from Landsat 8 is used. From clustering analysis at multiple thermal thresholds, we show that the hotspots can be described as a case of percolating clusters. By comparing the area-perimeter fractal dimension at these thresholds, we find these clusters to be statistically self-similar. Furthermore, at the percolation threshold, the cluster size distribution is found to follow a power-law size distribution; and at a higher threshold, deviation from the power law is observed in the form of exponential tempering. We argue that the spatial distribution of the hotspots itself plays a significant role in the overall UHI and fractal analysis techniques lend themselves aptly to the characterization of the same. This has several further applications, such as targeted heat mitigation, assessment of health impacts, and energy load estimation.
WOS:000455185200002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="113">
<title>The light pollution as a surrogate for urban population of the US cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2017.11.039</url>
<snippet>We show that the definition of the city boundaries can have a dramatic influence on the scaling behavior of the night-time light (NTL) as a function of population (POP) in the US. Precisely, our results show that the arbitrary geopolitical definition based on the Metropolitan/Consolidated Metropolitan Statistical Areas (MSA/CMSA) leads to a sublinear power-law growth of NTL with POP. On the other hand, when cities are defined according to a more natural agglomeration criteria, namely, the City Clustering Algorithm (CCA), an isometric relation emerges between NTL and population. This discrepancy is compatible with results from previous works showing that the scaling behaviors of various urban indicators with population can be substantially different for distinct definitions of city boundaries. Moreover, considering the CCA definition as more adequate than the MSA/CMSA one because the former does not violate the expected extensivity between land population and area of their generated clusters, we conclude that, without loss of generality, the CCA measures of light pollution and population could be interchangeably utilized in future studies. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved. RI Andrade, Jose/C-5451-2013; Carmona, Humberto/L-4967-2016; Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/J-4630-2016 OI Andrade, Jose/0000-0002-5571-7610; Carmona, Humberto/0000-0002-7505-6717; Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/0000-0002-9247-6780
WOS:000423495100090
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="114">
<title>Network Structure and City Size</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0029721</url>
<snippet>Network structure varies across cities. This variation may yield important knowledge about how the internal structure of the city affects its performance. This paper systematically compares a set of surface transportation network structure variables (connectivity, hierarchy, circuity, treeness, entropy, accessibility) across the 50 largest metropolitan areas in the United States. A set of scaling parameters are discovered to show how network size and structure vary with city size. These results suggest that larger cities are physically more inter-connected. Hypotheses are presented as to why this might obtain. This paper then consistently measures and ranks access to jobs across 50 US metropolitan areas. It uses that accessibility measure, along with network structure variables and city size to help explain journey-to-work time and auto mode share in those cities. A 1 percent increase in accessibility reduces average metropolitan commute times by about 90 seconds each way. A 1 percent increase in network connectivity reduces commute time by 0.1 percent. A 1 percent increase in accessibility results in a 0.0575 percent drop in auto mode share, while a 1 percent increase in treeness reduces auto mode share by 0.061 percent. Use of accessibility and network structure measures is important for planning and evaluating the performance of network investments and land use changes. RI Levinson, David/A-8554-2012 OI Levinson, David/0000-0002-4563-2963
WOS:000301357100019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="115">
<title>Urban Scaling of Football Followership on Twitter</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Social sciences have an important challenge today to take advantage of new research opportunities provided by large amounts of data generated by online social networks. Because of its marketing value, sports clubs are also motivated in creating and maintaining a stable audience in social media. In this paper, we analyze followers of prominent footballs clubs on Twitter by obtaining their home locations. We then measure how city size is connected to the number of followers using the theory of urban scaling. The results show that the scaling exponents of club followers depend on the income of a country. These findings could be used to understand the structure and potential growth areas of global football audiences.
WOS:000449055300014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="116">
<title>Population-Area Relationship for Medieval European Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0162678</url>
<snippet>Medieval European urbanization presents a line of continuity between earlier cities and modern European urban systems. Yet, many of the spatial, political and economic features of medieval European cities were particular to the Middle Ages, and subsequently changed over the Early Modern Period and Industrial Revolution. There is a long tradition of demographic studies estimating the population sizes of medieval European cities, and comparative analyses of these data have shed much light on the long-term evolution of urban systems. However, the next step-to systematically relate the population size of these cities to their spatial and socioeconomic characteristics-has seldom been taken. This raises a series of interesting questions, as both modern and ancient cities have been observed to obey area-population relationships predicted by settlement scaling theory. To address these questions, we analyze a new dataset for the settled area and population of 173 European cities from the early fourteenth century to determine the relationship between population and settled area. To interpret this data, we develop two related models that lead to differing predictions regarding the quantitative form of the population-area relationship, depending on the level of social mixing present in these cities. Our empirical estimates of model parameters show a strong densification of cities with city population size, consistent with patterns in contemporary cities. Although social life in medieval Europe was orchestrated by hierarchical institutions (e.g., guilds, church, municipal organizations), our results show no statistically significant influence of these institutions on agglomeration effects. The similarities between the empirical patterns of settlement relating area to population observed here support the hypothesis that cities throughout history share common principles of organization that self-consistently relate their socioeconomic networks to structured urban spaces. OI Cesaretti, Rudolf/0000-0002-7003-1211
WOS:000385697200019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="117">
<title>Irrigated areas grow faster than the population</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/eap.1743</url>
<snippet>Unfolding regularities between population and irrigated agriculture might increase our capacity to predict their coevolution and better ensure food security and environmental welfare. Here I use three different data sets with detailed information at the national level for similar to 70&#37; of the countries of Africa, Asia, the Americas, and Europe between 1950 and 2017 to show that irrigated areas might grow disproportionally for a given increase in population, e.g., with beta &gt; 1. The results are robust across continents, time series, population cut-offs, and variations in the area accounted for irrigation by official institutions and independent scholars. This systematic pattern suggests the existence of an underlying law driving the growth rate of irrigated areas that transcends local particularities and can be well approximated by a power function of population, specially in the case of the Americas, Asia, and Europe. Nonlinearities derived from the open-ended growth rate of irrigated areas should be taken into consideration when designing irrigation policies in order to avoid unexpected environmental costs. OI Puy, Arnald/0000-0001-9469-2156
WOS:000443555100003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="118">
<title>An Allometric Algorithm for Fractal-Based Cobb-Douglas Function of Geographical Systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/910457</url>
<snippet>The generalized Cobb-Douglas production function has been derived from a general input-output relation based on fractality assumptions. It was proved to be a useful self-affine model for geographical analysis. However, the ordinary least square calculation is always an ineffectual method for the Cobb-Douglas modeling because of the multicollinearity in the logarithmic linear regression. In this paper, a novel approach is proposed to build the geographical Cobb-Douglas models. Combining the concept of allometric scaling with the linear regression technique, we obtain a simple algorithm that can be employed to estimate the parameters of the Cobb-Douglas function. As a case, the algorithm and models are applied to the public transportation of Chinas cities, and the results validate the allometric algorithm. A conclusion can be drawn that the allometric analysis is an effective way of modeling geographical systems with the general Cobb-Douglas function. This study is significant for integrating the notions of allometry, fractals, and scaling into a new framework to form a quantitative methodology of spatial analysis.
WOS:000345022000001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="119">
<title>A Visual Analytics Approach for Extracting Spatio-Temporal Urban Mobility Information from Mobile Network Traffic</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi1030256</url>
<snippet>In this paper we present a visual analytics approach for deriving spatio-temporal patterns of collective human mobility from a vast mobile network traffic data set. More than 88 million movements between pairs of radio cells-so-called handovers-served as a proxy for more than two months of mobility within four urban test areas in Northern Italy. In contrast to previous work, our approach relies entirely on visualization and mapping techniques, implemented in several software applications. We purposefully avoid statistical or probabilistic modeling and, nonetheless, reveal characteristic and exceptional mobility patterns. The results show, for example, surprising similarities and symmetries amongst the total mobility and people flows between the test areas. Moreover, the exceptional patterns detected can be associated to real-world events such as soccer matches. We conclude that the visual analytics approach presented can shed new light on large-scale collective urban mobility behavior and thus helps to better understand the "pulse" of dynamic urban systems.
WOS:000209465500003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="120">
<title>A worldwide model for boundaries of urban settlements</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.180468</url>
<snippet>The shape of urban settlements plays a fundamental role in their sustainable planning. Properly defining the boundaries of cities is challenging and remains an open problem in the science of cities. Here, we propose a worldwide model to define urban settlements beyond their administrative boundaries through a bottom-up approach that takes into account geographical biases intrinsically associated with most societies around the world, and reflected in their different regional growing dynamics. The generality of the model allows one to study the scaling laws of cities at all geographical levels: countries, continents and the entire world. Our definition of cities is robust and holds to one of the most famous results in social sciences: Zipfs law. According to our results, the largest cities in the world are not in line with what was recently reported by the United Nations. For example, we find that the largest city in the world is an agglomeration of several small settlements close to each other, connecting three large settlements: Alexandria, Cairo and Luxor. Our definition of cities opens the doors to the study of the economy of cities in a systematic way independently of arbitrary definitions that employ administrative boundaries. RI Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/J-4630-2016; Andrade, Jose/C-5451-2013 OI Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/0000-0002-9247-6780; Andrade, Jose/0000-0002-5571-7610
WOS:000433498000124
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="121">
<title>Unveiling relationships between crime and property in England and Wales via density scale-adjusted metrics and network tools</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0192931</url>
<snippet>Scale-adjusted metrics (SAMs) are a significant achievement of the urban scaling hypothesis. SAMs remove the inherent biases of per capita measures computed in the absence of isometric allometries. However, this approach is limited to urban areas, while a large portion of the worlds population still lives outside cities and rural areas dominate land use worldwide. Here, we extend the concept of SAMs to population density scale-adjusted metrics (DSAMs) to reveal relationships among different types of crime and property metrics. Our approach allows all human environments to be considered, avoids problems in the definition of urban areas, and accounts for the heterogeneity of population distributions within urban regions. By combining DSAMs, cross-correlation, and complex network analysis, we find that crime and property types have intricate and hierarchically organized relationships leading to some striking conclusions. Drugs and burglary had uncorrelated DSAMs and, to the extent property transaction values are indicators of affluence, twelve out of fourteen crime metrics showed no evidence of specifically targeting affluence. Burglary and robbery were the most connected in our network analysis and the modular structures suggest an alternative to "zero-tolerance" policies by unveiling the crime and/or property types most likely to affect each other. RI Ribeiro, Haroldo/C-8614-2012 OI Ribeiro, Haroldo/0000-0002-9532-5195; Hanley, Quentin/0000-0002-8189-9550
WOS:000425831000023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="122">
<title>What if fertility decline is not permanent? The need for an evolutionarily informed approach to understanding low fertility</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2015.0157</url>
<snippet>Demographic transition theory assumes that fertility decline is irreversible. This commonly held assumption is based on observations of recent and historical reductions in fertility that accompany modernization and declining mortality. The irreversibility assumption, however, is highly suspect from an evolutionary point of view, because demographic traits are at least partially influenced by genetics and are responsive to social and ecological conditions. Nonetheless, an inevitable shift from high mortality and fertility to low mortality and fertility is used as a guiding framework for projecting human population sizes into the future. This paper reviews some theoretical and empirical evidence suggesting that the assumption of irreversibility is ill-founded, at least without considerable development in theory that incorporates evolutionary and ecological processes. We offer general propositions for how fertility could increase in the future, including natural selection on high fertility variants, the difficulty of maintaining universal norms and preferences in a large, diverse and economically differentiated population, and the escalating resource demands of modernization. OI DeLong, John/0000-0003-0558-8213
WOS:000374921700014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="123">
<title>Towards knowledge ecosystems: Modelling knowledge dynamics in environmental systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.procs.2014.08.179</url>
<snippet>In order to understand basic mechanisms of so-called Knowledge Ecosystems, the paper presents a study for modelling the emergence and diffusion of knowledge in regards to environmental conditions. The text gives an outline for the description of Knowledge Ecosystems by integrating 1) models for environmental dynamics based on resources and attractiveness, and 2) models for knowledge dynamics based on the behaviors and processes of knowledge agents (innovators) and agencies. As key methods, the work employs Cellular Automata for the modelling of knowledge environments, as well as agent models for the simulation of knowledge agents (innovators). The paper presents preliminary results of the ongoing study, including a first version of both scopes integrated into one descriptive system. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.
WOS:000345394100144
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="124">
<title>Recursive subdivision of urban space and Zipf's law</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2013.10.022</url>
<snippet>Zipfs law can be used to describe the rank-size distribution of cities in a region. It has seldom been employed to research urban internal structure. In this paper, we demonstrate that the space-filling process within a city follows Zipfs law and can be characterized with the rank-size rule. A model of spatial disaggregation of urban space is presented to depict the spatial regularity of urban growth. By recursive subdivision of space, an urban region can be geometrically divided into two parts, four parts, eight parts, and so on, and form a hierarchy with cascade structure. If we rank these parts by size, the portions will conform to the Zipf distribution. By means of the GIS technique and remote sensing data, the model of recursive subdivision of urban space is applied to three cities in China. The results show that the intra-urban hierarchy complies with Zipfs law, and the values of the rank-size scaling exponent are very close to 1. The significance of this study lies in three aspects. First, it shows that the strict subdivision of space is an efficient approach to revealing spatial order of urban form. Second, it discloses the relationships between the urban space-filling process and the rank-size rule. Third, it suggests a new way of understanding fractals, Zipfs law, and spatial organization of urban evolution. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000329881800038
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="125">
<title>Misery loves company: happiness and communication in the city</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjds/s13688-015-0044-2</url>
<snippet>The high population density in cities confers many advantages, including improved social interaction and information exchange. However, it is often argued that urban living comes at the expense of reducing happiness. The goal of this research is to shed light on the relationship between urban communication and urban happiness. We analyze geo-located social media posts (tweets) within a major urban center (Milan) to produce a detailed spatial map of urban sentiments. We combine this data with high-resolution mobile communication intensity data among different urban areas. Our results reveal that happy (respectively unhappy) areas preferentially communicate with other areas of their type. This observation constitutes evidence of homophilous communities at the scale of an entire city (Milan), and has implications on interventions that aim to improve urban well-being. OI Alshamsi, Aamena/0000-0001-6846-4627
WOS:000368069900007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="126">
<title>Urbanism and the division of labour in the Roman Empire</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2017.0367</url>
<snippet>One of the hallmarks of human agglomeration is an increase in the division of labour, but the exact nature of this relationship has been debated among anthropologists, sociologists, economists, and historians and archaeologists. Over the last decade, researchers investigating contemporary urban systems have suggested a novel explanation for the links between the numbers of inhabitants in settlements and many of their most important characteristics, which is grounded in a view of settlements as social networks embedded in built environments. One of the remarkable aspects of this approach is that it is not based on the specific conditions of the modern world (such as capitalism or industrialization), which raises the issue of whether the relationships observed in contemporary urban systems can also be detected in pre-modern urban or even non-urban systems. Here, we present a general model for the relationship between the population and functional diversity of settlements, where the latter is viewed as an indicator of the division of labour. We then explore the applicability of this model to pre-modern contexts, focusing on cities in the Roman Empire, using estimates of their numbers of inhabitants, numbers of documented professional associations, and numbers of recorded inscriptions to develop an index of functional diversity. Our results are consistent with theoretical expectations, adding further support to the view that urban systems in both contemporary and pre-modern contexts reflect a common set of generative processes.
WOS:000416598500002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="127">
<title>Mining large-scale human mobility data for long-term crime prediction</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjds/s13688-018-0150-z</url>
<snippet>Traditional crime prediction models based on census data are limited, as they fail to capture the complexity and dynamics of human activity. With the rise of ubiquitous computing, there is the opportunity to improve such models with data that make for better proxies of human presence in cities. In this paper, we leverage large human mobility data to craft an extensive set of features for crime prediction, as informed by theories in criminology and urban studies. We employ averaging and boosting ensemble techniques from machine learning, to investigate their power in predicting yearly counts for different types of crimes occurring in New York City at census tract level. Our study shows that spatial and spatio-temporal features derived from Foursquare venues and checkins, subway rides, and taxi rides, improve the baseline models relying on census and POI data. The proposed models achieve absolute R-2 metrics of up to 65&#37; (on a geographical out-of-sample test set) and up to 89&#37; (on a temporal out-of-sample test set). This proves that, next to the residential population of an area, the ambient population there is strongly predictive of the areas crime levels. We deep-dive into the main crime categories, and find that the predictive gain of the human dynamics features varies across crime types: such features bring the biggest boost in case of grand larcenies, whereas assaults are already well predicted by the census features. Furthermore, we identify and discuss top predictive features for the main crime categories. These results offer valuable insights for those responsible for urban policy or law enforcement. OI Kadar, Cristina/0000-0002-2413-1174
WOS:000440101900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="128">
<title>Languages cool as they expand: Allometric scaling and the decreasing need for new words</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep00943</url>
<snippet>We analyze the occurrence frequencies of over 15 million words recorded in millions of books published during the past two centuries in seven different languages. For all languages and chronological subsets of the data we confirm that two scaling regimes characterize the word frequency distributions, with only the more common words obeying the classic Zipf law. Using corpora of unprecedented size, we test the allometric scaling relation between the corpus size and the vocabulary size of growing languages to demonstrate a decreasing marginal need for new words, a feature that is likely related to the underlying correlations between words. We calculate the annual growth fluctuations of word use which has a decreasing trend as the corpus size increases, indicating a slowdown in linguistic evolution following language expansion. This "cooling pattern" forms the basis of a third statistical regularity, which unlike the Zipf and the Heaps law, is dynamical in nature. RI Petersen, Alexander/D-9243-2012; Perc, Matjaz/A-5148-2009 OI Petersen, Alexander/0000-0002-0955-3483; Perc, Matjaz/0000-0002-3087-541X
WOS:000312273400002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="129">
<title>How does public opinion become extreme?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep10032</url>
<snippet>We investigate the emergence of extreme opinion trends in society by employing statistical physics modeling and analysis on polls that inquire about a wide range of issues such as religion, economics, politics, abortion, extramarital sex, books, movies, and electoral vote. The surveys lay out a clear indicator of the rise of extreme views. The precursor is a nonlinear relation between the fraction of individuals holding a certain extreme view and the fraction of individuals that includes also moderates, e.g., in politics, those who are "very conservative" versus "moderate to very conservative" ones. We propose an activation model of opinion dynamics with interaction rules based on the existence of individual "stubbornness" that mimics empirical observations. According to our modeling, the onset of nonlinearity can be associated to an abrupt bootstrap-percolation transition with cascades of extreme views through society. Therefore, it represents an early-warning signal to forecast the transition from moderate to extreme views. Moreover, by means of a phase diagram we can classify societies according to the percolative regime they belong to, in terms of critical fractions of extremists and peoples ties. RI Reis, Saulo/E-4154-2013; Andrade, Jose/C-5451-2013; UFC, DF/E-1564-2017; Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/J-4630-2016; Anteneodo, Celia/C-7179-2013 OI Andrade, Jose/0000-0002-5571-7610; Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/0000-0002-9247-6780; Anteneodo, Celia/0000-0001-9130-2933
WOS:000355294100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="130">
<title>A model of urban scaling laws based on distance-dependent interactions</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.160926</url>
<snippet>Socio-economic related properties of a city grow faster than a linear relationship with the population, in a log-log plot, the so-called superlinear scaling. Conversely, the larger a city, the more efficient it is in the use of its infrastructure, leading to a sublinear scaling on these variables. In this work, we addressed a simple explanation for those scaling laws in cities based on the interaction range between the citizens and on the fractal properties of the cities. To this purpose, we introduced a measure of social potential which captured the influence of social interaction on the economic performance and the benefits of amenities in the case of infrastructure offered by the city. We assumed that the population density depends on the fractal dimension and on the distance-dependent interactions between individuals. The model suggests that when the city interacts as a whole, and not just as a set of isolated parts, there is improvement of the socio-economic indicators. Moreover, the bigger the interaction range between citizens and amenities, the bigger the improvement of the socio-economic indicators and the lower the infrastructure costs of the city. We addressed how public policies could take advantage of these properties to improve cities development, minimizing negative effects. Furthermore, the model predicts that the sum of the scaling exponents of social-economic and infrastructure variables are 2, as observed in the literature. Simulations with an agent-based model are confronted with the theoretical approach and they are compatible with the empirical evidences. RI Ribeiro, Fabiano/G-9519-2014; Rodrigues Neto, Camilo/C-9126-2011 OI Rodrigues Neto, Camilo/0000-0001-6783-6695; Meirelles de Miranda, Joao Vitor/0000-0001-5951-1284
WOS:000398107700032
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="131">
<title>The Non-linear Health Consequences of Living in Larger Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11524-015-9976-x</url>
<snippet>Urbanization promotes economy, mobility, access, and availability of resources, but on the other hand, generates higher levels of pollution, violence, crime, and mental distress. The health consequences of the agglomeration of people living close together are not fully understood. Particularly, it remains unclear how variations in the population size across cities impact the health of the population. We analyze the deviations from linearity of the scaling of several health-related quantities, such as the incidence and mortality of diseases, external causes of death, wellbeing, and health care availability, in respect to the population size of cities in Brazil, Sweden, and the USA. We find that deaths by non-communicable diseases tend to be relatively less common in larger cities, whereas the per capita incidence of infectious diseases is relatively larger for increasing population size. Healthier lifestyle and availability of medical support are disproportionally higher in larger cities. The results are connected with the optimization of human and physical resources and with the non-linear effects of social networks in larger populations. An urban advantage in terms of health is not evident, and using rates as indicators to compare cities with different population sizes may be insufficient. OI Correa Rocha, Luis Enrique/0000-0001-9046-8739; Lambiotte, Renaud/0000-0002-0583-4595
WOS:000363252400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="132">
<title>Scale-Adjusted Metrics for Predicting the Evolution of Urban Indicators and Quantifying the Performance of Cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0134862</url>
<snippet>More than a half of world population is now living in cities and this number is expected to be two-thirds by 2050. Fostered by the relevancy of a scientific characterization of cities and for the availability of an unprecedented amount of data, academics have recently immersed in this topic and one of the most striking and universal finding was the discovery of robust allometric scaling laws between several urban indicators and the population size. Despite that, most governmental reports and several academic works still ignore these nonlinearities by often analyzing the raw or the per capita value of urban indicators, a practice that actually makes the urban metrics biased towards small or large cities depending on whether we have super or sublinear allometries. By following the ideas of Bettencourt et al. [PLoS ONE 5 (2010) e13541], we account for this bias by evaluating the difference between the actual value of an urban indicator and the value expected by the allometry with the population size. We show that this scale-adjusted metric provides a more appropriate/informative summary of the evolution of urban indicators and reveals patterns that do not appear in the evolution of per capita values of indicators obtained from Brazilian cities. We also show that these scale-adjusted metrics are strongly correlated with their past values by a linear correspondence and that they also display crosscorrelations among themselves. Simple linear models account for 31&#37;-97&#37; of the observed variance in data and correctly reproduce the average of the scale-adjusted metric when grouping the cities in above and below the allometric laws. We further employ these models to forecast future values of urban indicators and, by visualizing the predicted changes, we verify the emergence of spatial clusters characterized by regions of the Brazilian territory where we expect an increase or a decrease in the values of urban indicators. RI Mendes, Renio/F-9261-2017; Ribeiro, Haroldo/C-8614-2012; Alves, Luiz/H-3389-2013 OI Ribeiro, Haroldo/0000-0002-9532-5195; Alves, Luiz/0000-0001-6204-5552; Lenzi, Ervin/0000-0003-3853-1790
WOS:000360965800002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="133">
<title>The angular nature of road networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-017-04477-z</url>
<snippet>Road networks are characterised by several structural and geometrical properties. The topological structure determines partially the hierarchical arrangement of roads, but since these are networks that are spatially constrained, geometrical properties play a fundamental role in determining the networks behaviour, characterising the influence of each of the street segments on the system. In this work, we apply percolation theory to the UKs road network using the relative angle between street segments as the occupation probability. The appearance of the spanning cluster is marked by a phase transition, indicating that the system behaves in a critical way. Computing Shannons entropy of the cluster sizes, different stages of the percolation process can be discerned, and these indicate that roads integrate to the giant cluster in a hierarchical manner. This is used to construct a hierarchical index that serves to classify roads in terms of their importance. The obtained classification is in very good correspondence with the official designations of roads. This methodology hence provides a framework to consistently extract the main skeleton of an urban system and to further classify each road in terms of its hierarchical importance within the system.
WOS:000404126500052
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="134">
<title>On the problem of boundaries and scaling for urban street networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2015.0763</url>
<snippet>Urban morphology has presented significant intellectual challenges to mathematicians and physicists ever since the eighteenth century, when Euler first explored the famous Konigsberg bridges problem. Many important regularities and scaling laws have been observed in urban studies, including Zipfs law and Gibrats law, rendering cities attractive systems for analysis within statistical physics. Nevertheless, a broad consensus on how cities and their boundaries are defined is still lacking. Applying an elementary clustering technique to the street intersection space, we show that growth curves for the maximum cluster size of the largest cities in the UK and in California collapse to a single curve, namely the logistic. Subsequently, by introducing the concept of the condensation threshold, we show that natural boundaries of cities can be well defined in a universal way. This allows us to study and discuss systematically some of the regularities that are present in cities. We show that some scaling laws present consistent behaviour in space and time, thus suggesting the presence of common principles at the basis of the evolution of urban systems. OI MASUCCI, ARMANDO/0000-0001-6633-4239
WOS:000363487600029
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="135">
<title>Major transitions in information technology</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2015.0450</url>
<snippet>When looking at the history of technology, we can see that all inventions are not of equal importance. Only a few technologies have the potential to start a new branching series (specifically, by increasing diversity), have a lasting impact in human life and ultimately became turning points. Technological transitions correspond to times and places in the past when a large number of novel artefact forms or behaviours appeared together or in rapid succession. Why does that happen? Is technological change continuous and gradual or does it occur in sudden leaps and bounds? The evolution of information technology (IT) allows for a quantitative and theoretical approach to technological transitions. The value of information systems experiences sudden changes (i) when we learn how to use this technology, (ii) when we accumulate a large amount of information, and (iii) when communities of practice create and exchange free information. The coexistence between gradual improvements and discontinuous technological change is a consequence of the asymmetric relationship between complexity and hardware and software. Using a cultural evolution approach, we suggest that sudden changes in the organization of ITs depend on the high costs of maintaining and transmitting reliable information. This article is part of the themed issue 'The major synthetic evolutionary transitions'.
WOS:000384460600012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="136">
<title>Settlement scaling and increasing returns in an ancient society</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.1400066</url>
<snippet>A key property of modern cities is increasing returns to scale-the finding that many socioeconomic outputs increase more rapidly than their population size. Recent theoretical work proposes that this phenomenon is the result of general network effects typical of human social networks embedded in space and, thus, is not necessarily limited to modern settlements. We examine the extent to which increasing returns are apparent in archaeological settlement data from the pre-Hispanic Basin of Mexico. We review previous work on the quantitative relationship between population size and average settled area in this society and then present a general analysis of their patterns of monument construction and house sizes. Estimated scaling parameter values and residual statistics support the hypothesis that increasing returns to scale characterized various forms of socioeconomic production available in the archaeological record and are found to be consistent with key expectations from settlement scaling theory. As a consequence, these results provide evidence that the essential processes that lead to increasing returns in contemporary cities may have characterized human settlements throughout history, and demonstrate that increasing returns do not require modern forms of political or economic organization. OI ORTMAN, SCOTT/0000-0003-0709-5287
WOS:000216590300006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="137">
<title>Collective behavior in the spatial spreading of obesity</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep00454</url>
<snippet>Obesity prevalence is increasing in many countries at alarming levels. A difficulty in the conception of policies to reverse these trends is the identification of the drivers behind the obesity epidemics. Here, we implement a spatial spreading analysis to investigate whether obesity shows spatial correlations, revealing the effect of collective and global factors acting above individual choices. We find a regularity in the spatial fluctuations of their prevalence revealed by a pattern of scale-free long-range correlations. The fluctuations are anomalous, deviating in a fundamental way from the weaker correlations found in the underlying population distribution indicating the presence of collective behavior, i.e., individual habits may have negligible influence in shaping the patterns of spreading. Interestingly, we find the same scale-free correlations in economic activities associated with food production. These results motivate future interventions to investigate the causality of this relation providing guidance for the implementation of preventive health policies. OI Gallos, Lazaros/0000-0002-2713-7934
WOS:000305798200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="138">
<title>Evolution of urban scaling: Evidence from Brazil</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0204574</url>
<snippet>During the last years, the new science of cities has been established as a fertile quantitative approach to systematically understand the urban phenomena. One of its main pillars is the proposition that urban systems display universal scaling behavior regarding socioeconomic, infrastructural and individual basic services variables. This paper discusses the extension of the universality proposition by testing it against a broad range of urban metrics in a developing country urban system. We present an exploration of the scaling exponents for over 60 variables for the Brazilian urban system. Estimating those exponents is challenging from the technical point of view because the Brazilian municipalities definition follows local political criteria and does not regard characteristics of the landscape, density, and basic utilities. As Brazilian municipalities can deviate significantly from urban settlements, urban-like municipalities were selected based on a systematic density cut-off procedure and the scaling exponents were estimated for this new subset of municipalities. To validate our findings we compared the results for overlaying variables with other studies based on alternative methods. It was found that the analyzed socioeconomic variables follow a superlinear scaling relationship with the population size, and most of the infrastructure and individual basic services variables follow expected sublinear and linearscaling, respectively. However, some infrastructural and individual basic services variables deviated from their expected regimes, challenging the universality hypothesis of urban scaling. We propose that these deviations are a product of top-down decisions/policies. Our analysis spreads over a time-range of 10 years, what is not enough to draw conclusive observations, nevertheless we found hints that the scaling exponent of these variables are evolving towards the expected scaling regime, indicating that the deviations might be temporally constrained and that the urban systems might eventually reach the expected scaling regime. RI Ribeiro, Fabiano/G-9519-2014 OI Meirelles de Miranda, Joao Vitor/0000-0001-5951-1284; Rodrigues Neto, Camilo/0000-0001-6783-6695
WOS:000446383500025
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="139">
<title>The Statistics of Urban Scaling and Their Connection to Zipf's Law</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0040393</url>
<snippet>Urban scaling relations characterizing how diverse properties of cities vary on average with their population size have recently been shown to be a general quantitative property of many urban systems around the world. However, in previous studies the statistics of urban indicators were not analyzed in detail, raising important questions about the full characterization of urban properties and how scaling relations may emerge in these larger contexts. Here, we build a self-consistent statistical framework that characterizes the joint probability distributions of urban indicators and city population sizes across an urban system. To develop this framework empirically we use one of the most granular and stochastic urban indicators available, specifically measuring homicides in cities of Brazil, Colombia and Mexico, three nations with high and fast changing rates of violent crime. We use these data to derive the conditional probability of the number of homicides per year given the population size of a city. To do this we use Bayes rule together with the estimated conditional probability of city size given their number of homicides and the distribution of total homicides. We then show that scaling laws emerge as expectation values of these conditional statistics. Knowledge of these distributions implies, in turn, a relationship between scaling and population size distribution exponents that can be used to predict Zipfs exponent from urban indicator statistics. Our results also suggest how a general statistical theory of urban indicators may be constructed from the stochastic dynamics of social interaction processes in cities. OI Youn, Hyejin/0000-0002-6190-4412
WOS:000306548900023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="140">
<title>Population patterns in World's administrative units</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.170281</url>
<snippet>Whereas there has been an extended discussion concerning city population distribution, little has been said about that of administrative divisions. In this work, we investigate the population distribution of second-level administrative units of 150 countries and territories and propose the discrete generalized beta distribution (DGBD) rank-size function to describe the data. After testing the balance between the goodness of fit and number of parameters of this function compared with a power law, which is the most common model for city population, the DGBD is a good statistical model for 96&#37; of our datasets and preferred over a power law in almost every case. Moreover, the DGBD is preferred over a power law for fitting country population data, which can be seen as the zeroth-level administrative unit. We present a computational toymodel to simulate the formation of administrative divisions in one dimension and give numerical evidence that the DGBD arises from a particular case of this model. This model, along with the fitting of the DGBD, proves adequate in reproducing and describing local unit evolution and its effect on the population distribution. OI Li, Wentian/0000-0003-1155-110X
WOS:000406670000045
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="141">
<title>Human mobility in large cities as a proxy for crime</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0171609</url>
<snippet>We investigate at the subscale of the neighborhoods of a highly populated city the incidence of property crimes in terms of both the resident and the floating population. Our results show that a relevant allometric relation could only be observed between property crimes and floating population. More precisely, the evidence of a superlinear behavior indicates that a disproportional number of property crimes occurs in regions where an increased flow of people takes place in the city. For comparison, we also found that the number of crimes of peace disturbance only correlates well, and in a superlinear fashion too, with the resident population. Our study raises the interesting possibility that the super-linearity observed in previous studies [Bettencourt et al., Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 104, 7301 (2007) and Melo et al., Sci. Rep. 4, 6239 (2014)] for homicides versus population at the city scale could have its origin in the fact that the floating population, and not the resident one, should be taken as the relevant variable determining the intrinsic microdynamical behavior of the system. RI Andrade, Jose/C-5451-2013; Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/J-4630-2016 OI Andrade, Jose/0000-0002-5571-7610; Universidade Federal do Ceara, Physics Department/0000-0002-9247-6780; Furtado, Vasco/0000-0001-8721-4308
WOS:000396161700111
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="142">
<title>Energy and time determine scaling in biological and computer designs</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2015.0446</url>
<snippet>Metabolic rate in animals and power consumption in computers are analogous quantities that scale similarly with size. We analyse vascular systems of mammals and on-chip networks of microprocessors, where natural selection and human engineering, respectively, have produced systems that minimize both energy dissipation and delivery times. Using a simple network model that simultaneously minimizes energy and time, our analysis explains empirically observed trends in the scaling of metabolic rate in mammals and power consumption and performance in microprocessors across several orders of magnitude in size. Just as the evolutionary transitions from unicellular to multicellular animals in biology are associated with shifts in metabolic scaling, our model suggests that the scaling of power and performance will change as computer designs transition to decentralized multi-core and distributed cyber-physical systems. More generally, a single energy-time minimization principle may govern the design of many complex systems that process energy, materials and information. This article is part of the themed issue 'The major synthetic evolutionary transitions'.
WOS:000384460600009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="143">
<title>Cultural Dynamics, Deep Time, and Data Planning Cyberinfrastructure Investments for Archaeology</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.7183/2326-3768.3.1.1</url>
<snippet>Archaeological data and research results are essential to addressing such fundamental questions as the origins of human culture; the origin, waxing, and waning of civilizations and cities; the response of societies to long-term climate changes; and the systemic relationships implicated in human-induced changes in the environment. However, we lack the capacity for acquiring, managing, analyzing, and synthesizing the data sets needed to address important questions such as these. We propose investments in computational infrastructure that would transform archaeology's ability to advance research on the field's most compelling questions with an evidential base and inferential rigor that have heretofore been impossible. At the same time, new infrastructure would make archaeological data accessible to researchers in other disciplines. We offer recommendations regarding data management and availability, cyberinfrastructure tool building, and social and cultural changes in the discipline. We propose funding synthetic case studies that would demonstrate archaeology's ability to contribute to transdisciplinary research on long-term social dynamics and serve as a context for developing computational tools and analytical workflows that will be necessary to attack these questions. The case studies would explore how emerging research in computer science could empower this research and would simultaneously provide productive challenges for computer science research.
WOS:000452828600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="144">
<title>Distance to the Scaling Law: A Useful Approach for Unveiling Relationships between Crime and Urban Metrics</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0069580</url>
<snippet>We report on a quantitative analysis of relationships between the number of homicides, population size and ten other urban metrics. By using data from Brazilian cities, we show that well-defined average scaling laws with the population size emerge when investigating the relations between population and number of homicides as well as population and urban metrics. We also show that the fluctuations around the scaling laws are log-normally distributed, which enabled us to model these scaling laws by a stochastic-like equation driven by a multiplicative and log-normally distributed noise. Because of the scaling laws, we argue that it is better to employ logarithms in order to describe the number of homicides in function of the urban metrics via regression analysis. In addition to the regression analysis, we propose an approach to correlate crime and urban metrics via the evaluation of the distance between the actual value of the number of homicides ( as well as the value of the urban metrics) and the value that is expected by the scaling law with the population size. This approach has proved to be robust and useful for unveiling relationships/behaviors that were not properly carried out by the regression analysis, such as i) the non-explanatory potential of the elderly population when the number of homicides is much above or much below the scaling law, ii) the fact that unemployment has explanatory potential only when the number of homicides is considerably larger than the expected by the power law, and iii) a gender difference in number of homicides, where cities with female population below the scaling law are characterized by a number of homicides above the power law. RI Mendes, Renio/F-9261-2017; Ribeiro, Haroldo/C-8614-2012; Alves, Luiz/H-3389-2013 OI Ribeiro, Haroldo/0000-0002-9532-5195; Alves, Luiz/0000-0001-6204-5552; Lenzi, Ervin/0000-0003-3853-1790
WOS:000324465000019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="145">
<title>The Scaling of Human Contacts and Epidemic Processes in Metapopulation Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep15111</url>
<snippet>We study the dynamics of reaction-diffusion processes on heterogeneous metapopulation networks where interaction rates scale with subpopulation sizes. We first present new empirical evidence, based on the analysis of the interactions of 13 million users on Twitter, that supports the scaling of human interactions with population size with an exponent. ranging between 1.11 and 1.21, as observed in recent studies based on mobile phone data. We then integrate such observations into a reaction-diffusion metapopulation framework. We provide an explicit analytical expression for the global invasion threshold which sets a critical value of the diffusion rate below which a contagion process is not able to spread to a macroscopic fraction of the system. In particular, we consider the Susceptible-Infectious-Recovered epidemic model. Interestingly, the scaling of human contacts is found to facilitate the spreading dynamics. This behavior is enhanced by increasing heterogeneities in the mobility flows coupling the subpopulations. Our results show that the scaling properties of human interactions can significantly affect dynamical processes mediated by human contacts such as the spread of diseases, ideas and behaviors. RI Karsai, Marton/G-3391-2011; Tizzoni, Michele/H-6442-2016; Karsai, Marton/M-6684-2015 OI Karsai, Marton/0000-0001-5752-556X; Tizzoni, Michele/0000-0001-7246-2341; Karsai, Marton/0000-0001-5752-556X; Perra, Nicola/0000-0002-5559-3064
WOS:000362983600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="146">
<title>Statistical outliers and dragon-kings as Bose-condensed droplets</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjst/e2012-01561-y</url>
<snippet>A theory of exceptional extreme events, characterized by their abnormal sizes compared with the rest of the distribution, is presented. Such outliers, called "dragon-kings", have been reported in the distribution of financial drawdowns, city-size distributions (e.g., Paris in France and London in the UK), in material failure, epileptic seizure intensities, and other systems. Within our theory, the large outliers are interpreted as droplets of Bose-Einstein condensate: the appearance of outliers is a natural consequence of the occurrence of Bose-Einstein condensation controlled by the relative degree of attraction, or utility, of the largest entities. For large populations, Zipfs law is recovered (except for the dragon-king outliers). The theory thus provides a parsimonious description of the possible coexistence of a power law distribution of event sizes (Zipfs law) and dragon-king outliers.
WOS:000303337700003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="147">
<title>Building a science of cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cities.2011.11.008</url>
<snippet>Our understanding of cities is being transformed by new approaches from the complexity sciences (Batty, 2005). Here we review progress, sketching the background beginning with the systems approach which treated systems as being organised from the top down to that which now dominates where systems are treated as evolving from the bottom up. The switch in thinking we describe is best pictured in the transition from thinking of cities as machines to cities as organisms. We first review developments in the dynamics of cities where the notion of equilibrium has been replaced by a veritable potpourri of different types such as chaos, catastrophes, and bifurcations. We then look at patterns and processes that give rise to morphologies that illustrate fractal patterns and self-similarity. We follow this with ideas about networks and interactions that sustain cities through their transport and then we show how such processes of movement and mobility can give rise to the diffusion and segregation of different spatial activities. In all these developments, ideas about scaling that relate size, shape and scale in space and time are evident and we thus sketch three scaling laws based on rank-size, allometry and gravitation that are central to our synthesis of how spatial processes give rise to physical morphologies. We conclude with notions about how these ideas are being embedded into models that have potential applications to inform policy. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. RI Batty, Michael/I-5638-2014
WOS:000300813400003
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
